Everyone in this lecture, we're going to talk about the and basics.
So many people get fear when they hear the word recording because it's a pretty confusing technique,
especially for the beginners.
But we will try to explain it in a simplified manner with the help of certain examples, and we will
do a lot of problem-solving undergraduate as well.
Let's see what is it?
A guidance, as they say.
It's a technique in computer science with a solution to a problem.
OK.
Depends upon solution to smaller instances of the same problem.
OK, this is something that what you need to remember.
Let's say you have a problem, and that problem is a complex problem.
That means it has a lot of in quality.
And you want to break this problem into maybe smaller instances of the same problem.
Or maybe you break this into three such problems of later size and by three and by three and by three
you'll get.
The other idea would be to solve this problems and combine the answers of some problems to get done
that for a bigger problem.
Guess that this is something what we would be doing.
And what is the meaning of smaller instances of the same problem?
Let's say we want to compute some function.
If then the smaller problem will also be on the same function if, OK, something like this.
So I'll try to explain with the help of one very simple example.
Let us see the most classical example that is taken to.
Deja goes into that is the factorial question, OK, so let's say I want to compute a factorial of a
number and OK, let's add that number and this five.
And I want to compute of an that is equal to end victory.
This is I'm doing what I want to compute now, although this is a easier problem, but still we can
break this problem recursively.
We can break it endosomal.
It's a problem of the same type.
So you know, what is the property of Victorians?
So Victoria is nothing, but it can be written as an indoor and minus one factorial.
And rather than minus one factor, it is nothing but f off and minus one.
So it can be written as like this.
So what we have done, we have done a lot of larger problem in terms of a smaller problem of the same
day.
Now how do we compute it algorithmically?
For example, if I want to compute five factorial, this will be written as 5.0 for this forward.
For Total can be written as 14 two three factorial.
This can be written as three into two factorial.
This can be written as doing two one factorial.
This can be written as one and two zero factorial i zero factorial.
We know we have reached a point where the problem cannot be broken down further.
So such a point is known as base case.
So let us see what are these dumps?
So at this point, we would say we have reached a guess which is known as base case, that means we
we cannot reduce our problem further and the basic, as is the case where we know the answer of this
problem gets zero effect or nothing, but one what we will do, then we will run one into one one and
this one will go bad kid.
So this would become two into one, that is do.
And this too will go back, kid.
This is nothing but trained to do.
That is equal to six under six will go ahead.
The three victories will get replaced by six.
This will become 5:46.
That is 24.
This 24 will go ahead and five and 24 will be 120.
So when we would be dealing with regulation, we will see two directions in one direction, we are breaking
the problem and we are trying to simplify it.
So that means we are moving towards the base case, OK, towards the base case.
And another direction would be in which we are again coming back from the base case towards the main
problem.
OK, so this is from top to down.
And this is from down Gadhafi.
OK, we would be doing work in two directions.
First, we will be breaking and simplifying the problem.
Then we would be combining the solutions to form the answers of the bigger problem that we have left.
So this is how this recording is going to work.
You may ask how does it will work in the form of a program?
Well, guess when we're going to write the code, we will take the help of call stock function, call
stack.
OK.
So I hope you remember those calls, that concept.
So what happens is, let's say you have a function mean and it makes a call to the function helo, which
further makes the function call to the, let's say, dual function height.
What happened is in the call SoC, you will see that these functions will get started on the top of
each other.
OK.
And in the order in which they're called, and once the function high is completed, it will go off.
Once the functional is completed, it will go off and once the mine is completed, it will also go off.
But it couldn't actually uses the concept of call stock to store all the states of these variables that
we are going to have.
So it will become more clear as we go through some more examples.
But for this video, the concept is, you understand at high level what recording is going to do.
It is going to break down your complex problems into smaller problems.
We are going to solve those problems and get back over answers.
OK?
So let us see another example.
For example, we want to define an operation.
Go to home.
Let's say you are standing at.
Some calling it, let's say, some ex guarding it on your home is add some value that is equal to end,
so you want to reach this home and what you will do.
One is you put a look and you can simply do take one step every day.
But another thing you're going to do is you will say, OK, you know, I'll just dig one step and I
will ask recursion to take me home from X plus one.
OK.
So the idea is you take one step and leave the rest of the work, for the record, know because at this
point can be solid recursively again.
And despite what you would be doing, take one step, leave the rest, work for the good and big one
step, leave the rest.
Work for the records.
OK?
And what would be the best guess?
The best course would be if you are at the home, stop moving.
You don't need to do any of it in the recursive case.
OK, the other case in which we defined that occurrence, like F11, is nothing but an index of and
minus one.
This case is known as a recursive case, but what would be a recursive case for this problem?
You will take one step towards home and you will call the same function go to home from X plus one.
OK.
So if I show you in the form of a little bit of a pseudo code?
So this is how the court would look like, so there is a method.
Go home, which gets the current location.
And it also gets where the home is located.
So you check if we have already reached the home.
We will say, OK, we have reached a home and we don't do anything further.
And the device what we do, we take one step and we call Go home.
But on that particular step, OK?
So this is how a recursive call would look like.
So you can see we're calling the same function because we said that we are going to break down the problem
in terms of a smaller problem here, although we have breaking down if we need any steps to reach the
homes that we have taken one step and we said, OK, the remaining and minus one steps will be taken
by the same recursive function.
So this is a local and the idea is, you understand at high level what is required is going to do so.
It it goes in all.
It's also related with the idea of principle of mathematical induction.
So you might have studied about this principle while in your school or in college.
So in this principle, what we actually try to do is we first figure out the smallest use.
Maybe we see what could be the smallest possible solution for the given problem.
Maybe what could be the value of f of zero?
Maybe what could be the value of a f of one?
So this really depends upon what kind of question it is, OK?
In some cases, we may have a four zero four one, maybe of of two as well.
We want to figure out what is the value of the smallest case, for example, in case of a factorial
the smallest cases, zero factorial, that is one.
OK.
In case of a Fibonacci, there would be two smallest cases because two, if you want A. We need two
initial values zero and one only, then we can build the next value.
So this we will look at later on as well.
What step is always figured out the smallest case?
Then, when you're writing code for the recursion, one assumption that you have always you always need
to take this.
Suppose you are breaking down your problem f often in maybe to solve problems f off, let's say, and
by three and maybe have to end by three.
What do you need to assume that such a problem can be solved?
OK?
So you have to assume that these two solve problems will be solved recursively.
Using this assumption, you have to write a reference.
OK?
You have to write a recurrence for the following.
OK.
How I can combine the solutions of the smallest of problems to get done to four f often.
So once you do this, your code will work fine and you can also verify and think by your code works.
OK.
So you have to solve the current problem, assuming there's a problem, solution exists.
OK, so this is.
Our assumption, but it will actually work and we will prove it, Wildwoods.
So we have to find out.
OK.
Let us assume that some f off and minus one is true.
Or do you think this?
We will find out.
OK, what is that for then in terms of a foreign minus one or minus or something?
OK, so it could be any other problem.
It can be broken down in any, any way.
And it will depend upon problem, the problem, how we break down the problem into the problems.
So this is a high level introduction about regulation, and in the next lecture, we will actually see
an example along with the code.
That's all for this lecture.
Thank you.