Hi and welcome back.
And now we are going to deal with the first example of the good and that is how to compute the factory
floor of a number.
So we have already seen that often what factorial can be written and multiplied by f of n minus one.
And for example, if we have five factories, you can build an aspiring to perfect total.
And we discussed when we are going to solve recursive problem, we will figure out two guesses.
One is a base case.
And second into the records is OK, in the base case, I know when the value of an is equal to zero,
the answer off a total should be one and American civilians.
I know the formula is nothing and multiplied by 11 minus one.
These are the only two things that we need to know the ones we know.
These two things we can write the code on.
Right after writing the code, I will tell you how the call stack works and why we are getting the right
answer.
OK, so we will also talk about file stack integration and why it is correct.
So let us first dive into the code and then we will see.
So I'm going to make recursive program for Factorial.
So let us say we have a function, in fact, total, the return type isn't needed because the function
is going to return an integer, so we get some value input.
And we have a base case, and we also have a recursive case.
What is going to happen in the best case, we are going to see if any zero, then we know the answer
is going to be one.
That's it and the recursive case.
We know that the given problem has often gone better than us and multiplied by the fact of n minus one.
That's it, and we can do that on the sunset.
And we are done.
OK, so this is the complete federal program, and now we are going to test of a good bill, maybe take
input from the user and then the factorial of that particular number and.
The builders successful.
So let's run it.
So if I go five, I get done one 120, if I give six Dhanteras 720, that means it's working perfectly
fine.
And now let us also look what happened, actually.
So then your program started.
OK, so there is a cost.
There is a concept of a call stack.
The what is called stack stock is a special memory.
So it's like a container and all the functions that are called.
There they go inside the stock.
So first of all, the main function?
It went into the stock.
And all the local variables like and here we have only one local variable, so that is defined it and
let's say we took this values in what then is defined as five from where we call the flag function and
we tell, OK, we have to compute the factory love and equal to faith.
This takes whether the best guess is true.
So this is not true.
It makes the recursive call.
OK.
You can see it computer value on set.
So there is a variable answer that is not yet computed.
There it is.
Five and do something so that something is what that is factorial offer.
So you make another recursive call to the fact total that call gets pushed into the stock market and
is for.
And here we also create another local variable because there is a local variable in every call.
We are going to create these local variables.
The value of is forward and do something that something is another function call will done OK and equal
to three.
Here we have until equal to trained to something that something is nothing but another function.
Call an equal to two and very close to doing something that is f of one.
We make another function call.
And that to this one and two zero victory.
So we make another function, call with any call to zero the No.
One and zero.
We say it's done one.
So this function actually returns one, it gets removed from the call stack.
So here I will change my goal.
Now we're going to work in a different direction.
Now we have reached the base case, OK?
The base case is you done one to the point from where it was called, so it was called from here.
So we return to one here.
So it becomes and that is one into one.
Now I, for one, is going to done one.
And you can to return on that note, this statement a little what happened is when you were computing,
this answered.
This function was paused at line number 12 and it was waiting for the value of fact of N minus one.
It wanted a value from fact of n minus one, it returned tons of that is one into one that is one.
This gets removed from the constant and this until one is stored here.
They're just doing the one.
A dysfunction was waiting for the value of f of one.
And now it has got the value because this function returned to its parent.
This will get removed, so it will return to the one that is due to will come here.
Similarly, this function was waiting for of two.
Now that value has arrived and it will return.
Six.
The six will come here.
It would become 05:46 that is 24 and it would return 24 hit.
It would become five and 224.
That is one 20.
And this value would come here because Maine is waiting for this value.
So here you will get an answer off 120.
That's it.
And finally, once your mean is also over video, this also gets removed from the cluster we've heard
talk about how much time it will take.
We actually.
Miracles take off and levels deep, so we are making a number of calls, each call takes concerned time.
So the time taken is all that often.
OK.
Time is order of it.
And what about the space complex?
OK, Bill Gates, ever talk about how is this space complexity changing throughout the entire program?
So initially, you can see there was only one start frame that it increased to two two three four five
six.
So then it came back to again like zero.
During the point when the base case was hit, the space utilization was maximum and that was equal to
all that often.
OK.
So in the worst case, during this entire execution to this is space and this time of execution, at
a particular point, the space utilization was maximum.
So we would say this space complexity of this program is also ordered often, although we're not taking
any extra.
But we are using the cores stack.
Which takes memory, and you can see for maximum depth of and we have created a number of under variables,
each storing a different value at a particular point in the program, the space utilization went up
to linear, so we can see both space and time are going to be harder often for this problem.
And you run when you need to remember that all recursive problems will take up extra space.
OK, so the Guardian actually takes extra space because of the concept of this implicit stack.
So that's it, that's all for this lecture, and now I hope you understood how it goes and actually
works for this particular problem.