Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we're going to learn how to write recursive function to compute anatomy when I can.
OK.
So if you have not heard about V1 auxiliaries, I will tell you it is a very simple mathematical series
in which the first two dams are zero and one, and every time every item is the sum of previous two
dams.
Okay, so I can say that, and that's done is nothing better than some of the previous two terms you
have of and minus one less effort when minus two.
And if I talk about what would be the next and what would be some of these two?
That is one.
What would be the next dump?
Some of these two that to the next term would be three.
The next would be five.
Next would be eight.
The next would be 13.
And so on.
OK.
So what we are given, we are given a particular value of end and we want to look at what is the anatomy
of this particular series.
So, for example, zero one two three four five six seven the seventh film of the series is going to
be 13.
The 11th done is going to be some x y z.
The fifth term is nothing but five that we need to figure it out.
OK.
So as I said, when we are dealing with recursion, we will need two things.
One is a recursive case that we've already seen.
We already know about this problem.
And second is the base case if.
So the idea of picking this problem is not to reach the gold, because gold is very simple ideas to
teach you and the concept of records when there is more than one coin in the previous question we saw
there is only one goal happening from each one Jim Gold.
But in this case, from each function call, you guys are going to happen again.
So we will talk about how the record gentry would look like in this case and what would happen to the
gold stock and so on.
Let's talk a little bit about the baskets.
The baskets is going to be two cases of let's say you are competing for an equal to two.
So it was going to make two gold one on one and one on zero.
But now I had one.
What are you going to do?
Will you make two more gold?
Will you make a call on zero and minus one than that is?
We cannot make calls under negative indices.
That means we have to take one as a base case and we have to take zero as a base case.
So this part is not needed.
So we will have to base case.
Is it?
The value of an equal to zero is going to be zero and the value of an equal to one is going to be one.
Let me first show you the gold and then along with the gold, we will try to brighten how this gold
is going to work.
OK, so let's let's make a new program for Fibonacci.
And let's go up a little little bit from here.
This this is no fib.
Anderson on February.
So as I said, we are going to have to be asking this, OK, so I can put both of them in a single condition,
if any zero or in is one, we can return.
And that means if no zero, we are running zero, if any is one, we are attending one, actually.
Otherwise, we are going to say we are going to compute two values.
One is if one that is above and minus one, another value is F2 that is above and minus two.
And our answer would be nothing but a fun plus.
OK.
So we could have that included in return five off and minus one plus five above in minus two.
But just to make things easier for you for the first time, I would add in the cold.
Like this, OK?
Now this this will also make their understanding of Caltech more clear what is exactly happening now,
this is the cold.
Let us first run it.
And.
Regardless, if you want to get Fazilka, tell me this, haven't done it 13, tell me the fifth time
it is five, that means it is working perfectly fine.
Now let us see what happens and don't call stack level.
So let's say this is of a call stock.
And I'm going to run it for a small example, except for f an equal two foot.
OK.
And now in the in the beginning, we had only men.
What happened is from Maine, we made a call to if we were to give an equal to four.
So we called Fibonacci with the value of an equal to four.
And it tried to compute the value of our fine, so it made a call to three.
It called theabove and Nicole to OK.
And three, what it did we ask, is this not true?
It tried to make a call.
So another call it will make, but it will make later on.
That is true and equal to these calls are not executed yet.
This will be executed later.
The tremendous according to the tremendous call to do.
OK.
And what happened to you?
You must have made a call to one, OK, fib of two.
It made a call to a fourth and equal to one night and equal to one.
We saw their dysfunction.
It's the best case and it will not exude discord.
It will return a value of endless one.
So one actually returned one.
This actually got removed from the memory.
OK.
So this actually got removed from the memory.
And now what happened is.
This brand is also gone.
OK, so this branch returned one under it is now gone from the stack.
OK, so what is going to happen is it was going to computed the value of a fund.
It was not going to compute.
The value of this function will now execute line number 10 for the first time at this particular point.
Or it will make a call on zero and it will return a value of zero.
It will make a call on FIB, but any call to zero.
And this is going to return zero and this is again going to get fobbed off.
This is going to get removed from local stock at this point.
This is how the check is going to look like.
And Lord knows, man, that is one plus zero.
That is one who is going to tell Tree.
That means it is.
One tree not only knows one of dozens of bouquets of tree nodes done to have fun for tree is one, and
tree is now going to compute F2 for which it is going to make another call.
So this is going to get removed.
This is going to get removed.
And what is it going to do?
Tree is going to make a call on.
We both won, OK, so it is going to make it more fun, so everyone will get at it in the quarter and
it will again return one to three.
So it will return.
My answer is.
Also one.
OK, so an actress, what what it is going to do, neutrinos that I know one answer was one the another
one was also wondered is going to return one plus one that is two.
And now Ford knows that my fun is to get to know that one of the answers to OK.
And now Ford is going to make a call for F2 that does this line number 10 and this call will get executed.
OK, so we make a call.
Let's do the same story going to repeat.
Who is going to make a call on one?
One is going to Delmond.
That is one.
It will get added to the calls and then once it returns, it will get removed.
Then two will make a call to zero.
Zero will return again zero and one plus zero is going to be one.
And at Ford, we earlier knew that one answer was two and F2 is now one.
So it is going to return to plus one that is trying to do me a favor Ford is going to be.
So I'm not drawn to Goldstuck completely, but what I am trying to tell you is if you want to make it
easy, if you want to see how many calls are made or what calls are made.
So the ideal way is to draw drive using two cars in three.
OK?
And from this, you can easily estimate the space time complexity of the program as well.
What happens at the end equal to Ford?
Or let it let us do it for an equal to five, if I will make two calls for entry?
This call will happen later on.
Ford will make two goals three and two.
It will make two goals to earn one.
This call will happen later on.
It will make two calls one in zero.
One will execute first, though one will return.
One zero will return.
Zero two will return.
One and one will return one.
He will return to one plus one and two.
Now to two is not going to have done anything directly because it is not the basket, so we need to
further expand it.
They will make two goals.
It is going great and one, it is going to return zero.
It is going to return to plus one plus zero.
That is one and four.
It is going to return to +1 three and five is going to make a call on three threes, not our base case.
It's going to call on two and one.
It's going to call on one and zero.
It will return one.
It will return zero.
It will return.
Two and five is going to return three plus two.
That is five.
OK, now these are the number of calls that we have made.
And roughly the number of calls in this case, if I talk about on the first level, I have one goal.
On the second level, I have two goals on the next level four goals.
It is a GP and we have roughly in levels.
Approximately we are making exponential number of calls.
The time taken would be the number of calls less time.
We need quite slow in each call.
We are doing OK trend work that is adding to numbers, so it is hard enough to raise to Ebola.
And what about this pace?
How much memory we have taken in the worst case, the maximum depth of the call stack would be this
much.
OK.
Because at any point, only one of the brands is going to exist in the call stack, OK, so the memory
of the program would look something like this.
It is increasing, then maybe decreasing, then increasing or decreasing, increasing, decreasing and
finally zero in this particular branch, the utilization is maximum.
OK, so it would be something like of this kind.
This is one and equal to one was at this point and this was an equal to 0.8 something like this.
At these two points, the space utilization is maximum, so the time is order of two days to devour
in space utilization this order thing.
This is how the Philharmonic is going to work.
I hope the concepts are clear.
That's all for this lecture.
Thank you.