Hi, everyone.
Now we have already looked at two examples in which we used the occasion to bring the solution.
Now we're going to look at the third question in which we had not given a number, but we have to work
on an OK.
For example, we need to write a recursive function that checks whether a given error is sorted or not.
OK?
So you would think how do I apply to college in 1980?
That idea is very simple.
Like we say, for the problem of say, then we can break it into one one work by noon, what we will
do and remaining in minus one units of work that goes in very similar thing.
We can apply here as well.
So let's see how we can actually handle this problem.
So let us let me draw NRT.
And let's say we have certain elements, let's say one, two, three, five, four and six two.
This is the area, and I want to check if we decided on North.
Now what you can do is.
The first step you can take and you can ask it, it goes in to tell whether the remaining that is ordered
or not.
OK, so the first step would be you compared the first the 02 11 with the first element that you take.
If one is less than two and the remaining that is sorted, then you can say that indeed it is going
to be sorted.
OK, so what is the condition for area of say?
Then let's say you have an idea of size and you can check it is sorted if area of zero is less than
ideal one.
OK.
And let's say there is a function that returns, whether it is altered or not.
So what we will need to do, we need to check if this is the case and.
The remaining areas also started, OK, the remaining areas of the size and minus one, if it is, if
it is all decided, then we can say yes, then that it is going to be OK, this is what I'm going to
tell you.
One is less than two and two three five four six.
This is the remaining area.
Is this area sorted again?
I will make a recursive call.
OK, so I am breaking down this call.
It was less than three years.
Then we will make a call on the remaining grid that is the five or six.
Then we break it down now for this area, is it it is less than even yes, three is less than five and
we can check.
That the remaining that is 546, is it sorted or not?
Now, at this point, we're going to take is five less than four done to this?
No, OK.
As soon as we get this anthrax, no, we don't need to make any further calls and we can return calls
from this particular point.
So this basically tells, OK.
This condition is false.
It tells its parent that this condition is false.
Where we are doing it and of proven false.
That means that output would be false.
That we are doing and of proven false output would be false and hence to the main goal.
We will look at knowing this error is not sorted and we are going to return.
This is the case for Linda.
It is not sorted.
Now let us also look at the case when it is not what is going to happen.
Let's let me take a small example one, two, three and legs of life.
We are going to take one is less than two.
Yes, remaining.
It is sorted.
We don't know because it will take.
It will take.
Those less than three.
Is the remaining resorted?
We don't know the is going to take these lives than faith and is the remaining resorted.
Remaining, it is only one element.
Yes, it's one element that is sorted.
This is true.
This is true, tried and true.
It returns true.
This is true.
And this ad is going to be sorted now from here, you can figure out.
The base case, though, if only one element is left.
Then you can say, yes, it is us or today, OK?
In the recursive case, you have to check for two conditions.
One is if a zero is less than even.
And the remaining area is sorted.
OK.
The remaining at it, you can make a recursive call to check whether that date is sorted or not.
So that's all for this concept.
And now we will look into the cold.
I so now let's see the goal for this problem.
Whether that is or so, there are multiple ways to write the goal.
I'm going to discuss three of the OK, so in the first function, I'm going to write a Mulund function
that tells whether this water does not take input.
The edit and I also take input the number of elements the arrays currently contain.
OK.
We talked about we will have a base case I'm going to talk about.
We will have a recursive case.
What happened in the base case?
We said if only one element is left or maybe the elements are there and they, then it would be sorted
out so I can return to that.
What we have already discussed in the recursive case we talked about, we will check if at zero.
Is less than a day off one.
And the remaining that sorted, it sorted the remaining three, OK, so now let's say this is the area.
And the remaining that I want to guard from this particular point, I can pass this point as Europe
as one because it will take my edit starting address for the remaining problem to the next index, so
I can check if the edit that starts from anyplace +1 is sorted.
And this edit contains how many elements this contain, then minus one elements.
OK, if this is the case, then I can say return true.
If one of these conditions is false, then I can return false.
That's it.
That's the entire goal.
Now we can try to run and check for this example.
Maybe I can.
To see out is sorted and I give the Eddie and I give the relevant.
Let's build a gold and let's try to run it.
So Dodge started artillery and I'm getting a zero.
That means this ad is not sorted.
Maybe a let me make it as.
Six, seven.
Then.
I should get an answer, one that yes, this ad is.
Now you're going to Discord is working perfectly fine.
And this is exactly how we have discussed and the code should be implemented, OK?
So some people may find another way to implement it.
Let me also go through that way.
Some people may find this error plus one and then minus one consuming confusing, then maybe is sorted.
And you may like to buy an index.
OK.
Let me tell you one more way in this way, you're not changing the value of and so what we're going
to do, we are going to pass the address in the form of an index.
OK, let's say we're checking whether Adelphi is less than ideal 5+1 and we can say, OK, let us check
the remaining sub area that starts from my plus one is sorted or not, OK?
And when it reaches this value, OK, we're going to mix up problems.
Our problems are problems.
The problem, then, is equal to and minus one.
That means we have added, which contains exactly one element.
So let me write the same code in a different manner so I can check if I equals in minus one.
That means we are at the last index we can return to.
That is ways we can check if.
If is less than a day off.
+1 and the remaining areas sorted is sorted or maybe is sorted to.
This is a second way.
Then we pass in the area instead of changing the area, address what we can do, we can move the index
point one step forward.
That is a plus one.
And instead of reducing the size, often we can do the erase from my plus one bill and minus one.
So we keep it as in and we can check we can get it done through true.
Otherwise we can return Dunford's.
This could be another way of writing.
OK.
What is not declared?
But this should be better.
This should be a at.
So maybe I can call this method is sorted.
Do.
And here I need to pass in value if I initially there's going to be zero.
And if I'd underscore now I get it sorted.
But suppose if I put it 16 here and I and this meant now you can say it is going to return zero.
So what the methods are almost saying, the only thing is in the first method, we are not explicitly
passing the address.
We had a.
Ending the base address of daddy in every call, we are making a copy of the address and we are updating
it.
OK, but in the second address, instead of changing the base address of the we have kept agreeable
eye, which tells us in the current function call, we are going to start over area from an index site
and we are going to do the work and minus one.
OK, so that's all for the two approaches, and I hope the goals are very simple and they should be
clear to you now.
That's all for this lecture.
Thank you.