Everyone in this lecture, I'm going to talk about a very simple problem, but it's very important to
take up this problem for strengthening your concept of the recursion.
Okay, so we will understand the concept of going towards the base case and coming back from the base
case through this example.
So you can also try this problem on your own.
Before we dive into the code.
So the question is very simple we just need to simulate the same functionality as of a fire loop using
this particular problem.
We have to print all the numbers one two in recursively, in decreasing order and in increasing orders.
We need to write two methods one.
Let's give an insulator.
Five.
The first method should print one two three four five.
OK.
The second method that is for the increasing one.
And the second method, if in his favorite children, they would put like five foot into one drastically
decreasing one.
OK, now let's see how we can actually do it.
So let's see.
We have a method decreasing, which brings the numbers in the decreasing order.
OK, so what we discussed was we will take one step and the rest of the steps will be taken by the record.
What I can do in this decreasing method, I can say, OK, no, the value of an I will put the value
of an.
OK.
And then I will call the method decreasing off and minus one.
That will automatically print all the numbers from N minus one to one.
OK.
And in the best case, we can have a case that, OK, if you are reducing and fifty each point, then
the number is zero, we can return, OK?
So let us see what is going to happen if, let's say end is five.
This is this is for the recursive case and for the basic is I can take if an is zero, we can return.
We don't do anything.
OK?
Are you going to have also another case, like if there is one friend one and then and that is also
fine, but either of these cases would book.
I can start from an equal to five.
What I will do, I will print, then I will print five.
I'll make a call on an equal to four.
A blueprint for I'll make a call on inequality.
I will Braintree, I'll make a call on an equal to two, Alperin told me to call on and equal to one
I then one, I'll make a call on any to zero.
I will say they're done.
It will get it done.
It will say they're done.
It was written, it was written.
Finally, what I got in the output is nothing but five four three two one.
That's how easy it is going to be.
You'll get what the grazing or what we need to do.
We need to do the work in this direction.
I will tell you what changes we would make, so let us first rate the function for decreasing, so again,
to avoid decreasing intent.
So we have a base case.
If an is zero, we will stop.
That is done and.
Otherwise, I can see out the value of an.
And followed by a function called two degrees in love and minus one.
That's it.
So any any statements that are written before the function call, OK, so these are executed when you're
going to the base case?
OK.
And you're going towards the basics.
Anything that is coming before the function call will be executed when you're going towards the biscuits.
Now let me also underscored onshore to you large lash increasing, decreasing.
And I think we should take in the value of often and then we should call this function.
Let's end his.
I get done outward as five, four three two one.
Now I don't want to make a similar function for increasing, but the good thing is there will be only
one lane of change that is you will change the order in which this statement is executed.
So if I put this statement here and does to make it more clear, I'm going to rename the function as
increasing.
And you will see this is going to work perfectly fine and we will see why it is going to work OK.
So let us try to think what this function is going to do to let us let me call decreasing and we will
then indulge and let me call an increasing function as well.
So if I say, OK, fine, if I get the numbers in the decreasing order, I get the numbers and the increasing
order as well.
Let us try to see what this function is saying today, saying if you want to print the number, then
the increasing order from one to N, you will first print all the numbers in the increasing order from
one to n minus one.
OK.
And then you will print the number and this is the work that is done by the goods and this is the work
that is done by you in the previous code.
What said you will footprint the number numbering and then you will print the numbers, I mean, minus
one l one in the decreasing order.
OK, now you you might be surprised how this single swapping of one line of code actually change the
order in which the output is coming.
Effectively, what is happening is both the functions will have the same goal stock.
So first of all, you have mean, then you call the function with any call to five.
OK.
Decreasing function footprint.
The value sort prince five.
It makes Ocalan and equal to four.
Then it prints four.
It makes a call on an equal to three.
Then it makes equal to an equal to two.
Then it makes a call to any call to one, and then it makes a call to an equal to do settle the same
calls are being raised but made by the increasing function as well.
OK, so if you pausing then and it makes a call to faith, then it makes a call for the next call to
three two one, OK.
But the changes it is printing the statement after the call has been executed.
OK, so after we have returned from the base case, it is going to print one.
After we have returned from one, it is going to print two, then it is going to print three, then
it is going to print four, then it is going to print five.
And that's it, OK?
So this output?
Is generated by the increase in function and this output five, four three two one.
It is generated by the decrease in function.
So here.
Anything that is written before the function call.
Is executed.
Vibe going toward the basket that is from the top to the bottom.
OK, calling bottom as the biscuits, OK?
And when you're coming from the bottom towards the main main thing, that is stop.
OK, this is Barbizon, and biscuits is zero.
The top is in biscuits, as you know.
So when you're coming from a smaller problem towards a bigger problem in that code is written after
the function gone.
OK, so that is something you should always remember, and it is going to help you a lot while solving
recurrent problems.
When you need some problem solutions to be solved first and then combined, then you would be doing
this work after the function call.
OK?
So I hope these two concepts are now clear, and that's all for this lecture.