Everyone in this lecture, we're going to write this code in our program and we are going to build it
and run it.
First of all, you need a few of your things.
You need a text editor to write the code that you can download.
So we would be using sublime text.
It's very lightweight and very cool that I personally like a lot.
You can go with any other options as well as per your wish on taking those you need to install a C++
compiler.
I will attach the links in the description, and when you're done with the two things what you need
to do, you need to open up your extruder, which is which would look something like this.
And you need to save your fight, look, so if I tell you I saved as file as maybe a loader CPB, OK,
so or maybe hello world or TPP.
This will create a new file.
You can store it anywhere, any director you want.
And we are going to type the same thing that we have seen in the boilerplate code, you will say, using
namespace today.
And after that, we are going to create the mean that is the entry point of the program.
And we are also going to define the exit of the mean that is written zero.
It signifies that the program has successfully terminated anything.
Any good idea of right.
That logic will go ahead.
If you want to print something well in C++, we will use this syntax C out, followed by the value that
you want to print.
So maybe I want to print a very simple string.
Hello.
So string goes inside the barcodes, followed by end to end.
It is like a new line.
I want to shift to the new line.
So for that, we use in here.
And so these.
These things are this is an operator, OK, is this is actually a left shift operator, but it it it
has a special meaning for the compiler or get a compiler, understand these operators and these keywords
as per the rules of the C++ programming language.
So in the next set of videos, we are going to understand these rules, these new keyboards, what are
water functions?
What are variables?
So we are going to look at everything in detail.
But for now, we are just trying to show you how to write a very simple code on how you can run this
on your machine.
So now what happened is we have the source code.
OK, we have the source code with us.
So this file, this is known as source code.
There is a piece of application that we have installed on this system.
So that is known as a C++ compiler.
We have a C++ compiler on the C++ compiler itself is a complex thing to understand what we are going
to do in this lecture.
We're going to see at high level what is going to happen.
So it is going to accept a source file, which is a of TPP, and it is going to produce an executable
file.
May maybe something like Halo Dot, Eggsy if you are on a Windows machine or something like Halo out
if you're on.
A magic machine, something like this.
What we're going to do, it will give us a file.
These files can be executed.
We need to run these files, OK?
We need to run these files.
The first step is compile the code.
The compilation process will give us an executable as an end output, and we need to run that file and
that will show us the output of the program, so it is a two step process.
OK, so first step is building the code, which includes some violation and the second step is executing
the code.
That means we are going to run this code.
So every program we are going to perform these two steps.
I'm going to show you these steps through a command line.
So what you need to do, you need to open up terminal and you need to go to the location where you are.
So, for example, currently led to be at home to other quarters in the desktop world and inside CBB
lecture.
We come here and you do the command that we use to change that entry.
And inside this directory, if I do less alert means tell me what all files do we have?
OK, so it creates it has a file called Hello World Dog CBB.
OK.
So what I'm going to do, I'm going to build this code and show you the output.
So let us see how to use the C++ compiler, OK?
So there is a command that is known as D-plus Plus.
So you hit the D-plus Plus is a command that invokes the Jianyu C++ compiler.
Jianyu C++ compiler.
This compiler gets invoked.
And this needs to be installed on your machine.
This this piece of software gets invoked when you write this command deeply if you want to see what
version of Duplicitous, I'm using.
You can see this is these are the details of the compiled ways and you get so you can see this version
is twelve point zero and so on.
And this is for this particular hardware that my machine has been being you using, OK?
So you can install any version that maybe is the latest version of the previous version.
Totally up to you.
So what we are doing, we are going to use D-plus Plus to give our source file and create a executable
file.
So I'm going to say and C++, Hello world.
DOD CPB.
Now what happens this command executed successfully, and if I a list now?
There is a file called 8Ot out.
This is the default name of the file that has been created by our compiler.
And if I want to run this file, I have to say dodged like it or not.
This is how I compiled the file.
So this step is, is the compilation think that this is, uh, compile?
And this step is actually about executions, the law and order underscored again and underscored here,
if I press and enter now, you can see the output.
Hello, world.
I suppose I want to change my code and instead of saying hello world, I want to say hello everyone.
So what I will do, I will go back to my it and I will look.
Hello, everyone.
And again, back to the terminal, if I again run this good, I will not see any change because I have
not completed the compilation converts your source code into machine good orders, resin in the executable
file and that is run by the machine.
So what we need to do if we want to reflect the new output, we have to build our code again.
So we'll see D-plus Plus Hello World Dot A.P.B and laser dot like a dot.
OK, so now you can see the output is a lovely one.
OK.
And this is going to run your code on.
You see the output that has been updated as opposed.
If you want to rename your output file, you don't want the output file to look like you wrote out you
want something else.
So in that case, this d-plus plus except certain flags, so you can still get the name of the output
file.
It should be something else.
It should be hollowed out out instead of or maybe.
Hello, everyone got out.
And I'm going to compile the file.
Hello, World Dot CPB.
I'm going to compile the file Helloworld or TPP, not if I do it less.
What are you going to hit?
There is a file that has been created.
Everyone thought out.
So what we have said that the name of the executable file, it should not be rolled out.
It should be.
Hello, everyone.
No doubt we have specified.
A flag, and we are telling that again, the output should be this one, and it should not be the default
one, which is not or.
And here it is our source file.
And with this flag, we have defined what should be the value of it.
Output file.
So in this case, if you want to run discord now, you will not be using large, large adulthood.
You should be using torchlight.
Hello, everyone.
Dot Dot.
OK, now you see the output.
Hello, everyone.
That is a slight introduction to how do you build and run a code using a C++ compiler?
And I hope you clearly understood these steps, and the compilation itself is a complex thing.
So we will spend one with you on diving deep into the details of the compilation process.
That's all for this video.
Thank you.