Everyone, so you have seen how to build and run a very simple C++ program.
So we are going to increase the level by one step and we are going to solve a very simple problem.
And the problem is we want to find note the average marks.
So we are given the marks of a student in three different subjects physics, chemistry and maths, and
we want to find out their average.
The what we will will learn to take input output through this example and will learn a little bit about
the great apes.
Though we will dive deep into data types as well.
What we are doing, we are going to say, OK, we will take input the marks in the physics and chemistry
and will produce a final output how much marks the audience could.
What we are going to do.
Let us go back and do the sublime text, and we are going to create a new file.
And maybe we can say average marks.
Is the fight on what we are doing?
We are going to first include the head of the fight as usual, followed by the namespace.
And this extreme is responsible for containing the could not be used for doing input and output.
Right now, what we have only seen how to do output the output is done using a sealed object, but the
input is done using a C in object.
So C in is responsible for taking something as an input.
OK.
So firstly, we will we can hardcore look, we can say in physics.
The student got led to 18 months in physics and what we are doing, we are creating a bucket which is
going to store the marks of physics in a program.
You will need to store data.
So you have created a bucket which will store interior type of data.
And we are saying, look, the value is equal to the values equal to 80.
And similarly, we can create boomer buckets.
It's there is a bucket of chemistry there in the seven and months, which has led to 65.
And what I want to do, I want to do with the average, OK, they're doing, the average might result
in a number if it is not an integer which is having some value after the decimal as well.
Maybe what the point three three.
These kind of numbers are known as floating point numbers.
What we need to do instead of creating a bucket of type in digit, we can create a bucket of the type
average.
OK.
And 65 and we'll be 32.
All these drone beaters, and I want to put the average inside another book, so I can say Lord Average,
that is nothing but the sum of three numbers.
Divided by three.
And now, if I print the value of a bridge, let's see what happens.
Maybe you can see the bridge marks.
Odd.
And here you print the average.
So anything that is printed in the mail quote, this is printed as it is and this thing is used without
double code.
That means we are printing what is contained in the average bucket, so that will show as an output
on the screen.
If I that's OK, let's return on the exit of the program in this program, what we are defining, we
are defining our data.
We are processing the data.
And we are printing the output.
OK, so these are the three steps we are doing we are doing in this program.
Now let us go back here and let us try to run this code.
Maybe what I wanted to do, I want to invoke the compiler and the name of my file is average marks.
I can say average marks start MBP, so I'm using the W2 or to complete the names.
I know if I do a list.
Since we have not specified the name of the output file, it would be created in error.
Doubt if I now say I want to run this code, so I will say dogs like.
Torchlight is not out.
And now it says the average marks is 74.
We are not getting anything that is after the decimal know why that happened, OK?
It might be possible the average marks were seventy four point three two, but we are not getting this
one.
Let's see why.
So what happens in programming languages like C++ and Java whenever you divide?
And integer, but then indeed it, for example, if you divide the number five with two, you are not
going to get 2.5.
You're only going to get that in digit by.
Indeed, it is one endangered, it always leads and endangered.
That is the problem here.
OK.
What I want to do is I want to make one of these no flawed.
And then the output would be two one five.
So if I make this as 2.0, then the output would be 2.5.
OK.
Similarly, in our case, there are two things we can do we can make this as three 3.0 zero.
So this is this process of changing the day to day from one to another.
This is known as typecasting, so here it is, happening automatically in the numerator.
We have an integer in the denominator, we have a float.
The resulting value would be a float.
OK, so when you have an operation between an integer and a float, resulting value would be a float.
Now, if I print out what these average marks order, followed by a new line, let's see if our output
changes are not OK or if I say I want to build my code again.
And I want to run my code again.
OK, so in this case, it is still there, and the reason being it's precisely seven people, OK, so
if you do this, you will see that this number is divisible by three.
Exactly.
We're getting it as they were in default.
But let me make it as 76 in physics.
Then let's see what happened in this case.
And we have to build the gold again.
Now you see the average marks up seventy three point six, six, seven.
So you can see that this is because of now we are dividing it with 3.0, not not because of um.
So is it because of the final result is a flawed as we are dividing it with three point zero?
Well, I hope that this kid who will alternate will the tails of typecasting in the course, but this
is just an example to demonstrate what you can do.
One thing is left that instead of having hardcoded data, I want to take data as a user input.
I want to take the data and use it in.
What I will I will only define the buckets and I will ask the user to put data inside these buckets.
OK, so I can see physics, chemistry and maths.
I just defined there are three buckets of one for physics, one for chemistry and one for months.
And we are going to use a special object.
That is known as the in.
And again.
It is responsible for taking input, so we will give the in, followed by the arrows in the value of
politics, in the value of chemistry and developments.
And storied.
Now what I'm doing, I'm asking the user to give me the data of the first number that would go into
the FedEx bucket letter to indicate the next number is only two.
And 34, if I give input three numbers, they would be stored in these buckets.
In this particular order, only physics, chemistry and months.
And then again, I'm doing the processing and I'm going to print the average.
Let us try to run this code.
And maybe I can say average marks minus.
I want do the name of the violence.
And maybe average it out.
If I now run the file towards light every start out.
What you will see, you will see you're not getting any output right because it is waiting for certain
input to be given to me if I give the input as a default, the window to enter physics, it gives me
the average mark, said 54.
If you want to run this code again, maybe with a different example, maybe 30, 30, 39, 40.
Now you get the average marks as thirty three point three three three.
So you can see we are able to send user input if you want to make your.
This thing more readable.
You can also print a message for the user, you can joke you can enter the marks.
For physics, chemistry and maths.
So let us build this court again.
And we can see less evidence or doubt.
Now you're are getting a message on the terminal that this program is asking for marks in physics.
Maybe I can give nine.
Either you can give the input in a single line like we did earlier on.
You can hit a new line and enter and then you can give the input.
Now you can see the average marks at fifty nine point eighty.
I hope you understood how to write a simple program, how to take input and how to take how to do output
and how to do very simple processing.
It's a lot of things yet to come, but this is just the start.
And but the idea was after this do lectures.
You get comfortable with building and executing your code.
OK, if you have understood that well, then you are ready to go to the next step.
That's all for this video.
See you in the next.