Everyone in this lecture, I'm going to talk about a very special topic, which is known as dynamic
memory allocation.
OK, so what is this meaning of dynamic memory allocation?
We will discuss.
And what is the dynamic memory?
That is something that we are all doing to discuss and how we can look at it.
Obviously, we will look at the term index.
So what happens is when you create a relationship, you generally do it something like this.
So you define a constraint, either.
OK, this is a content site, and whenever you do this, the memory is allocated.
For example, later, this is a function in which you are creating this, Eddie.
So this function when it is called.
It occupies some space in this documentary.
The start is a type of memory that is available on all your local variables, let's say, and B and
C, all these variables will occupy some part in this back memory.
OK, so this is a this is like to be in.
This is like to see.
And whenever this function call is over, let's say you heard the written statement.
All these memories destroyed, OK?
So this content is memory that resides on the call stack.
This is known as starting memory.
OK.
And.
This is allocated by the pilot.
OK.
That means when this function is called, this memory is allocated by the compiler.
And when this function is gone, this memory is also destroyed by the compiler.
OK, so it's created and destroyed by the compiler.
So this is what happened with the static memory.
But in certain cases, we may need to work with dynamic memory.
OK.
What is dynamic memory?
It's a memory that is not allocated by the compiler.
Does memory that is allocated during runtime, for example.
You ask the user, OK, what is the value of n tell me?
And I will create a dynamic area of say then only when this value of and is given as inputs of what
we will do will talk.
It'll create a tree like this in stuttery equals new end.
And so basically the programming has to use a keyword called meal.
That means we're allocating new memory at runtime and it is going to contain and integers.
So this is the syntax of dynamic memory allocation.
So let me just try to explain you what is going to happen.
What we have done and stored.
Yeah, if you look at this index, this is actually a pointer variable.
That means it can store some address and you're making this equal to some of memory address or gets
a new and let's say some and.
OK, now this can be considered this can be a variable that is taken as input.
Now what happened is this memory is not allocated on the stock.
For example, let's say you are doing this inside of function call and you need something like this.
So what will what is going to happen when this function is called?
It will occupy some memory in the call stack.
This variable instead.
OK, so it is a static pointer variable.
It is statically allocated, so it will be a part of the call stack.
OK and start at.
But when you use this word new and this new is used for allocating memory on renting.
So this memory goes inside a part of a system memory known as the heap memory.
OK.
Generally, this heap memory is a large area inside the system.
Let's say this is a heap memory, and in this heap we are looking to the Eddie, which does not have
any name, but it does have some address.
OK.
Maybe this addresses letter two zero zero eight.
What is going to happen is this Eddy is going to point to this heap memory, OK?
And once this function call is or what, what is going to happen?
This call stack will be destroyed, but this memory will remain as it is because it is dynamically allocated.
It will stay until the programmer does not free it up.
OK, so it's the job of the programmer to delete and create this dynamic memory.
The compiler will not delete this memory, even if the function call in which this memory is created
is.
Over this issue, zero zero, it is going to get stored here.
So this is the gray box and two zero zero eight will get copied it.
We are actually putting our address in the printer variable and this is how the things are going to
work now if you use area of two.
This is actually converted into start off error plus.
So this is an that is based address error plus one is this address error plus two this address.
These two statements are actually equal.
OK, so we are actually going to an address and we are going to reference that second location.
So when I talk about, OK, how do you update the variable inside this memory?
Maybe I want to put this value.
Five.
You can simply write error of two equals five.
That means any for this index would remain similar.
It will not change because this gets broken down by the compiler into an instruction which looks like
this.
OK.
And yeah, so this is about dynamic memory.
Now, one thing I want to talk about is how you can delete this memory.
OK, now it's about your work is done and you don't want this.
So at the end of the function, what you can do, you can say, OK, I want to delete.
This particular area.
And this is going to delay the say, OK, so we are going to use new word, allocate the memory.
OK, we'll just explain you again in story.
This is equal to new and of and.
OK.
And if I want to put some value against the area of I equals some value, this is how I can update.
OK?
And maybe after some lines of code, you don't want this area.
You can also see this space.
You can delete, followed by square records, followed by a look.
The generators used for creating dynamic areas, but then maybe some real use case may involve.
OK, let's let's get into dynamic candidate.
So in that case, you're going to install X equals new.
So what it is doing, we have a stark memory, we have a stark memory in that we are creating a variable
called as Einstein X.
And this is during the.
During the address of another endangered variable that is there on the heap memory and suppose I want
to put a value on it, I can simply say it's of X equals 10.
This value is going to become a golden and later this is a b c.
So this value would be a b c OK.
But generally it would be a very maybe off, let's say.
So I wondered then this would become a complete array like this and sort of excluded basically means
X of zero is equal to 10.
OK, so we are going to put this thing OK.
So this is equivalent to saying star of X plus zero equal to 10 and with just nothing but sort of x
equal to 10.
So this is how it's going to work.
Maybe I want to put something yet again to x of one equal to 20.
This would put 20.
I hope this is clear.
And if you want to delete this array so you can delete as the keyword that frees up their dynamic memory
and followed by square brackets if it is any.
And followed by the name of Daddy.
That's it.
It is going to delete this memory.
Now this memory will not get deleted.
Elder function call is not over.
OK, so this.
This is in the hand of compiler, and this is in the hand of programmers.
OK.
So generally, this memory you can allocate on their own time and you have to free this up.
The compiler does not delete this memory, even if the function calls over and after the program is
finished executing, all the memories are destroyed, OK, because everything is a part of the program
memory.
But during the execution, if you want to free this up, you should use this delete upgrade.
If you don't use it and you don't need that particular area or, for example, you lose the address
of this, Eddie.
And you don't you forget to use this delete statement.
In that case, a condition arises which we call as a memory leak.
That means we have wasted some part of the memory which we are not using, and we don't have the address
to reach that particular memory.
Let me show you an example of memory leak.
Let us see an example of memory leak.
For example, you have a function on that function.
You say OK in Star X equals some.
Eddie, in New Zealand, you followed by 100 and then you do some work, maybe you do X or Y equals
two X or Y a minus one plus two for all values off.
I agree that an equal to one.
Maybe you better look kind of us stuff.
And later on, you're done some x thing.
OK, you said it done the last well of this.
What is going to happen is when you call this function, it's going to create a dynamic memory.
And when this function call is over, this X is gone.
You know, this addresses when to get lost and you have not returned and deleted treatment, any of
it.
And now there is no point at which is pointing to this memory.
So that means we have already wasted this memory and this is going to cause a memory leak.
So when you're writing code, you should try to avoid memory leaks.
And in many applications which run our servers, if you start creating memory leaks, then your server
will get full at a certain point and it will stop working normally.
OK, you will get some errors, memories for or you may not be executed or other programs on your server.
OK.
It's a critical thing.
You should handle memory leaks in your code, and that's all for this lecture.