Everyone in this lecture, I'm going to give you a demo of working with dynamic areas.
So let's see how we can create one at it.
And also we can delete it.
So we have main.
And suppose I take and put away Lewin, and I want to create a dynamic area of size and.
They will write and study equals Nuland.
And here I can give, say then and then you can also do initialization, maybe using a loop or something.
I lived in Ecuador, I lived in an A-plus place.
I knew in the area of I.
Equals LHC.
And maybe we want to print these values as well.
I can see that if they.
So let's build this good.
And try to run it, we have dynamic that is demo.
So maybe I won't do have an array of 10 elements, and you can see this is how we can create area of
an image as oppose.
At this point, my work is done.
I want to free up this memory.
I can delete the city and I can say, OK, let's delete.
This edit, and that's it, so this memory will get freed at this point before coming to return zero.
What happened is we have at every level in mean we have a dynamic it in heap.
So this is your family.
So when we come to this line by this line, we have already deleted this part of the memory, but this
video will still store the address of this address later.
This values to zero four.
So this and this will still persist in the memory, OK?
Because.
It doesn't the.
Starting memory, OK, so it is the memory of the main function and main function is not yet over.
OK.
Main function is over when this block is finished.
Even if I do see out error here, I will still get the address of that particular day.
OK.
So let me show it to you.
So if those are 10 elements so you can do this is the address of the area on this address would be same
as this one.
OK, I'm just going to.
Trying to clear the concepts, OK, so when you delete the.
So the static address doesn't get deleted until the long term goal is over or the scope of variable
as it is there, then it will not get destroyed, but the dynamic memory will definitely get destroyed.
So if I give 10 hit so you can do these two addresses are same, but maybe let us try to print what
is the right area of two maybe sealed area off to?
Now, let's see what what happened in this case.
Although we're still getting to oh, we're still getting to, but there is a possibility that.
So what happened is in this case, we had a heap at a particular memory location.
We are there to do.
We put it on.
We had appointed to this memory.
Now when we use the delete command, this record destroyed.
But that doesn't mean the data which is presented may or may not have the same value case or data that
is present at this look.
Data present aren't.
Address, it may get overridden by some other.
Some other data on the old data may persist, or you may might get segmentation fault as well.
So this behavior is not predictable, so ideally we should not do this.
So this is not recommended because we have deleted the edit.
So I hope this short demo about one bit is this clear.
And in the next lecture, I will give you an example of how we can create 2D dynamic videos.
OK, so let's see.