Hillary won in this lecture, we will talk about how we can create or to redefine McGeady.
We have seen how one dynamic that is created.
Now we want to create a two degree that's like a grid like structure like this.
And the problem here is we don't have any direct way of creating an initializing or to rely on me getting
like we have for a start degree.
OK.
So if you want to create a very simple delivery, you simply do entry, followed by the number of rules
and followed by the number of columns.
But this kind of initialization you cannot do for a dynamic area.
The what is going to happen is we have to allocate memory, Roberto.
OK, so we have to do work for each rule.
So first, we will allocate this little.
And we will store the address maybe later this addresses one zero zero, then we will allocate this
address this little and we will accept this addresses 800 and it is not necessary that they follow the
same order.
Then we will allocate the next crew and we will add to this addresses 600.
And maybe then we are allocate this one unless this addresses for fourteen hundred.
The idea is we will I over our laws and we will allocate these rows one by one.
OK, one by one.
We are going to allocate.
Roars on each row is a one deity.
Okay, so we are going to combine multiple one, there is two former two.
Now you may ask, what about these addresses, where we're going to store these addresses?
We will need another three.
OK.
And we will tour the address of the city and let me talk about the relationship we are storing there.
One two three four five.
Each of these bags is going to be in digit and the was.
Now you want to store the address of this little or so this is going to going to be of the type in.
This is going to be an array of pointers.
So this all or this, this is a special area.
This is going to be an area of pointers.
And we also need to store the address of this particular city.
OK.
We actually will make something like instant dot.
Followed by name of day, we have appointed variable that stores the address of this city and this at
store the address of each store.
This is how we are going to allocate to the dynamic.
Now this may sound confusing, so let us create a function that creates the city and returns the address
of this particular area.
OK, so now let me show it to you and start start.
It's a great story area.
It's a this is a function, this accepts the number of roles and the number of columns and sentences
are dynamic area we can return the area from.
This meant that it will not get destroyed even if we create this array inside of a particular function.
Now first, I will create this variable and start study and I will initialize it with.
With the area of.
And start OK on this would be besides would be equal to the number of troops.
OK.
What we did, we first created this part.
We first created the city.
And in this edit, each element is of the type done on this starting address is of the type of in-stores
done.
OK.
So I hope this this is cleared and now we are going to iterate over each at all.
Let me let me show it to you.
What we are trying to do before first, we created a bucket that can store the address of an array of.
That can store the address of an area of pointers.
OK, so we have.
Pointers.
OK.
This is an area in stocks.
This each bucket is of the diaper and stuff.
OK, so we have a roll number of elements in this.
Now we are going to iterate over the city and we are going to say, OK, you go over each row and look
at a new area like this.
So let me let me show it to you four and I equals two zero.
I less than the number of rows I + +.
And I can say at Delphi.
OK, so that means we are talking about this box later.
This is the IoT box.
So this is that Delphi.
This should point to a new area which has column number of columns at Delphi should be called NEWID
on each boxes of the table.
And that's it.
So this is how we allocate memory for each at all.
OK.
And maybe we also want to initialize this array with some value or give in, let's say, increasing
list of numbers.
So maybe I can see value equals zero and then I can.
I dread over the city for individuals to zero.
I less than the number of rows I + + + four and Jake will do zero j less than the number of columns.
Duplex plus the creation bar doesn't belong.
OK, so Creation Bar does this much.
Only are now we're just putting some values it.
So we are saying at F I and G, this is going to be called the value.
And they do valuable as plus.
And from here, I can return the city.
I've done this run this my third way because I want to tell you, even if you even if this function
call is over.
Since this ad is dynamically allocated, you can still access these values inside the main method.
OK.
So let us dig in.
But the number of roads and columns from the user and rose columns seen rows, columns and let's create
a variable and dart area that makes this function called create two D.A.R.E..
I give rows and columns here and then I can.
I trade and print all the elements of the city for into equal to zero.
I left the number of rows I + + four and equal to zero less than the number of columns, tables plus
I can the code area of I and G, followed by space and followed by new line here.
So let's build Discord and let's try to run it.
Maybe four or three columns, so I have four rows, three columns, and I can see this city OK, maybe
seven rows and six columns.
So this is how it looks like.
OK.
So I hope this initialization is clear.
So one important thing that we learned from this lecture is that if it was a static area, then you
cannot access the content in men.
But it's a dynamic area that means it is not the memories outside the scope of the goldstuck.
OK, so we called mean that had a variable known as error.
It called another method that was created already this method.
Created a variable error, which pointed to a.
To the area and this slide in the hip memory, once this function call is over.
This area is gone.
But later this address was handed, which was stored in error.
And this was returned to the mine.
So now man is able to point to this memory and this connection is gone.
And we are able to print the elements of this memory from the mine and we are able to do it because
it is a dynamic memory.
I hope now the concept of dynamic memory allocation are crystal clear to you, and that's all for this
module.
Thank you.
Bye bye.