Everyone, now we are going to look at very small example of a device operator.
So we need to write a function to check whether a number is or not even OK, so not even a function.
Even we can write a small expression to check whether a number is or not even OK.
So one thing you might know is vegan simply do.
And less do if this gives us zero, then we can say the number is even if it gives us one, the number
isn't OK.
But since we are learning about Bitwise operators, we want to solve this problem using the Bitwise
operator.
The one thing you will observe is all the hard numbers will have the last word as one and all the even
numbers will have last, but does zero.
OK, so I'm writing for.
So this number is one.
This number is two, this number is three.
This number is four.
This number is five.
One thing you can clearly observe is what are the number four four numbers?
The last word is one.
And it contributes to the triple zero.
That is one Sudans.
And that is what it makes the number look.
So everything else is that you are no OK.
Everything else is that you are number.
That means the last, but decide whether the number would be hard or it would be even.
What we need to do.
We need to check if last bit as one.
Or it is not OK, what we can do is, let's say we have some numbered zero zero zero one zero one zero
one one.
What we can do, we can do.
And with this one?
OK, what is this one?
This one is studying where zero zero zero zero zero zero zero zero and one if you do an idea and what
could be a possibility doing it?
And so we have lots of zeros.
Yet the only thing we will get these are the last positions.
If the last position is one, that means this position was one, OK?
And that means there's no resort.
But suppose the last position, if it is zero, then we will get a zero hit.
That means this number is actually even OK.
So I hope you understood how we can check whether the numbers are not even the let me show you a quick
demo in the court as well.
So if I have, let's say.
They scored.
I can simply wonder if those so index see next, I can check if X and one I can see out art is I can
see out.
So, Dalsgaard, if I give five survivors or if I give it it is even if I give 32.
It's hard.
It's even if I give 33.
It's hard, OK, 32 days, even 33 years old.
So I hope now you understood how we can use this and one who find out the last word.
OK.
And that's it.
That's it for this lecture.
So thank you for watching.
Goodbye.