Everyone's in this lecture will see how you can count, but count the number of segments in a particular
number.
So what I said, but said Brits are those Brits, which are one, for example, if I give you the number
nine, which is like one zero zero one, then I can say it has doubled, which are said words.
I want to count the number of red bits in the binary representation of any number.
That's what we need to know.
So let us see how we can approach this particular problem of accounting standards.
So let us discuss the approach.
So it's pretty easy.
So we know the number is stored like this and we also know how we can find out the last bit so we can
do around with one.
And this will tell us what is the last bit we will get to know?
Get this with this one.
And for the next iteration, what we can do, we can remove this bit by doing the right shift.
Okay, so we can see the last bit does an end one.
And if this is one, then I will increment the count of my side.
But if it is zero, I will not increment the count OK, or I can simply rate let's initial count zero,
then then again, to count plus equals two and one.
The last word is one.
Then count will increment by one of the last four to zero.
The count will increment by zero.
And I want to remove this so I can to any Puerto Nightshift one.
The next time you will get one and zero, it will be zero count will change by zero.
Next time it would be you remove this one, zero and one, it would be still zero.
So count will change with zero.
Next time you remove this one and run it as one two count will increment by one final count would be
two.
OK, so this is what we can do.
So I can write the function count because I get the numbering and there I can see why and is greater
than zero.
What I can do every time find out the last bit like in the end, last bit.
I don't know when we begin to count that to zero.
And here I can find out the last bit.
So last, but there's nothing word and one, and I can say count plus equals to last bit.
OK, if it is, one count will change.
One one zero count will not change.
And then we can do as an equal and right shift one.
And from here, we can read and count.
So will go to what I can say in 2013 and again, to see how it conflicts off.
And that's it, and I hope this is now clear to you.
And what we're doing is we're doing a very simple operation every time we are doing the right shift.
OK, so we do it.
And here this goes off.
Next time these two bits are indirect, OK?
And.
Finally, we will get to one here, so this one is added to the count.
So this we will do for all debates on voting no and the at most the number of segments is going to be
long, often OK.
The number of times this loop is going to run, it is going to run at most log, oftentimes a number.
And because a number and has log of and but that you can easily verify by taking some example, let's
say 16 16 is like this.
Those 16 has.
It's led to this.
The ballot for it would have it.
Most voters wondered if it's OK about seven.
So it's going to be around two days to divide three.
So seven is going to have it.
Most attributes log off.
Seven is close to three.
Log of 16 is close to four.
That's what I'm trying to say.
So for any number, you have a log in bits and.
OK, ground ground does not declared so this should be and B and yes, we are done and now we can actually
run our code and see the dog slash gun because if I get 16 16, there's only one bullet if I get 15
15 as voted.
But if I give it, it has also one side of it.
So that's all for this lecture.
Thank you.