Everyone, so now we're going to talk about how you can do forced experimentation using wet masking,
so you might not have heard about this dumb bird.
But this is an important concept that we use as a problem in many of the problems because a lot of experimentation,
it's basically computing, it is truly power and there is no art and there's also an ability of favorites
to the power three.
This is 125.
OK, let it relates to the power of faith and it says three multiplied by five times.
OK, so train to trains 927 into three is 81.
81 into three years to 43.
OK.
So this is what five six one engine means.
And if you simply do this multiplication and number of times, it will easily take orders of any time.
But we are going to do it in a better manner.
We are going to do it in a log of and day, and I will teach you how you can do it.
OK.
So let's say we have some number a let's say, three and we have and let's have faith and we want to
compute it is to devouring.
So what I will tell you is you try to visualize this operation like this.
This is three days to deepen our faith.
And what do you do?
You convert this faith into its binary representation, let's say three days to the one zero one.
OK.
So this is just for understanding purpose.
And later, we will see how to read it in the form of a good.
So what this basically tells us, if you talk about how many bits a number is going to have, so any
number and will have it most than words if you talk about letter number 15 15 has four words that is
log off 16 or 15 plus one, that is.
So one more than log of and let's in the worst case.
And let's talk about the number eight.
OK.
It also has one triple zero.
So that is again, log off and plus one that is that most number of bits that it is going to have a
log of it is three plus one that is four.
It is being diagnosed four, which is what is 15.
The log of have been is roughly close to four.
Four plus one is five or it is three three plus one is for that, most of which it is going to have.
So for any number, then we are going to have at most log in number of setbacks.
OK, although every number is a 32 bit number.
What I'm saying the last segment would be a deposition log in or log in, plus one, get that.
That's a property that we should note.
So what we need to do is if you're writing, it is to the power in, let's say, three and is five.
So we will write or get three is one zero one.
And what we are doing, we're going to iterate over these positions.
We'll give you a window outraged over the bits of N.
And every time what we can do, we can generate some powers.
OK, so at this point, this is nothing, but we can write it as.
The number itself at this point, we can rotate it as a squad.
And at this point, we're going to write it as if what we're doing as we're going from left to right.
We are going to do a work.
We are going to start from.
It is to devour one.
And every time we are going to the next bit, we are going to square the previous power.
OK, so now what you can observe is, you know, if you if you are able to generate these powers and
then by multiplying a subset of these powers, you can actually get relays to the power of faith hope.
So if you look carefully that this is one if you pick this power and if you discard this power and if
you put this forward and if you multiply these two, what you are doing get you're going to get it is
to power forward.
Multiplied by eight is to devour one, which it is to devote faith and is what is three three.
It has to devote faith.
So this is going to give you the result.
81 multiplied by three.
That is 243.
OK.
So basically, by just iterating over the bits of that number, we get to know what, what, what we
need to multiply.
Now you may ask how we will implement it.
It's very easy.
So initially, we'll take our answer to be one.
We'll get that there's three illustrative of a zero.
Then we will find out what is the last word of five.
So it is one.
And what is the current power we have?
That is it.
So we will multiply it, answer with it.
We will discard this, but we will move on to the next position and we will square our value.
OK, so let's say.
Ballad of.
So this was initially one, this was then after the next step, this bubble became a squid and the big
what is the next bit?
Initially, the world was one, the next big zero.
If it is zero, we're not going to do any work here.
OK, so we go to the next position.
The power of is now a fourth because we squared the previous value and the Britain's No.
One we are talking about desperate.
So if it is one, we are going to multiply this effort in never answered.
And our answer is going to become your faith.
And now if you extract the next book, it is going to be become zero.
And we we are we have already covered all the segments of Facebook and we are finally what we are going
to have.
You're going to have, Iran said.
That is equal to a faith.
OK.
And since this number in her blog, in which we could just find out this in order of love in vain.
So I hope this concept is clear, and now we can quickly jump into the as well.
So I'm going to write the method, let's.
And first explain intuition, then I get the number.
I get the number and I can say, OK, let's assume overruns.
It is one.
And while this number and this is greater than zero, we are going to find out the last word, last
word does not invert and then one and have the last word said.
Then we are going to do some work.
Otherwise, we are just going to compute the next biography.
The next biography would be it.
That is, the previous power into itself squared the previous research.
And then and would be updated as an equal to end right shift one.
Every time we are discarding one bit from the right, we are doing an equal when Richard won and initially
is equal to eight.
So this is a then it becomes in is good and it becomes is good into a good idea for.
So this is actually multiplying the previous powers.
So if the last word is say, then what we need to do, we need to multiply our answer with whatever
until we have multiplied with the current power off.
OK, so that is that may be a that maybe a fraud, whatever it may be, but we know that this air contains
the right power.
So from here, what we can do, we can return our answer and we are done, we can say, in a coma and
scene end and begin to see out fast.
Explain intuition and and and.
And now, if I show it to you how it is going to work, I can see it maybe is three and is five.
I get the right answer is to an extent I get the right answer is five, b three and three.
I got the right answer.
I hope this is now clear.
This is what we are exactly doing.
We are upgrading of it answered when the last word is one and we will also have the right power of a
generator because of this repeated squaring of the values.
OK, so that's it for this lecture.
Thank you.