Everyone in this lecture, we're going to discuss how we can convert a decimal number into its binary
representation using the Bitwise operators, OK?
So what I'm going to do, I'm going to write a method, invert and convert to.
Binary, and I'm going to get to Digit.
And let's say they're indeed it is nine, I will return a number which looks like one zero zero one.
OK.
So am I doing this or this enough?
I'm over.
Indeed, it.
Now, let's see how we can solve this problem, so it's easy.
What we need to do is, let's say this is a no.
And we know how to extract the last breath every time we will extract this bit and we'll create the
answer variable.
OK, the answer is initially zero, we will add one to it.
It will become one.
OK, our next time we're going to discard this bit by doing the right shift and equal to end right shift
one.
And we are also going to maintain a power is initially one that will multiply one with one and add to
the undertow because it is exactly one into one.
We next time this is actually 10 days to depart zero.
This is ten days to the one.
This is ten square and desist and what we're going to do.
We're going to generate the powers of time in the next iteration.
This power would be come in and we see this better zero.
OK, so this is what we will do will do zero.
And then the answer is not going to change, but we are going to discard this and we are going to go
ahead and the pilot will become 10 squid.
So next time we get this bit, this is zero and multiply 10 squid.
This is zero and it is not going to change.
It is still still one.
But next time, what is going to happen will discard this debate is going to become 10Q and we see this
better one.
OK, so this bit is one basically we can see for this big move on the island one thousand over answered.
So we will add one in ten days to the power three.
If you see what would be your final answer, it would be one plus and is do three.
That is, it's going to be one thousand one.
And this is how the binary representation of nine would look like.
OK.
So I hope you understood the logic now and try to go to it yourself.
And if you are stuck, then take the help from this tutorial.
So what I'm going to do and when you take input and I'm going to convert it into binary, OK?
And what I can do, I can see initially, the answer is zero.
The power is one.
And while this end is greater than zero, I'm going to extract the last bit that is and then one.
And I'm going to add something to my answer.
So answer would be incremented by a value of power in the last bit.
And for the next iteration, power will be multiplied with the then.
Initially, it is one then a decision, then then good and then Dan Gilbert and and would be there to
that end, right shift one.
That's it.
And we are done.
And from here, we can return the incident.
Let's build the gold, so begin to see out, convert to binary and we give the input and here.
And now let us boast over cold weather, it looks fine or not.
So what we need to do is go to the terminal and I can convert.
Decimal, divine.
OK.
No, Austin.
OK, so if I give then as in bodyguard, one zero one zero as the output, which is fine, if I give
15, then I get one one one, which is the binary representation of this particular number.
That's all.
Thank you.