Everyone in this lecture, we will talk about some common operations that we can do using great ways
operators.
So let us look at some examples.
Let's say we want to get the I a bit of a no.
For example, let's say the number is five.
And in binary, it would look something like this zero zero one zero one and the numbering of bags that
I'm going to do is from the right.
So this is the zero Typekit.
This is the first, but this is the second and so on.
If I say, OK, give me the second, but then I'm talking about this, but I want to check the value
of this particular debate, OK?
Similarly, there would be a function like that I admit or update, I admit, then clearer, it would
then clear a range of it.
So we are going to see multiple functions in this set of lectures.
So let us start with the first one.
I want to get the IoT back.
Often, no.
And so now you may ask, OK, how we can extract that Typekit, so it's going to be pretty easy itself
and his faith and the position of the desire that I'm going to take input, OK?
And we will bring the IoT big of.
The number.
OK, so now let's see how we can do it, so we know we can use device operators, we're told.
So if I do something like this, if I have, let's say, one zero one, OK.
And I actually want to extract this particular bit.
So we have seen how to get the last word OK.
So we basically do with the armed wing of one, but doing it and one will not help us in this case.
So what we want, we actually want a variable in which we have, uh.
We have one at this particular location and everything else is going to be zero, so if I put everything
else as zero, then I will get this number.
And how do I get this number?
There is nothing, but it is one left shift.
I, if you left shift one items.
Okay, so I is two, OK and we are talking about zero one.
We are talking about this week.
So one left you have two basically means this number one zero zero, which is this.
And if you do and here what you're going to get, you're going to get a number.
Zero zero zero one zero zero.
OK, because everything else is zero.
So doing a nine will convert everything else into zero.
And for this position, since you have one here, so doing around with one will give you this number.
Now you can check if this number is greater than zero.
That means the better one.
And if this number is equal to zero, OK, which would happen if this were to zero, then you can say
this is actually zero.
So what we need to do, we need to create a small variable little mosque.
OK, I'm calling this number as a mosque and we will do the and with the mosque will get to mosques.
And I think one left shift I and I can see the last bit is nothing but the number and mosque.
OK.
If I do that and and if it gives me a desert which is greater than zero, then I can return one.
Otherwise, I can return zero and this is going to give me the IoT big.
So let's run the code and see.
So if I do Dodge Slash while I'm on operations, I could tell you in the second part of five, there
it is one.
Tell me the first bit.
It does zero.
Tell me what does it not?
It does one that means it is working fine.
So that's all for this lecture.
See you in the next video.