Everyone, the next thing that we're going to look at is how do we sit together, we need to write a
function.
Lloyd said I had to break and we get the number and we get the position.
So one thing you're going to do is you can take this number by different and you can change the value
here or you can return the new number, OK?
So maybe another way to make this function is like this?
OK.
And here you have to return to new value.
So maybe I want to go with the first one because we we want to change the value of and in the function
itself.
So let's see how we can do it.
So it's actually very easy, very similar to what we have seen in the, let's say, the number is five.
And I want to say the first bit.
OK.
I want to say the.
Well, that's great, that is this one.
OK, so what I need, I need to do our operation a bit visit with the number, which looks like this
zero one zero, which is a tad bit at the either index.
OK.
And I had a virtual visit, so what we need to do, we need to create a mosque that is again, this
number is going to be one left shift.
I will get this number.
And we will do a bit raised with the value of.
And so let's see so we can see and mosque equals one left shift.
And what we can say we can do.
Let's update the value of an as and or mosque.
And we are done.
Now, if the number is five, if I say, OK, I get it, but OK, I can say void, I can do it, said
I had it.
Instead of calling this, I can call, so I had to beg.
I give the value of an hour and I and maybe I print the new value off.
And so let's try to run this.
I say, OK, I said the first bit, so you can see after getting the first bit, the result is seven,
which is fine if I said the zero two, but then the third will not change because that rate is already
13 five.
So that's all.
That's how it is going to work.
So we are getting this number one one one by setting the I estimate as one.
That's it.
See you in the next lecture.