Hi, everyone.
So now we are going to look at how we can clear the air Typekit OK.
So basically if we have a number like, let's say, one one zero one and I want to delete this word
and I want to make it zero, OK, I want to clear the I had it, so I is due for this example.
Let's see what I need to do.
I need to create a number in which only this zero.
Only this bitter zero and rest, everything else is going to be won, so I need this as zero and rest,
everything is one.
Look, can you guess how we can get this particular kind of a number, OK?
The one thing we know is that we want to work on the of so we can create a mosque using one love Jeff
Day.
It will give us something like this zero one zero zero.
OK, that is fine.
And how do we get this number?
It is nothing, but it's a.
It's a not of this number, so but why not?
So what we need to do, we need to do a negation here and we once we are getting this, what we can
do, we can do.
And if we do it and all these beds will be reserved, so we will get one zero one.
And since we have a zero here, zero and something, it is going to get zero.
So that's it.
So this is going to clear the eye had the boot.
So if I show you the mosque now, the mosque is going to be nothing, but not off one day.
And what you need to do, you need to update the world often so you don't need to set any goals do and
mosque and we are done then sort of calling retired.
But I'm going to call earlier.
I had to I give in and I.
And let us clear the air.
So this number isn't what.
One two four eight.
This is this number is 13.
So if I say, let's end it 13, and I want to clear the second, but.
If 13, I want to clear the second.
I should get a number, which is nine zero one two.
Yes.
So let's see.
I want to clear the skin, but oh.
OK, I need to run this code, build this code first.
The first lady is second convict.
I'm getting the output, which is exactly equal to nine.
OK.
So I hope this is clear to you and this is how we can clear any break in a number.