Everyone in this lecture, I will teach you an interesting property, how you can check whether a number
is a power of two or not.
OK.
And we will use Bitwise operators to do this check.
So let us talk about the power of two, let's say, 16, the number, which is a power of two or eight,
the number, which is a power of two thought is 16 16 in binary.
Looks like this.
Yes.
And what I can do is this led to this number is in.
Can you tell me what would be n minus one two?
Clearly, we know the N minus one would be.
Something like this, if and if and is about off.
OK, so we know event is a power of two, then the previous number would look something like this.
So there's no reason to live.
Have been an interesting property is if an is a power of two, then doing the end of these two will
always give me a zero.
OK.
And you can see this number is zero.
It is true for eight and seven as well if it is like this.
And seven is like this.
And if you do it and it of eight and seven, then you will get the number zero.
But this will not be true for any other number.
For example, five five is one zero one.
What is Ford?
So Ford is one double zero.
And if you do it it, you will not get a zero.
OK.
So basically, the check is if if you get something like this, if and and and minus one, if they produce
a result that is equal to zero, then that means inizio power off.
OK.
So simply what we can do in the cold, we can take input end and they can check if and and and minus
one.
And I mean, we put a record here.
If this is equal to zero, then you can see CO2.
Yes, power of two.
As you can see, not a power of two.
OK, so let's relate.
Ran it and take it quickly.
So wonder indeed.
Yes, it is a bubble of two, one, two and 144.
It's not the power of two.
OK, and one 024 is a power of two.
And 12, it's not over.
So yes, it's working fine.
So it's romantic without doing anything with just this island operation with and minus one, we can
tell whether a number is Bobroff do or not.
That's it for this lecture.
Thank you.