I would everyone in this lecture will talk about to the.
So what is a suitable pseudocode as a human readable description of an algorithm?
OK?
To those who don't know what is an algorithm to algorithm is nothing but a sequence of steps that we
take to solve a particular problem.
We have drawn flowcharts, so those steps in the flowchart, they represent a particular algorithm.
OK?
And what is the pseudocode?
So the code is not the real code, OK?
It is not the code that the machine can execute.
It's a good that is written in plain English in a human readable form.
OK, so now why it is helpful.
So as a beginner, it is helpful if you want to write something that is language independent, OK?
If you want to write a code and that you want to get it reviewed from a person who does not know a particular
language like C++ or dollar or Python, so you can write it in the form of a pseudo code, so it will
help you to write language, independent code or a review.
It will help you to structure your code before you actually start writing a tool kit.
Suppose you are not very sure about the structure of your code, and you want to see if it will work
in corner cases or it will pass all the tests so you can write it quickly in plain English and then
you can verify that this code works or this code does not look OK.
So it is the fastest way to verify to get a review as well.
OK.
That is what Pseudocode is.
So you can come up with their own notation of writing Sudoku.
But there are a few basic ways of writing it, so we can discuss one of those ways to define the pseudocode
instructions.
So in a word, flowchart, we have discussed almost six type of instructions OK?
The first was start or end two into the code.
We generally don't have anything for this type so that we will skip, but we will have exit for the
end.
If you want to the note end of a program, you can write exit.
OK, then we discussed that we have input and output, so in order to do input and output, you can
read a number and that is how you will write it or you want to print something, you're going to print
the number and or print them with print.
There are two things maybe you want to print something either does.
So maybe you want to print Hello.
This will go into double codes.
If you want to print the value of something like you want to print the value of some, you will put
it without double quotes.
OK, that will print whatever is present inside the same bucket.
And I thing that we have seen is assignment, you want to give a particular value to a variable, but
example you want to see marks equal to 80.
That is written like this, using this symbol equal to, OK, so that what's the number 80 inside a
bucket called marks?
OK.
That is what assignment is to assignment can also take the form of simple interest equals to be into
our entity of 100.
This is also assignment, OK?
So you have multiply it.
This is also a form of assignment.
What you're doing, you're evaluating the expression and you're putting the value of this exploration
inside a bucket called simple interest.
So this is also an example of assignment.
The next thing that we have seen in flowchart is a conditional box.
OK is a conditional box, depending on the condition being true.
We take one of the two directions either yes or no, that is represented using something known as if
it's.
If a condition is true, then do this thing.
OK, so if followed by the condition, for example, in this case, if I was less than an.
Then do this work, OK?
Otherwise, if this condition is false, then I will look elsewhere, do this work, OK?
So if has its own block and has its own block now, there are ways to denote the opening and closing
of the blocks in Python.
There is a concept of indentation that means we will leave this space empty before writing these instructions
that basically tells that these instructions as part of this block in other languages like C++ and Java,
we have curly brackets here that denote.
The starting and ending of this blog, what introductions are part of if we denoted using curly brackets
into the logo, you can also use then and end to denote the starting and ending of the block.
So it is then and and I personally do not write before writing, then again, because it makes the code
more.
Linda and I personally like these curly brackets.
OK.
The whenever we will work with the language, we'll follow the rules of the language.
But into the code, you can use anything, you can use indentation, you can use curly brackets, you
can use then and it's totally your choice.
We have seen how to write up a false statement as well.
Another thing that we have is called as a loop.
OK.
So we have seen that we can simulate a loop using flowcharts.
Well, let's let's recall an example of a look, so he said, let Michael Ausiello, then we said,
OK, is Islas then?
And there is no separate component for loop inside of LoJack.
But we represented a loop.
Using some components, OK, and then we started, I all like this one.
This is how we created a loop inside of low-Tech.
By combining multiple different boxes.
So far, look to have we had an initial rendition.
We had defined a stopping criteria when to stop.
We had to find some work that is repeated inside a loop.
And we had defined a bad condition.
OK.
How to update the variable that is part of the stopping condition inside the loop in order to represent
this part of the code.
This part of the flowchart, we have something which is called by loop.
OK.
And this is common across all programming languages.
So how do we write it?
Let us see an example of this flowchart written in the pharmaceutical will write I equal to zero, then
we will take a while.
I is less than 10, followed by curly brackets.
OK, so this is the condition, the this condition is true.
This part of the code that will be written here.
OK, whatever work you want to do, this will be repeated continuously and then you will have I will
do I +1.
This part of the code.
Is running again and again, OK, until this condition is true.
So you do some work, you in agreement, you again go ahead.
You check the condition.
You do some work.
You again come in.
And once this condition becomes false, OK, you come out of the loop and you ended.
OK, so if this condition is false, that means, no, you come here and then you at exit, that head
will go ahead and then you will exit.
These are six basic types of instructions that you will find in every programming language and from
the next video.
We will discuss some examples of pseudocode and will try to convert our changes charging the code.
So that's all for this video.
Thank you.