I would want in this lecture and find out the sum of numbers from one twin, I will write to Pseudocode.
OK.
So in the flowchart, the first step was to read and then we discussed what we need to maintain.
What is the no, OK, so what is the current number?
So we'll start from Michael to one, then we will make it do, we'll make it three will make it forward
and we will go.
OK.
And during this, we will also update our son.
So what we will initially, two things will be OK.
I S1 the initial value of the number and the sum is zero.
So in order to do this, think we need a look, right?
And for that, we discussed that we can use available to we had while followed by certain condition.
We'll see what that condition is.
That condition would be nothing but while.
This value of I.
OK, this value of AI is less than equal to N, if this is less than equal doing, we can keep on updating
overtime so we can get some equal to someplace.
So this is the work that we will do in every step, and we will also go to the next value of life that
is like gold.
Like this one, after we are out of the loop, we can print the value of some and then begin to exit.
That's it.
That is how we can write the pseudocode.
OK.
So if you want to go to a dry run this one so we can talk.
The sum is zero is one that equals I'm blessed because one is less than equal to four.
It's endless for so some becomes zero plus one.
That is one.
I becomes what I becomes two.
OK.
And it was less than equal to for Sam, equal to someplace, plus some becomes one plus two.
That is three.
I becomes three.
Now I becomes three three is less than equal to Ford and some blasé, so some becomes plus 3.6.
OK.
And I comes forward to it takes up this value.
And again, for low as any, the before Suzanne becomes six plus four, that has been.
And I Begum's faith, so as we see the veil of I becomes five and it is not listening to this look will
stop and we will come to the line number 16.
That does bring some.
And here we will print Ben and we will exit.
OK, that means this pseudocode is working perfectly fine.
And that's all for this video.