Everyone in this lecture will discuss the pseudocode to check if a number is prime one or two.
Let us recall the flowchart that we have drawn to check a number is prime or not.
Now let us try to convert this flowchart into the code, OK?
The first step is read and look read and.
The next step is, Initialise, is because we are trying to find out it in the range to do n minus one,
so he's OK, let equal to two and here which is a smaller then.
And so here we also see that this is a part of a loop.
This part is done repeatedly.
We take while.
I is less than and are you going to do violence less than equal to n minus one?
Both are fine.
To hear what you're doing, you're repeatedly checking the foreign number and you're checking that,
is there any adviser in the range to do and minus one?
So the value of I is going from two trillion minus one that is less than to what you're taking hit.
Your checking is and divisible by.
So you will if it OK, this is this is not a look.
This is a starting point of the law.
This is if if.
And is divisible by I.
If an is divisible by then, what are you going to do?
You can simply say that this number is not prime and you can ignore.
This is what we have seen, so we're going to print.
Not Prime.
And begin to exit as soon as we get one device that.
We consider this number is not.
And we can exit, OK.
So for this very look, we have to stop being territorial.
We have written the work that needs to be done.
We have done the initial look and listen to what is left as the update condition, OK.
So if an is not divisible by, I then go to the next day.
OK.
That is basically the step I do one day, so it becomes I equal to a plus one.
I called up this one.
Now, if you come out of this vile loop, that means you could not find a device that in this range
it would do and minus one if suppose you get that he has a device that often you would simply hit the
exit.
But if you're not coming out of the loop, that means you have scanned all numbers still in minus one
and you could not hit the exit.
That is why you're coming to this line, where you going to print this as a prime number.
So basically this direction, if you come out of the loop, you can joke that this number is a prime
number.
And now you can hit the exit.
Your program is complete.
OK, now let us brighten this for an example, it's a seven.
So what happens, you start from two do does not divide seven, you make it three.
OK, we go to three to three is less than seven.
Three does not divide seven.
You make it four.
OK, so you come here again for what, less than seven?
Or does not divide seven?
So you come here.
You make it five.
Five does not divide, seven, you make it six fixes less than seven.
But six does not divide seven.
You will again come here.
And finally, you make it seven.
The value of I is now seven, which is not less than him.
And you end up with this line.
I knew circa seven is up and I'm am.
And that is true.
Seven itself is a prime number.
And then you exit a couple.
The number like nine.
OK, what happens about nine?
You start from an equal to two.
It does not divide it with less than nine.
Two does not divide nine.
So you come here, you make it three.
It is less than nine, but nine Model three.
This is equal to zero, and hence you print that nine is not time and exit writing exit here means nothing
below exit would get executed and that is the end of your program.
OK, so that is how you can draw a flowchart and to try to look good logic if a number is prime or not,
get so a quick recap of what we have done.
So we start from, let's say, riding bicycles to two while I is less than and keep on dividing, OK?
So if an is divisible by I.
Then you can say, OK, this number is not trying to bring, not prime and exit.
Otherwise, you go to the next location.
I called you, I +1.
And if you come out of the loop, that means you could not find a device that you can simply separate
prime and then you can exert, OK.
That is the complete robot for this program.
Thank you.
I hope you have understood this logic now.