I assume now we will discuss to write the pseudocode for the D3D problem, so given the numbers like
in me, we want to find out the D3D of the numbers, OK?
So for example, then British 18:20, we discussed the distasteful.
Another thing that we discussed in order to find that easily, we will iterate from one to the minimum
of the two numbers and we because the DCD can never be greater than the smaller number.
OK.
What we want to do while iterating over this range, we want to find the largest number.
That divides more than me.
OK, so this we will implement using all the words, so first of all, we will read the numbers in B,
and in order to iterate over this range, we will keep a bucket I that will store it on what value we
currently are.
So in the beginning, we get to this one and begin to give.
While this eye is less than equal to minimum of a comma, B will do some work.
OK.
So what we will do will take that visibility, so we'll check if it is divisible by and B is also divisible
by two.
In both of these cases, after dividing with, the remainder should be zero.
OK.
So if if both of these conditions are true, then what we can do we can look at if two divides both
20, then averages it is two, then we go to three, then we go to four and we do this thing for every
location.
To these Oakajee three equals two I.
Otherwise, what we can do, otherwise we can see.
If you, irrespective of this condition, is true or false, we will always try the next numbers will
to equals two plus one.
That's it.
I will complete the loop.
And now when we are out of the loop, we can print the value of DVD and begin to exit.
OK.
So this is how we'll compute digitally.
And you may ask not what happens if that is.
No, these you do, OK.
So in the worst case, if there is no device, either one would be at least one is the one.
One always divides two numbers and be OK if we ordinarily would be there to one.
For example, if you have seven and eight, you want to find easily.
So one divides a one two vote, seven and one divides B.
This really would be one.
And finally, if you print the DCT, the value of the city would be one.
So I hope you have understood this algorithm.
So we have exactly implemented what we discussed, OK?
So given the numbers like 1822, what we are doing, we are going from equal to one two three four up
to up to up to eight, and we are checking whether one divides.
But yes, then one is the decision to divide us.
But then do is that easily?
Who does not divide it nor object to the three fold divide would then vote is the decision.
And this continues on till the minimum value.
So finally, this is the value of the city that you will get the largest one.
So I hope you have understood this algorithm and that's all for this.
We you.