Everyone in this electoral cycle, the start button problem, so given away live and we want to bring
the burden like this, OK?
So first of all, we will try to break this burden to every time you, you get a pardon problem.
You have to look at what is the work that you have to do in every row because the printing happens.
Roberta, there are three rows for an equal to three civil write down some observations.
The first observation is that there are Andrews OK, and the second observation is in each row.
There are.
Or in Iowa?
Look, there are a number of stars.
These are the two observations during these two observations we can call this up.
So this is led to rule number one.
So one.
This is wrong.
Number two.
It has two stars.
This is rule number three.
It has three stars.
OK.
And how do you jump from one to another?
You have to print a special character, which is known as a new line corrected.
So all languages have this correct that it does not visible.
It's not printed like this, but it takes your cursor to the next line.
So whenever you print this correct, it takes the cursor to the new line.
OK.
That is the meaning of the new line, correct?
So let's write those who pseudocode for this problem.
So first of all, we'll read the value of an OK, and then we will need a loop to iterate over those.
So there are two things we have to print arrows repeatedly.
I can get laid equal to one.
While I was less than equal, doing what we will do will do the work for every rule.
OK?
What is the work that we have to do?
And I drew so in the ayato.
We have to print a number of times.
So that means printing high number of stars would again require a loop.
This would again required a loop current number of times.
So let's see how we can do it so we can look.
Let's do dodge equal to one.
While stars is less than equal to I.
What we will do will talk, will we will print a start.
We'll talk later, printers dot and let's increment the count of stars that we have printed the stars
as a variable or it's a bucket that is striking how many stars we are printing in the Andrew.
And that's it.
And after every rule, as we discussed, then we are going to the new rule, we have to print a new
line corrected that will take the good city to the next line for printing.
That's it.
And finally, we're going to exit the let us do a quick, dry run of this program.
So as one?
OK, what happened in the first through the stages one and we'll start less than equal to.
So this loop is going to run one times and it is going to print us.
Not after that.
A new line will come to me, come here and I becomes a plus one.
I becomes to again.
Resist dodges one.
OK.
That means this loop is going to run two times, so we print one and two.
OK, so the values of stars is changing from one to and either the stars that we are printing after
this, the value of I would become three.
And sides again start from one.
And we will print less than equal to three stories.
So that is one to three.
It will print three stars in the store.
So in each it'll.
This is how the value of stars variable is changing in the first world is one in the secondary during
the Third World is one to three and so on.
After this, the value of I would become.
And this is not less than equal to and hence we will stop and we will come out of the loop.
And this is a pattern that you will observe on the screen.
So I hope you have understood the start button, and that's all for this video.