I so now we will solve this pyramid pardon problem, so we have to print this kind of a burden for a
given.
And so in this burden, we have three rows.
And as you can see in each row, there are some spaces followed by some started OK.
So first of all, I will write the observations.
So the observation is there are Andrews.
OK.
And in each row, there are some spaces.
How in this business that we will figure it out?
Followed by some number of stops, OK, followed by some number of stunts.
We have to generalize this for any.
I threw.
So let us see what happened in this president.
If you look carefully that there are those places it.
OK, and they're the ones buried under zeros, basically zero, because we've right the number of spaces
in the air through two spaces, one space, zero space.
So as we are going down, as the value of I is increasing, OK, the number of spaces is decreasing.
We can see as one is two and three.
That is the rule number two.
Can you relate?
Can you generalize how many spaces are there in our group?
Clearly, we can see that this is nothing but three minus two to the three minus one.
That is, we have two spaces, OK?
In the second row, we have three minus the rule number.
We have one space in the third row, we have three minus three.
That is zeros.
But clearly we can get these spaces by doing.
And miners say in the Dietro era and miners ice business, this we figured out through our observation
the better and miners ice bases in the hydro.
Now, let us talk about the number of stars, how many stars we have one star, three stars and five
stars.
Let's figure out the formula for stars.
One Star Resort and five stars.
OK.
Now, let's see how we can generalize this one.
So the role no doubt, is a.
That is nothing but one, two and three.
So if you look carefully in the first rule, one starts, they wrote three star third Rule five stars
by observation.
I considered in in the intro that there is doing to a minus one stars because this value is nothing
but two into one minus one.
This is nothing but two into the minus one that is three.
This is doing two three minus one.
So yes, we are able to generalize the number of stars.
OK.
So again, this is through observation.
If you don't want to observe if you want to use a predefined formula.
So what happens is that the number of stars, the former sequence of the type, which is known as automatic
progression in a bizarre sequence.
Split the difference between two consecutive terms is consent.
So this is common difference, which is to this is common difference that just this different is constant
across all their terms.
So if you want to find out the item of this AP, there is a formula which is a plus a minus one in duty.
So what is it is the first dump b the difference between two consecutive terms.
So what is it?
Is one is A and B is due so you can do one plus do a minus two.
It does alter the way mine is, either you use the AP formula or you can use the observation, what
are going to give you the same result?
And hence we can see that there are two into a minus one stars.
In the eye.
OK, now we we have seen how to break down this pattern.
OK?
And after printing to a minus one size, I will also print a new line.
So now you can write the pseudocode for this problem, so that is very easy.
So first, we will read how many doors we have, then we will need a loop.
Why did our those first Rosekind again?
So let's say we are starting from the first rule.
We will go till the end that rule.
What we will do, we need you.
We will do three things.
First, we will print faces.
Let's face it is one how many spaces and minors spaces?
Wild spaces is less than equal to and minus.
What we will do will print a space and we will implement the ground of spaces that has been printed
by one.
That's it.
The next thing that we have to do is doing do a minus one start.
So let us print us.
Let's say the ground started this one wireless dodgers less than equal to two and do a minus one.
What we will do will print a style and will increment the count of stars by one.
The article to plus one gadget, followed by a new line, so we will talk it will print a new line.
And we will go to the next drill by doing a call like this one.
That's it.
That completes our zero vote.
And here we can write exit.
Now you can see this is how we have broken down our logic into smaller components.
This loop is responsible for borrowers.
And the inner parts responsible for.
Some part of the.
So this part is responsible for spaces in each row.
This is responsible for stars they need to do.
This is responsible for shifting the cursor to the new line.
And this I called my plus one maintains.
It is a great condition for the out-of-date book.
So.
This is how we can afford this burden now as a homework, you can write in this pardon on your own.
But I do write in this for and value and equal look forward and try to see what pattern do you get?
OK, so that's all for this video.
Thank you.