Everyone, so let us see how we can, right, reprogram.
So first of all, I will include some header files, and I'll stream is basically for doing input and
output, so we will use it for scene and see out we are, which are the input and output statements
in C++.
So what we will do?
Let's create the edit.
So let's say we have an array of marks and let's say we are just creating it for denser and OK.
Now we may ask the user, Okay, tell us how many students we want to give as input so I can do it and
then CNN and maybe let us increase the size of that.
That means we have reserved the memory for up 200 students.
But we will ask, OK, how many students we get?
We want to enter.
OK, so enter the number of students.
So that is OK.
I want to enter the marks of five students.
So what we will do, we will say OK board and I called to zero I less than an A-plus plus again.
So give me the marks of I had student because we are storing the marks from zero to minus one.
So this is how we are doing input.
And let us do output as well.
Again, default intake was to zero I less than an A-plus plus and again to see out marks off.
And let's give a comma and maybe and.
So that's it.
Let's build a good.
But less successful.
And let us try to underscored.
OK, I want to say I want to give marks of late to aid student only to the monks are 10, 12, 90,
80, 32, 44, 66.
OK.
And maybe there won't be.
So you can see we are getting these marks printed, so these are getting stored inside the memory.
And then we are printing it, OK, now what we did is I will just give you a quick recap.
So we made a very bold marks on this could have up 200 places, but we only used a small part of the
city.
OK, so this is 99.
This is zero one two three four five six seven.
We only used this much part of the.
And restored Mark's hit, we are trading from zero in minus one that is seven to these are eight students.
We said, OK.
Big put these values and to store them, because when is it scene marks of zero?
Whatever is the first input that will get stored in this particular value.
So maybe later this is 80 80 will get stored in.
Similarly, I'd seen on one enough to see marks of two marks of three Anton.
Similarly, we are doing as the old year.
OK, so this is all we can do input and output, OK?
It will also happen that you want to take.
Garden Wood from one, OK?
So in that case, what are you going to do?
You can say, OK, let us bring the values from one down and let us try to bring the values from one
to one.
And maybe you can say marks of zero equals minus one.
Maybe this is not defined.
You can also do something like this.
You can assign a value.
OK?
Or maybe you can also do an update that every marks should be multiplied by two.
Because of whatever marks you are getting should be multiplied by two.
So you can to marks off.
I.
Equals marks off, I multiplied by two.
Okay, so let us run this program again and see if I say I have only four students.
Alexa marks are 10, 20, 30 and 40, so you can see we're getting the output 20, 40, 60 and 80.
So we are able to update the values in the area.
Now you may ask.
We didn't get this value.
Why?
The reason is, although this value is getting stalled, but we're not printing it, we are starting
of a look from equal to one.
If I say this loop should start from zero, then you will see this value is also present.
I have four student, let's say, 10, 20, 30 and 40, and you can do this minus one is present at
zero.
The index and the next two values are already there.
OK.
And what happens if I printed in less than 100 in that case?
We have not done any initialization here.
What we will see, we will see the remaining will use would be a garbage.
So you can see we are getting these random values.
So these are because we are printing below and we have not seen any value at that particular point because
this is nothing but garbage.
But one thing we discussed, if we do the initialization of the eddy, then the remaining garbage will
become equal to zero.
So if I say OK, initialize the city with the first value is zero.
So if you do initialization of some element, then the remaining element automatically becomes zero.
OK, so even if you pull the minus one here and you remove the statement, you will see the remaining
elements of the eddy would automatically take this value of zero.
Or guess what?
LED to 10, 20, 30 and 40.
And you can see the remaining elements are always zero in this case, OK?
I hope you understood all these aspects of creating, updating input and output offer.
Eddy.
Let's see the next it.