Everyone in this lecture will talk about one important concept that you should don't when you're trying
to pass at is two functions, okay?
So let's discuss this concept and what are the intricate things that some people may miss while working
with areas and functions?
So let me create a new example and let me call it as they all do.
And again, we will have Io's dream namespace.
And what we will do maybe will create a simple function.
OK, and we will create a simple function to print that.
OK, let's call it as Braintree, and this function is going to accept the eddy.
And it is also going to accept the number of elements of that.
So why the number of elements that need it, I will tell you exactly why it is needed, the next excretory.
And let's initialize it one two three four five six.
And let's say this is the three.
And here I have not given the size, so I'm going to compute the number of elements.
These are very that means, oh, how much memory this is going to take.
So this is going to take six and offered 24 bytes and each element is of their type.
Indeed, it is.
I'm going to divide it by size of eight.
So this is one common practice you would often see.
This will give us 24 divided by food that is six.
We have six elements in this particular area.
So what I'm doing, I'm computing how many elements I did in this particular.
OK.
Now one thing we are going to do is I'm going to print size of.
Eddie, inside this particular mine.
OK, so maybe I can say we are in Maine.
And.
Let us do the same statement.
Let us run the same statement in the printed function, OK?
Yes.
So here what what you can see, we are getting a widening that size of very little on the size of all.
This area, and I will tell you what this is going to be.
So despite the warning, we are going to run the good because it's a warning, it's not a compilation
at it.
So what I'm going to show you, we are inside function.
So despite the warning, we are going to run the code and let me assure you, this is the road to Eddie.
And here we are.
Getting inside mean on the size of that is 24, which is fine.
We also should call this function, but integrity.
And here we are saying get taken the city and Dallas.
The size of the city, so now you can see inside mean the size is 24.
Inside function, the size is eight.
Now can you think of why this is happening, why this is happening?
The reason is inside mean we actually have already.
OK.
So inside, man, we actually have our edit, but inside the function, we don't have it, we just have
the address of daddy.
OK, we only have the address.
Of the Eddie.
So these addresses are stored in the form of variables known as pointer variables, and these variables
have a saves of eight bytes.
And this edit will have a size of depending on how many elements we have.
And this gives it a six undervote that is 24, right?
OK.
So one thing I want to tell you is if you do something like this, if you print that ahead, you can
simply do four intake will do zero less than an A-plus plus.
OK.
And you're going to see out at very.
So this is going to work.
This will work fine.
This we have already seen.
We know and this six, this look will work fine.
But if you do a similar thing here, if you do a similar thing, it.
So if you try to bring this error here, OK?
Let me show it to you.
This will not work as expected.
This will not work as expected, so we are printing this array inside me and we are also printing this
ad inside a function.
So let's.
Try to run this.
And you can see inside mean we are getting all the six elements inside function, we are just getting
there two elements.
The reason is we don't have the correct value of in here.
We don't know what is the number of elements yet because what is happening is.
Let me let me show you to what actually happened is when you created the city, this main has its own
local memory.
OK.
And this function, Braintree, this also gets when it gets called, it also gets in, gets pushed in
the call stack.
And this is the function Braintree.
So when you're passing this area here to here, OK, this does not happen by pass by value.
This happens by pass by reference.
OK, then instead of passing the area, you are actually passing the address.
This variable is actually the address of that is and I mean, you actually have the eddy that is located.
This size is 24 bytes.
But when you're passing the city, you are related.
This address is hundred.
So you're only storing this address here and this box occupies eight bytes.
Then you try to compute the value of in that the size of it.
So here this area is only of decided bytes divided by size of and that is food.
So you get this say this too.
And here you get 24 divided were for that six.
That is why this law works as expected and this will not work as expected.
OK?
So that's a mistake that we believe can do.
So you should always remember when you're passing, it is two functions, then the user is advised by
reference.
That means only their addresses, bust and undefined you can make in their indexes to make it more explicit.
You can use this diethood.
That means it is a pointer variable.
It's not a it's not that it's a pointer variable to both.
The previous index on this index are same.
You can either use this or you can use this manual by single error dual function.
OK, so let's build our code.
And let me show you again that this works in a similar manner.
And what may happen is now you want to actually print that inside the function to what you should do
is instead of computing the value of ended.
OK.
What you should do, you should accept the value of N as an input from Maine because Maine knows what
is the correct size of the eddy.
So you should pass.
And here and now and the code you will see both mean and the function that giving us the correct output,
OK?
So one more thing we can do is maybe I can say let me update area of zero equals, let's 100.
And now what I will do, I'll first call this function.
And then I will print inside mine, OK, then I will print inside me, so I've changed the order.
Now what we can see is we are updating the zero element inside this function.
And since it is biased by friends there, it is expected that the value of any or zero should change
in both.
OK.
So you can see area of zero is now changed, both inside the function and inside mine as well.
That means both of them are sharing a common memory.
Border areas are same.
They have a common memory location.
They are not different.
This also confirms the fact that it is a robust way different.
I hope you understood this concept.
Let us meet in the next lecture.