Hello, everyone, in the section, we'll talk about a very interesting algorithm that we know that
that is used for searching, and that is it's a very simple technique that is known as linear search.
So let us talk about what is linear.
So it's a searching algorithm that is used to find the index of an element in a given area.
For example, let's say you go to a restaurant and there are certain items in the menu.
Let's say you have dosa, you have noodles.
You have, let's say, rajma, OK?
And maybe you have burger.
So let's say you went to the restaurant for the first time and there is a large menu and you're looking
for an item to cook.
So what do you do?
You start out reading through all of the menu items and you start looking at various co-presidents,
so you see, OK, this is where the caucus president didn't say this particular list.
What you did, you went through every item and you scanned it.
OK.
Doesn't match my requirements.
If yes, I stop at that particular point.
This way of searching in an area is known as linear search, and it's a brute force technique.
You can say we are trying out all possibilities where a particular element is present.
So let us look at in the context of voting digitally.
For example, we are given the city which contains some number of elements, and we want to search for
a particular Gladys Knight.
So what we will do is go to this index and will check, does it March nine?
No, it doesn't.
We go to the next, does it March nine?
We go to the next.
Next, next.
And finally, we come at this place.
Does this Adelphi my matches over key nine or not?
Yes, it does.
Match, then what we do, we stop over search.
We don't want to go any further and say, OK, stop and return their index of this particular element.
And if this is not present, we can return some value, let's say minus one if a limit is not found.
OK.
What we will do.
We will now write a function to do linear search.
And let's see how we can do it so I can see in linear search.
We have Eddie, and we have it and OK, that denotes the size of Betty.
And one more thing we will get is the key, the value for which we are looking inside this particular
ready.
So what we will do, it will read from an equal to zero I less than an A-plus plus.
And here we can check it, Jake.
If current element matches with key to the current element, as at Alpha, if this matches with the
key element, then we can simply return.
I will give you found out the element that you are looking for, and that's it.
And once if you come out of the loop or get out of the loop, that means you have already reached.
You've already scanned the elements.
And this written statement was not executed so that in that case, we can return minus one.
But this element does actually not present inside this edit.
Now what we can do, we can create an array of, let's say, some numbers.
It's a 10, 15, 12, nine six four three.
And and it and.
And this letter size of Eddie, a bond size of eight.
And you can say the key is something that is given by the user, I don't know.
So see in key, I take in put that particular key and I check the index by calling this method linear
search.
And and key, I check if this index is not equal to minus one.
I bring your element as present.
He is present at index.
And here we bring the index that is index.
Otherwise we going to see out this particular key is not found.
That's it, let's build a good.
And let us try to run it.
So this is a dodge slash, you know, three linear search.
And I need to give up your religion nine to nine is present at index three.
This is what we get two, zero, one, two and three.
Yes, nine is president at Index three, where if I give it to the number 19, if it is 19, is not
found.
Let us also talk about how much time Discord will take in the worst case.
OK, so what we are doing in this court is in the worst case, we are iterating over the entirety the
number of operations.
The number of instructions that we are going to execute is going to be proportional to the value of
in give.
The larger is the value of in LA.
This is the time taken, OK?
And it is going to be a linear function of n so begins in this linear search has a complexity of order
often.
OK.
This is going to take all that off.
And so that's all for this linear search algorithm.
I hope you really understood this one.
And in the next lecture, we will learn about binary search.