Everyone in this section, we are going to talk about object oriented programming, which is a very
important concept in programming, and we will not talk about any specific algorithms in this case.
It's not about algorithms, it's it's about style of writing.
OK, so right now, what we have seen, we have seen a functional style of writing code where for every
logic we create a function.
But in object oriented programming, the functions are tied around objects and we deal with these objects
and the concept of classes.
Let me tell you what is an object to object basically denotes an entity from a real world, OK?
For example, let me give you one example let's say I'm using this digital pen.
And now this digital pen has a software application in which I have different things or can.
Maybe I have a digital pen object inside my software out, and this pen object has different attributes.
For example, one attribute is color.
OK, I want to use a little green color for writing.
Maybe later on, I want to switch on the grid.
OK, maybe I also have a property.
Let's add thickness.
What is the thickness of this pen so I can adjust this property?
I contained this property to my pixel.
OK, maybe I also have a function to set the color, or can I pass in some color?
Maybe let's read.
And that will change the color of this pen to read.
Now what you can see is this pen object has certain properties.
Or it has some attributes.
OK.
And it also has some methods.
Yeah, so these are some methods that this Ben has.
And what you would have done is you would easily have defined different variables like string coloured
string and thickness.
OK.
And some function.
That color or something like that.
So instead of.
Making these different 30.
This is a variable.
Instead of making like different variables and they're stored what we are going to do, we are going
to wrap it inside a single.
We are going to wrap it inside a single class, which is known as spin.
OK, so all these attributes and methods are tied with the entity that is open to Ben is a real world
entity that we're depicting and saw fit.
OK, so maybe let me give you another example.
Let's say you are making an online shopping system and you want to implement the functionality for a
shopping cart.
OK.
This shopping cart would also have certain attributes.
Maybe it would have a list of items that you want to buy.
OK?
List of items that you want to buy it may have.
The method to get the total sum, OK, this would be a method that will I trade on the list of items
that we would have and it will find out the total and maybe there is a method that is known as applied
discount.
OK.
So you can see all these methods and attributes are connected with one, an entity that is shopping
cart.
OK, so it doesn't make sense to make them as independent functions.
We want to implement these functions as a part of a shopping cart because what we will do will define.
The structure of the shopping cart, OK, how does the shopping cart look like, what it will contain
and what are the methods that will operate on this particular data?
OK.
So later on in this course, we will build a small shopping cart backend using object oriented programming
principles.
But first, we will understand the basic concept of object oriented programming.
So now I hope you understand the term entities in real world.
OK, so I've given you two examples.
OK.
What we have learned is all the objects that we would make in the code.
They will have two things.
One is a state the state will store what data is present in that particular object and behavior.
So these functions operate on this data, for example, in the case of a pen.
The data is color of the pen and the thickness of the pen.
OK.
And the function is maybe you want to change the color, or maybe you want to change the thickness,
OK?
Or maybe you want to show the thickness.
Maybe there will be a function that color.
I want to see what color is currently selected in the pen object.
OK?
So this could be another so I have this software application, you can see it has a lot of colors available.
Maybe I want to use this color by clicking this pink.
The color of the pen will change to pink internally.
What happened is it called the red color method of this pen object, and that changed the color property
of the pen.
But I'm going to pink.
OK, this is what actually happened.
We want to write such code for software applications.
So now let us take another example of, let's say, a card object.
So maybe you want to build a system for a software or a card shop or a card showroom?
And then that would have, let's say, details about the card.
OK, maybe you want to define a card class and that would have a name of the God color of the card,
a model of the card, maybe a year of manufacturing.
And so on.
OK.
A lot of details can be that and maybe there could be a function that could tell me whether this card
is in stock or not, OK, or maybe what is the price of the car or maybe checkout?
Maybe someone wants to buy this car, then maybe that is a checkout method.
So God is a product, OK?
So why do we need object?
We need objects so that.
We can write code that is related inside a single class, OK?
And this will make the work of a programmer easy, maintainable.
And we can.
And it also provides that a lot of.
And one very important feature of these object oriented programming is encapsulation, so encapsulation
ensures that the data, the functions which operate on this data, they are in the same class.
And this ensures modularity of the code.
OK.
And.
And and we are not.
And it also ensures that we are not able to interface with some other data that belong to some other
class, OK, so it also provides protection against unauthorized access.
Maybe this function is not written for this class.
Maybe this is for Ben class and this function is for, let's say, some other product class.
OK.
This function cannot modify the date of this class.
These functions, this function will modify the date of this class.
Okay, so we can ensure that then capitulation is dead and.
And this feature is also known as a data hiding or cave, yet hiding specific data, which is not relevant
for that function.
OK, so apart from it, there are other features of object oriented programming as well, such as inheritance
polymorphism, which we are not going to talk right now.
OK.
So, but you can read about these features on your own as well, OK, so let's dive in to object oriented
programming from the next lecture in more depth.