I would want to know we're going to talk about what exactly is a class and what is the meaning of object.
So basically classes like a blueprint, OK, so a class does not take any memory.
It's just a map that tells compiler to give, and you will construct some object by filling data in
this class.
That object is going to take memory classes used to define the blueprint for creating the object.
So this is what, for example, when you make a map for at home, the actual map does not take up the
space on the line.
But when you construct your home after taking inspiration from that map.
So that is the thing that actually takes space.
OK, so the actual home is will be an object, and the map of that would be a class.
OK.
So this is what is going to happen in our case.
So let's see, how do we write the code for a class?
OK, so object, as I discussed, it is an instance of the class and it actually occupies some memory
and we need to define classes to make object in the memory, OK?
For example, I want to make object for, let's say, multiple cards.
OK, I want to store information about records in the memory.
Then let's say I'm creating an array of cards.
Let's add this is God zero.
This is God one.
This is card to each of these object is going to have the same attributes.
It is going to have a name.
It is going to have a color.
Again, it is going to have a name.
It is going to have a color and moral maybe name, color more.
Look, all of them are created from the same map.
So we would have define a glass god.
And we could have defined this as a name property.
It has a property.
It has a model property and it has some functions as well.
OK, so.
This code does not occupy a space, but when you create objects on this code, for example, I say,
OK, I want to create a God, a certain name, certain color and fit certain model.
Then this object is going to take place in the memory.
So that's what I'm talking about.
OK, now let's see actually how the court would look like data members to the information about the
court.
So it say we have a God on this God has some certain price.
Certain morality and name of the God is a strength so that you can use that adultery or you can use
a string as well.
Well, maybe you can write string name.
So I've written it ahead because later on, I want to teach a concept that is for which this name should
be in it, OK?
But you can take a drink as well, thing is working perfectly fine.
So, OK, this is how you define.
So we have a glass covered, followed by name of the glass, followed by the attributes.
And here you close your curly brackets, followed by a semicolon.
OK?
Now, not just a tribute, as we discussed, we can also have methods inside the glass, OK, so maybe
these are the methods that we have defined and there is also a concept of excess modifiers, OK?
These data members, these are private by default.
That means that this they're not visible outside the glass or and they're not visible outside the glass
and public means they're also visible outside the glass.
So in a glass.
You can have a few things which are private and you are going to have few things with you which you
want to expose to other classes and objects.
So that data is known as public data.
OK.
You want to give certain methods using which you can work on this data.
So you are exposing these methods on all the private data members and functions, they added, and so
private insurers data hiding in public basically exposes data.
Maybe what I want us to some other Glaeser object, I want to show the price of the car.
OK, I want to display the detail of the car, but I don't want to make this public so that anyone outside
this car can modify the price of the car.
I don't want one any other cars to modify the price of the car and movies I did two minus one.
Something like that.
OK, I want that logic that we are part of the car class.
OK, someone else should not modify the price of the morality of the car, because that's why we need
to protect this data from getting overridden.
But maybe someone does.
I want to only read the price of the car.
OK, then what we will do will create something like go and get price.
It is a method.
And this method is going to return the price, so it will ensure that the price variable is used only
in read only mode.
We are not going to give the right access for the price variable or the for the price property of the
car.
OK.
So this is a concept of excess modifiers and these methods are not public and these are data members
are private.
A class will have certain data members.
It will have certain member functions as well.
OK.
And now let us write some gold starting from the next liquid.
And I hope you'll gordon basic understanding of classes and objects.