Everyone in this lecture, we're going to define a product class that will represent the product for
a shopping website.
Let us write a class product.
And what we're going to do.
We are going to say, let's assume that the product has four dead members or four properties, maybe
each product has a unique I.D., each product has a unique name that is, let's have two hundred characters
long.
Each product has a MRP, and maybe it also has a selling price.
OK, so let's say these are the four things.
And.
So what we're going to do.
We are going to say, OK in the mean, let us define let us actually create a real product in the moment
because we are going to product Gamera product is a glass.
It does not take any memory unless you create the object out of it.
So this camera is an object that you have created.
OK.
This camera is an object that you have created.
So this camera is going to occupy some memory.
So if I simply show it to you, see out size off camera, then you will see that it is going to take
up some space.
OK?
So you can see it is taking Android 12 bytes, 200 bytes for NIM.
OK.
And for bytes.
For this one, for byte, for this one and four bytes for this one total to one hundred and twelve bytes.
So we have this product class now.
This product object is containing folded.
OK, so you can treat it like a bucket.
It's like a variable in which now we have four subfields I.D. name.
MRP.
And selling price.
OK, so if this is no product and the name of this product is not yet defined, but we say, OK, this
variable that we are using in all this product is known as Gamera.
If you want to get the MRP of the camera or the selling price of the camera, you can simply to see
out.
MRP camera dot and might be so using the DOT operator, we can access what is the MRP of this camera?
For now, there is one problem that by default, as I said, all these data members, they are going
to be private.
You cannot access them directly outside this class.
What you need to do, you need to make them public.
So maybe I'm going to make the MRP as public.
And the selling price as public, so anyone can read and write this and might be OK.
So now what I can do is I can run this code again.
And I'm getting zero, so maybe by default, we have not initialized either it is zero.
It may be garbage as well, I don't know.
OK.
What I need to do, I need to first set the price of this camera so I can the camera dart and let it
equals 200 and camera dart later selling price equals to 200.
OK, now, although it is not practical, OK, so am I be currently selling price should always be less
than equal to MRP.
But here we don't have any tricks here.
We don't have any tricks that we are doing.
So we are simply saying, OK, Brent, the MRP of the camera.
And we are saying, okay, let us print the selling price of the camera as well.
OK, so selling price of the camera as well.
Now, if I run this code and.
You can see MRP is on and selling prices also.
So this should be a selling price.
What we are able to do, we are able to read and write the data members of this object, OK, so we
are able to modify these two properties because they are public.
OK.
Now, making everything public is not recommended because.
What can happen is anyone can change, and this could lead to wrong data, OK?
This could cause inconsistencies in data.
OK, because we want this tech to be enforced.
We want to enforce this check.
OK, we want to enforce this check.
Know what we should do, what we don't want the 100 percent right access where we want to give a conditional
access.
We want to put some condition when the selling price of the product is updated.
So what we will do will learn about the concept of getting settled very soon.
And before that, we will learn about one more concept that is a concept concept of a contract treadmill.
So let us discuss this concept from the next lecture on in this lecture, what I wanted to tell you,
how to use the excess modifiers.
So we have learned by default the data members are private and you can make some of the data members
public.
We have created class, we have created object and we try to update the data members by accessing them
using a dart operator.
OK, so this is what we have learned.
Let us learn about more concepts in the next lecture.