So now we have learned how to use private and public access modifiers.
And but now we're going to learn a concept in which we are going to fix this problem.
That selling price should not be less than what we are going to do.
We are going to restrict the access of these data members.
Firstly, we are going to make them as private and we are going to provide some public methods that
will modify the MRP and the selling price.
Okay, so maybe there is a method void that might be OK.
And it is a method wide that selling price.
Now, let's say we get some price and we say, OK, this MRP should be equal to price.
And here we get some selling price and we say, OK, maybe again we may be passing somebody the price
and we say, OK, the link price should be called the price.
Now what is going to happen?
We are going to remove this code.
And instead of calling this method.
We will call instead of directly accessing the property, we will call the method September BNZ selling
price.
So I can see camaraderie that it might be, let's drag on camera, Dodd said selling price later to
wounded.
It is not going to fix the issue and it is again going to cause one problem that.
You can see this is again, a private number, and we cannot noted the values of price, and that might
be so what we need, right?
I know the function that we have great known as sectors that is taking some property off the camera.
But we are going to also create ghettos.
Are going to return some property of the product and get MRP that is going to return the MRP and get
selling price that is going to there, done the selling price.
OK, now.
OK.
Oh.
Yeah.
So again, here we will see Cameron not get out, so we are now going to call the method instead of
accessing the property and get selling price.
And you can see other problem will now be solved.
OK, this should be camera, don't go telling place.
All right.
So if I underscored now so we can see again, we have a mighty period, but we have selling prices 200
but should not happen.
What it means is now we are able to replicate the same functionality that we have done earlier using
the concepts of greater intelligence.
But these are more powerful by because.
Here we have a matter in which we can pull back and be strategic, so we can say when we are sending
a selling price, we can put additional checks here that.
If Price is greater than what might be, then we can say we will set the selling price equal to MRP.
OK, otherwise we can set the selling price equal the price.
That means if you put a price that is lower than or equal to MRP, then you will, then this price will
get updated, otherwise it will not get updated.
So that's what we are doing it.
OK?
So let let me let me show it to you if I said selling price equal to 200.
And if I underscored again so you can see both MRP and selling price are now 100.
OK.
And if I say no, the selling price should be 90.
And I what we should Bernard, then this will get updated.
So selling prices 19 MRP under OK.
And if I say it should be 190, then it would be made as it.
OK, so you're going to so we can see the concept of greater than traders are quite powerful when we
are going to work with glasses and object.
So that's all for this lecture and I hope you understood.
Now we have used both data members and we have provided methods to the public in order to work with
these drivers, and we can put additional stakes and constraints when the values of these data members
are set.
OK.
So that's all for this lecture, and maybe you can also check that the price should be greater than
zero.
So if is negative, then this price will not update.
OK.
Only then you should update the price.
Maybe if someone says, OK, let me said the ad might be as miners are injured, then this is not going
to work.
All right, so that's all for this lecture, thank you.