Everyone in this lecture, we're going to talk about new default methods which are presented by default
in every class.
OK, so these methods are known as one of these methods is constructed that we will talk about and that
is a copy constructor that is a copy assignment operator.
And also there is a distraction as well.
We are going to talk about all of them one by one.
And for this video, we will focus on constructing only, OK.
So we'll talk about what is this method constructed?
Why it is helpful and how we can use it or modify it to basically control through the special method
whose name is same as the class name.
This method is responsible for constructing the object.
OK, so right now we have not called constructor.
We have not seen how the contractor is called, but it is called in the code that we have written,
OK, so the role of the contractor is in constructing the object.
And it is called automatically when the object is created, OK, so let let me show you OK.
The memory allocation also happens when this contractor scored and contractor is called only once or
each object.
Each object.
So like these are these methods set selling price.
They can be called multiple times, but contractor is a special method whose name is same as the class
name.
By default, this constructor exists.
OK, so this piece of code was there, but it was it.
OK, so this this is how the constructor looks like.
Let me let me show you unstrap.
Let me show you code inside constructor.
We have not called this method, but it is called automatically add line number 47.
OK, so now we have written some reinstatement inside this.
So what we will see will see that.
You can see inside contractors getting printed because this method is getting called automatically,
OK?
Now, since this method is getting called automatically, we can use it to do some work as well.
OK, so maybe let us make another contractor.
This contractor is going to accept parameters in.
Oh, God, my name.
OK.
And maybe I might be on and selling price.
What are we going to begin to leak worldwide so we can initialize the object using this contract?
But we're now there is one problem.
Here it is not clear which it is, which one because of what we have.
Each plus as a hidden has a special property which is known as this.
I want to read for this particular lady, so I will write this I.D. It would be equal to it.
Basically, this I.D. goes it and this I.D. comes in.
What is this?
This is a special pointer which points to the current object.
Okay, so this basically points to the current object.
So what we will do if the attributes are seen, for example, let's to this is.
This is and then.
Then we don't need this for this property, because we can say it.
Naomi Goldwyn but this would be wrong.
We actually don't want to copy the address.
We actually want to copy the edit.
We will use a method print copy.
But Iman Poppy, all the added into the name.
And Wiggins said this NORAD equal to 80 and this arrow might be equal to it might be this arrow selling
price equal to selling price.
So you may also ask me about this ad operator what this operator is.
So this is a pointer.
And this is an object.
This points to this object and it has some property.
There is some property.
If you want to refer this property, there are two ways.
One ways you first get the object using this pointer, using their data friend, operator and then you
write x rays using the arrow notation to this arrow, which basically means you are talking about this
x property of this object.
OK.
We are doing this.
Around my typical time in this area, selling price equal to selling price.
Now what we can do, we have done something which is known as an struttura overloading that means.
We have defined.
New contractors do method, which have the same name.
And that's why this concept is known as overloading, but only one of them will get caught, OK?
Now if you see if I run this cold and if I do product camera, then the first contractor is going to
get called OK, and you're going to be inside this particular contractor.
But if I initialize this camera like this and I pass in some I.D., let's say one 01 is 90.
And then maybe the name is, let's say, Sunni or little GoPro, you know, eight, eight or nine.
And maybe then I can say MRP is 28000 and maybe selling prices 26000.
OK.
So OK.
And maybe now we can just comento this code.
This is not required.
And we can simply do the MRP and the selling price, OK?
And.
OK, let's see.
Let's build a good.
So.
We have a warning this warning can be ignored.
So again, the MRP is set to 28000 and selling prices to 26000.
So this is happening because of the parameterized contracts that we have.
OK.
This is the constructor with barometers.
And this is where the contractor comes very useful.
So we will use this parameter is contracted to do the initialization of the object that we want to get.
So I hope you understood the concept of defining the construct that and it is getting called automatically
when the object is created.
And for each object, it can be called only once.
So I hope these concepts are clear, and that's all for this lecture.