I certainly know we have talked about object initialization using constructors, and we have seen how
to construct.
I'm a trace contractor.
And you also talked about the concept of contractor overloading.
That means overloading basically means multiple functions with the same name.
So when we are defining multiple contractors, that is also a kind of a function.
Overloading and dysfunctional overloading is known as constructor overloading.
So in this lecture, we'll talk about one more type of constructor, which is known as copy constructor.
And what does this contract going to do?
It is going to create a copy of a given object, OK?
So that means we can initialize one more object by sending the current object and this object can be
created.
OK.
So let me let me show you in the form of code.
So if I have, let's say, a camera and I want to create one more product, which is again a camera,
and maybe I want to initialize it using using my first camera.
And maybe let me just call it as second camera, OK?
Or maybe.
Maybe a webcam.
OK.
And I want to initialize it using my camera object to what I can do, I can still get it.
Can this object and construct a webcam?
So if I say, OK, camera dart.
OK, so maybe what we can do, we can make one more function, it will show the details of that camera
because whatever functions your details that is going to display all the details of the cameras, we
are going, I'm going to call this method.
So show details, but camera and maybe webcam, not show details.
And I'm going to show the details of this one as well.
Now, if I run this code, you can see.
OK.
Let let us that underscored again, though this is a warning, it can be ignored.
Now you can see we're getting the output two times.
So this is for camera one.
And the second one is for camera two.
And what we can see is all the properties off camera one are copied in camera two.
OK, so it has a ID one zero one.
It also as HD one zero one.
It has a name GoPro.
It also has a name.
GoPro.
OK.
And it has a similar price as well.
Now what we're going to do.
We are going to see how this copy was managed, OK?
This copy is made.
Using a special contractor, which is designed by default.
And this is known as copy contractor.
OK.
If I write the code for the copy constructed, it will look something like this.
So we are going to have a product and we are going to pass in the object, so that object will be of
their type product.
And maybe I can say that is some product X for which I'm going to make a copy now building this court
is going to throw an edit that it says will be contractor must boss its first argument by defense.
So we need to understand why it is saying that this argument must be passed by reference.
OK?
So when you do something like this and let's say X equal to 10 and you do and Y equal to X, what are
you doing?
You're actually making a copy of X in Y.
Well, guess what?
Similarly, when we are going to pass in an object, it will function.
Maybe you have a function that takes some in these attacks and we win the mean.
You have some in y equal to 10.
And you call this function with the value of doing this by saying you are making X as a copy of Y.
OK, so you are actually creating a copy that is initialized with the value y.
This copy is created only if you copy constructor exists.
So what we are doing, we are actually making a copy construct.
But OK, and we are saying this copy constructor is asking for a copy which should be created by a copy
constructor.
So that means that copy cannot be created.
OK, so that means instead of passing this x y value was by value means box.
By making a copy, we actually have to pass it by a reference.
So if I just add this idea, that means we are not making a copy.
This X is going to be about camera one object and we are not making a copy out of it.
Then this function is going to work.
So if I build the code now and if I know, I run it.
Let me show you.
OK, now if you carefully look at the second one.
Second one, what you can see.
You can see the name is null.
OK, so this is Camera2 and this.
Camera one.
Let us see this one.
What we are printing, so this is not it, actually.
What we are doing.
Let us run this court again.
So, yes, this is ghamro one.
And this is camaraderie.
Now what is happening earlier, the default copy contractor was doing some work, but now we have overwritten
the copy contract that we sort of give you will define our own copy constructor and the body of that
copy contract that is going to be empty.
It is empty.
That means normal user logos or name is null.
It is garbage selling prices garbage and might be garbage.
So this is not nothing but a garbage value.
OK, so that means we actually have to write the logic to do the copy, OK, if we don't do it.
Then, though, by default, copping injector does it, but since we have it under the default copy
contract it now, it is expecting that we will provide the code to create the copy here.
OK, so we have to write the code to create the copy.
So what we can do, we can simply say let us copy the ID of X in the current dynamic.
So again, the ID equals to extort I.D. I aikins in name equals to extort name.
I can say I might have equals to extort.
I might be against the selling price equals to extort selling price.
OK, so now if I build this code?
Alright, alright, so there is one problem with the Eddy this determined, but is it Eddy and I will
tell you how we should handle it.
I will tell you how we should handle it.
But let us skip the name variable as of now and let me run the good.
Let me run the call.
And you can see that all the properties of the forest eddy are now copied in all the properties of the
secondary.
OK, so all of them are copied as it is.
OK, so we have not copied the name as of now, there is a concept behind it.
I will teach you something in the next lecture, but I hope you are understanding.
The concept of a copy conjecture, I guess this is one way of making the call, and that is another
way.
I will tell you.
So this is one way in which you can call the cops you contracted, OK?
And maybe there is a product, Andy Gum, which is equal to camera.
So in this case, also what is going to happen?
We are going to call the cops contractor.
OK, so this also makes a call to the copy contractor and I can say and can start.
Shortages.
So you can see we are getting.
OK, let me just see.
This should be handled.
The camera recorded its webcam to our children, Handycam cameras showed it is alright.
Yes.
So the bird was old.
So now if I see I'm getting camera one, I'm getting camera too, and I'm getting camera three, OK?
And suppose if I just do it without defining my own copy, but I will also get the name.
I will also get the name.
So let us do it without defining the copy and chapter.
Now you can see all of them have the same name.
They have the same details and yes, so that means both the copy contractor working fine.
But now the question is if the default copy contractor is working, why do we need to define the copy
contractor?
So we try to answer this right in the next lecture.
And there is a concept of shallow copy and deep copy behind it.