Everyone in this lecture, we're going to talk a little bit more about the corpulent in the last act
of you saw this index gives us an edit.
We will avoid it because we cannot copy the name of the ADI or we cannot
assign something to the anymore.
Because as at any time is a read-only, content to name here points to a memory.
So we have a name and we have an editor whose name is exactly what we actually want to do is we want
to copy the contents of this edit to the city.
What we will do later this is the ABC.
Then we will put ABC here, OK?
So we'll see.
Let us point.
Let us copy.
Using string copy and we will copy ex-Tottenham, that is the destination.
And this is the source, ex-Tottenham is the source.
If I do this and then my God, it is going to work perfectly fine.
And if I show you the output now, we can see that even the name value is getting copied in the three
object that we have created.
And maybe you may say, OK, handy, Cam Dart, that that might be equal to, let's say, 1000, then
this might be will also get upgraded.
So if I did this, so you can see this has a different MRP.
Now let's talk a little bit more about.
What?
Yeah.
So now we want to actually talk about the concept that is shallow copy and copy to copy contractors
working to create a copy of a given object.
And but we need to define our copy constructor.
If an object has pointers to dynamically allocated object.
So this is a concept that I am going to discuss now.
What is going to happen?
Let me create a copy of this file and we will write a different code now.
What we're going to do, we are going to instead of keeping us there together, we're actually going
to keep a pointed.
The word enemy.
OK, so this Eddie will lie in a heap memory.
So what I'm going to do instead of writing this name, I'm going to say, let us say this is something.
So instead of saying this name begins, it is God's done name.
And here we are getting appointed and we can say, OK, if you're getting a binder doing it at first
we will allocate the city so I can.
The name equals two new God.
And how much space we will need.
That will be a straight line off and +1.
And then we are going to copy everything inside the name.
OK, so first we are allocating the memory depending upon how big the name is.
A little everything goes off land 50 now.
If it is, if the name is, let's say, handycam or if it is GoPro.
So we are going to.
I look at a space of lint sticks by for this one, one for another character.
So it's a dynamic area, so name is going to point to a dynamic that is going to store GoPro.
And this lies on the hip, and this is one change that we need to make inside the contractor.
And here also maybe what is going to happen?
Let us just come under the carpet and but as of now?
Because we want to learn about the concept.
OK, so if I now say I want to change this version to go through it, so I have another camera, let
me just.
Segment this out as well.
So I want to say I have a product that is this camera one.
I have a camera.
Also, there is an old camera, which is the same model of camera one.
And now I'm going to say, let me update a particular name of the let me try to update the name of the
old camera, maybe I want to make a GoPro eight.
So what I will do?
Let me try to expose a particular variable.
Maybe I can give a function.
Lloyd said name of the camera, and here I give God starred.
Name.
And I simply do I do still keep.
I say name this arrow name and name, so I have created actually settled for the name.
OK, so this is a setter for the name.
Now what is going to happen if I say, let's say old camera Dart said name and I say, OK, go GoPro
eight.
It's a this is the name for the camera.
That I know.
Oh, yeah.
Let's say this is a name for the camera.
OK.
So let me let me see if we can do something here again to Old Camera Dot.
Sure, it is.
And again, the camera dog showed it.
So you can see we have used copy contracted to create the old camera and better contractor for the first
one.
This is a warning that we can ignore.
And if I don't, the colonel.
To know what you can see is the names of both the cameras have been changed.
Ideally, this should not happen.
OK, now what is actually happening at gold level is if this is GoPro it, this is GoPro eight.
So if you're thinking that I have done something wrong?
Let us also update the price of the old camera that said that one was cheap, maybe third selling price.
And maybe it is just one thousand.
Let's see.
On the.
Let's build a good.
And if I show you, you're going to.
The price of the old camera has been updated as 1000, whereas the price of the new camera is still
26000 and the name of the old camera is GoPro eight.
And this should have been GoPro nine.
GoPro Hero nine.
OK, so this was the.
Now what actually happened, what happened behind the scenes?
This is very important to understand.
So let us see what is actually happening behind this entire story.
So what they did, it called the default copy contractor, so we hired a camera.
Object in the memory.
This was camera and we created an old camera object.
Using the camera object.
So this is no old camera.
OK.
Old camera.
So this was GoPro.
Nine.
And this was GoPro.
How is this named stolen because of this name is actually a pointer that points to some memory.
Let's add this addresses 100.
And here we are storing the string GoPro eight, a GoPro nine.
And this one is actually stored here, OK?
And similarly, we have a price variable later 228 K and something something, and here also we have
a name, we have a price.
And then this object was created, everything was copied as it is, including the name some name property
had a value hundred, so that was copied it rice was 28 K, not 28 gave us copied it.
Then we called the method, said name for this one and we said, OK, let us change the name of this
to go pro it so ordered happened.
It was pointing to the same memory because the actual error was not copied, but instead.
What happened instead, it actually copied the address.
OK, so it actually copied the value that was there in the printer.
So this happened because the copy was not copied was a shallow copy.
This is known as a yellow copy.
When we're not pointing the copying, the actual memory, you are describing the address.
But then I did OK, let us update the prize to one key and let us agree to the name to go through it.
Then it actually changed the name of this camera to go through it.
And that change would reflect it as well and here as well.
OK, so that is why you can see the price would remain the same, but the memory that was lying outside
somewhere in the heap that was shared by the two objects.
And this is causing problems, OK?
So how we can handle this?
The answer to this is we will actually create a deep copy and in order to create a deep copy what we
need, we need our own copy constructor to do the work.
OK.
So what this contractor was doing, it was actually doing something like this.
It was doing.
Called starting.
This work is done by this.
OK, so this call, you can see it is building fine and this work is done by the shallow copy, so this
is how exactly the shell logo is created.
It just blindly copies all the values without looking at what memory should be copied and what should
not be.
So if I run this code, you will see the same output.
The name is changing, but the price is not changing because price is in a different bucket, but the
name is in the common bucket.
So how do we handle this?
How do we handle this?
The idea here is you first.
Behind this name, though, some new memory, so you should create a new memory, so a new guide of
Esther Elion of ex-Tottenham Plus one.
So you first create a new idea that means instead of using this arrow, we can name while copying will
first create a new edit who was lent the same as this one.
OK, then in this new idea, maybe this addresses 824, so this addresses 824.
In this address, we will copy what is there in the original letter, so we will say, OK, let us copy
as DCP, right?
Let us go up in name.
Whatever is the next name.
Let's do the copy, OK?
And now if I run the code.
You will see.
That the new name is appropriate for the old camera and the original one still remains.
GoPro Hero nine this is a concept of deep copy.
OK, so we we are now having to address this is GoPro eight, and this one was originally GoPro Hero
nine.
So it remains as it is.
OK.
This is what we have done in case of up using a deep copy contract.
So I hope this concept is clear and this is what I wanted to teach you.
So we need to define our own copy contract that if the object has pointers to dynamically allocate object,
and that means a deep copy of the object is needed.
So I hope you really understood this concept well now.
And that's all for this lecture.
So thank you and I will see you in the next video.