So in this lecture, we're going to talk about one more operator that is known as copy assignment operator.
So we have learned about copy contractor and.
We learn that sometimes we may need to create a deep copy as well, so similar to copy, but we have
a copy assignment operator which can be used to initialize one object from another.
Maybe you have some object.
And later on, somewhere in the code you wanted to object, one should be called to object to.
OK.
In this case, the object is already constructed.
OK, so the contractor was already called.
You can only call contractor one time, and that can be either the default contractor or the parameterized
contractor or the copy contractor.
So now you want to make a copy, so here you will not cop killer copy contractor.
Here you will call a special method, which is known as copy assignment operator, and this operator
will tell how object one should be initialized from object, what all values should be copied and let
us try to see this.
This method already exists.
So if I say I want to say, let's say I've created an old camera here, if you look carefully.
So if I just don't do the initialization at this point, so the contract has already been called OK,
and maybe I want to say something like let me just the man told this court.
I want to say after some time that old camera should be equal to camera.
So at this point, a copy assignment operator function will be called.
So we need to see what does this copy assignment operator?
And let us dive into that as well.
So.
So we have we are calling the function Gamera authorities, and we are calling the function old camera
on our shoulders here.
This copy assignment operator is going to get called on with one more thing I'm going to do, but let
me just show you the output first.
So.
Let us build a cold and now let me show you the output.
So you can see it is inside the default constructor that we have printed and then this is object one.
And this is object two.
And they both are the same.
So let us try to change one of them.
So again, the old camera not set name and I do GoPro eight, OK, and it's the old something like this.
And if I build a gold now on liquid on it, you can see the name is changed for both the cameras.
This is happening way not because of propaganda, but because of sloppy assignment operator, which
also creates a shallow copy.
Okay, so that means we need to define our own copy assignment operator.
So.
The way to define it is like this we have void uprated equal to.
And here we give the product, and maybe here we're going to see out inside Bobby assignment.
Well, the good.
And let me show you.
Oh, okay.
Yes.
So this is giving us a segmentation fault because we are doing certain him on this, it is right now
not created this that is not created because of.
Yes.
This is not going to work because that is not yet created.
So what we will, I'll just go up, it is called and I will be started.
This is going to override the default.
Well, assignment operator and this court is going to create a deep copy.
So let me show you.
Now, if I see the name, here it is GoPro Hero nine under his GoPro, it all.
Now this is working because.
What would it be actually write the logic for creating a deep copy?
Inside lobby assignment operator, OK.
This is the same day that you have to remember, this is a return type of the metal.
It doesn't return anything.
Operator is a key word, and equal basically tells us that we are overloading the assignment operator
for the product object, and we will get a product for which we are copying into into our current product.
OK?
When you're making this phone call here.
So this is basically you're doing old camera and there is a method which is for equality.
So this method is nothing but equal.
And this camera object is actually parsed as a parameter.
OK, so this is what is happening when you're doing this thing.
We are actually making a call to the copy assignment operator that we have just written.
So I hope the concept of copies and rent operator is clear.
And sometimes we may need to create a deep copy on for the idea of to write the code for the obvious
and rent operator and copy the device.
Both of them will create a yellow copy because this is all we are creating a deep copy by initializing
or numeric and all the values are same.
The array addresses different and the memory is different.
OK?
So that's the whole point of making a copy.
All right, so that's all for.