Everyone, till now, we have learned about three functions contractor, copy and copy assignment operator
and the fourth one that is also present in every class.
This is known as destructor.
So you're going to talk about the structure.
So the structure is written something like this, the class name prefixed with this delectable design.
And here what we are going to do that we are going to write the code for.
Deleting the dynamically allocated memory.
So any static data that is created that is automatically destroyed, but in order to create dynamically
allocated memory, we need to write this code inside the truck that will get.
Because dieting memories freed by the non-violent and dynamic memory is the job of the user program
it will destroy, it is a function that is called automatically when the object is destroyed or for
example, we were making a product object and then the main function is finished.
And since product, as it's called domain, that object will be destroyed and their the for the product
will be called OK.
The compiler provides a default constructor on user need.
A user defined structure is needed when the class content pointers to dynamically allocated memory,
so this is something that we have to take care of.
Let me show you this example that we have written in this example.
If I talk about what are the things that are dynamically allocated, so only the name of the product
is dynamically allocated.
So that means we need to provide the code for the destructed to destroy the name when the object goes
out of scope.
So let me just write a district that they'd say, delete the product.
Maybe I can to see out or deleting.
And maybe you can say a product name, so maybe name.
Now, we have not called this function, but this function will be called automatically when the object
goes out of scope.
We're just before this function hits the ending block.
At this point, like no one going to succeed, then the main function is going to get what it is, going
to destroy all the objects that were created.
So what are the objects that were created?
There is a camera object.
It is an old camera object.
Both of them will be destroyed.
And let's see this in action.
This is going to hang up and automatically.
We are not going to destroy it is going to handle automatically.
You're going see the lighting, GoPro, it and the lighting GoPro Hero nine now when it says, OK,
I'm going to delete these objects, it is basically going to delete these buckets.
You know it.
And Hero nine.
OK, now these buckets also contained the address of a dynamically located memory.
And that memory is not going to get deleted, OK?
So this memory is not going to get deleted, so then you are deleted.
It is just going to delete this part of the memory, this part of the memory, the address of this was
how this was rendered.
Later, this was 200.
This was 200.
We we actually lost the address of this memory and this memory is lying unutilised.
OK, so this actually creates a problem which is known as memory leak.
OK.
So if you want to become a great programmer, you should not write code that causes memory leaks.
What we will do In order to handle these memory leaks, we will write the code inside the structure.
That means when this object is going to be destroyed, we will talk.
It will first destroy this memory, then we will destroy this object.
That is something that we are going to do now.
So you are doing it.
You simply need to say delete the name and make a name.
Want to know if name was not null?
OK, if name was not an alleged breath, then let's delete the name Eddie and let us make the name pointer
point to note that said.
Now you won't see any change in the output, but at the memory level, those two areas have also been
deleted.
OK?
So again, the same destructor is getting called, and those two errors also have been deleted.
So that's the concept of destructor and why do we need it?
We needed to avoid memory leaks when the memory is allocated dynamically.
So that's all for this lecture.
Thank you.