Everyone in this module, we will talk about flowcharts, the water flow times, the flowcharts Otto
diagrammatic representation illustrating a solution to a given problem we'll get.
So what is the problem so it can be any problem?
OK, for example, making a cup of coffee?
It can be a problem.
And you want to depict what are the steps needed to make a cup of coffee, OK?
So all the steps in a given order they can be represented.
Using a flowchart to a flowchart allows you to break down any process into smaller steps and display
them in a visually appealing way again.
So it it becomes very easy for the beginners to draw and understand a flowchart again without writing
complex code.
You can easily understand what steps you will perform in order to solve a problem.
That is what a flowchart is.
We have several components that are used inside logic, so you can call these components as building
blocks of the flowchart to get the first building block or the component is a Starbucks.
It denotes the starting step again.
That means the solution starts from this particular box, and it can also be used to terminate the process.
For example, if you want to end the process, then you can draw a box like this.
It's a oval shaped box, and you will draw this box to denote the start or the end of the process.
One thing that you would be doing very frequently is reading it.
For example, if you want to make coffee, you will read the input for how many guests you want to read
to make the coffee.
OK, so you will read the value of in the note the number of guests will want to have coffee.
OK, so we understood this value inside a bucket.
That bucket is created inside your room.
That is random access memory.
The way to depict the read statement is by using this.
Walks in a shape of a parallelogram and misread the value of so this will create a bucket inside Iran.
And for example, there are four guests, so this bucket will store the value for it.
OK, this will store the value for the middle if you want to put in.
OK, you want to print something you're going to print the value of in this kind of a box, which is
in the form of a parallelogram.
It is used for input and output.
The what you want to print something.
Directly, suppose you want to print high.
Anything that you want to display as it is, OK?
It is written inside double goods.
So these are the real goods.
And here you are writing.
And so this will actually print the value for it or it will not print.
And because it is, it will print the value of it.
So I hope these two components will clear.
The next component is a rectangle that is used anywhere.
You have to process some data, for example, you want to see that my marks of a particular student.
They will be average of marks in maths.
Less physics by two by example.
You want to do something like this.
So this is kind of a process.
So what you are doing, your calculating this value and you're putting this value inside a bucket called
marks.
But this is known as assignment statement.
OK.
This is known as assignment.
You're saying some equal to zero, so what you're doing, your assigning the value zero to a bucket
called some some is a bucket.
And that is not during a value.
OK.
All these instructions where the processing is happening.
Anything except from input output or you're assigning certain value, they will be depicted using a
rectangle the same as a bucket that is not storing the value beetle.
OK.
So this is known as assignment to later on, we will see the difference between the liquid, which is
known as assignment and the equal of which is known as equality.
These two are different.
Operators in programming, OK, so right now we have seen what as an assignment, the next component
is a decision box.
It has denoted using this diamond shape box, also known as rhombus.
So whenever you have a certain condition to check, that means you want to check whether this condition
is true or false.
You will have this kind of a box and based upon a condition, there can be two branches.
If the condition is true, then I will go in this yes branch.
If the condition is false, I will go in this particular branch.
An example of a condition could be is whether any OK is, is the weather rainy?
If it is raining?
OK, I want to go out with the umbrella.
If it does not, let us assume it is sunny.
I will go with sunglasses, something like this.
Every time you have to do some work based on a certain condition, then you will depict the condition
inside this both shape boxed.
OK, so this box is used to denote the condition.
The next thing that you will find in a flowchart is arrows.
OK, so these arrows are used to connect to different boxes, OK?
For example, I want to connect start with read.
That means after a start, go to this box, read and after you then go to this box.
These arrows are used to connect multiple building blocks inside the flowchart.
OK.
So in the next lecture, we will see certain examples and will solve some problems and will draw flowchart
for them.
So I hope the building blocks are clear.
See you in the next video.