Everyone.
So let us discuss this problem of finding simple interest and in order to compute simple interest,
we need three things we need to know the principal amount.
The rate of interest on diamond years.
And if given to these three things, you can simply compute the simple interest OK.
So you might have done it in school level maths.
We also know the formula for simple interest is given as principal that is denoted using be multiplied,
but it multiplied by time and divided by 100 OK.
For example, if your principal is 100, the rate is five and dime is two.
And if you divide it with 100, it gives you the value, then it gives you the value and.
Now, this is what the simple interest is.
Now suppose we want to write a program or we want to write a flowchart for this problem.
Let's see what steps we have to follow.
So as we discussed, the first step would always be start, OK, the next step in this problem is to
take input because once you have the input only, then you can process your data.
That will take input and we will read three numbers.
That is the principal date and time.
OK, so doing this step will create three buckets in the memory.
OK, so one bucket will store the principal.
Another bucket will store the read.
Another bucket will store the name.
OK, and now we are saying that, OK, we are going to process simple interest.
So we are creating another bucket whose name is simple interest.
And we are evaluating the value of this expression.
So we are multiplying three numbers 1.5 and two dividing it with a constant that is under it, and we
are storing the result here that is going to store the value in here.
OK.
That means if we deposit 200 rupees at a five percent interest for a period of two years, we will get.
Ben Rubies as a simple interest.
So let's see, let's put it in the simple interest that will bring the value of this bucket that Dennis
printed.
And here we were, consuming three inputs under advisement.
OK.
They go as input.
And this simple interest is the output.
And that's it.
Now we are done with the process and hence we write them.
That is how simple it is to draw a flowchart.
So I hope this problem is clear for you in the next video.