So in this lecture, we are going to discuss this problem, given three numbers, we have to find the
largest of them, OK?
For example, we have a number 10, we have a number 30 and we have a number 22.
Obviously, we know the largest in this case is the middle man.
This is the largest number because we have to print the largest of the three numbers.
Another example would be, let's say we have 12 eight to 10.
In this case, the largest is the number 12.
So let's see how we can draw a flowchart to find the largest of these numbers.
The first step, as we're discussing every problem, would be a start.
The next step would be to read the values of these three numbers.
OK, whatever it is, the input, we are going to read it, for example, into the input as.
Then, well, I need this input would be fed to the system by using a read statement, OK, in the next
step.
That would be a comparison to what we can do.
We can check if it is greater than equal to be and is greater than equal to see if this is.
If this condition is true, that means we are checking is then greater than both.
12.
And it is also greater than equal to it.
Obviously, this condition is not true.
But if this is true to what we can do, we can simply print and exit.
That means our work gets done.
So we can say in this case, if it is like 12, then indeed we know that 12 is greater than or equal
to 10 and 12 is also greater than or equal to eight.
OK.
So in this case, we will separate eight and end or exit whatever it is.
But if it is not the case, what does it mean, OK?
So this basically means, let's say the numbers are 10, 12 and eight, so is clearly not an option.
It cannot be on it.
So what we will do, we will take for be gone.
We believe it answered.
In order to have real as ever answered what we can do, we can check that if B is greater than or equal
to A and B is greater than or equal to C, OK.
This is the case.
If we go into this direction of yours begins OK.
B is the answer identifies if it is not the greatest B is not the greatest, then B must be the greatest.
OK?
So in this case, we will say print c and exit.
OK, now you may ask why I'm using this greater than equal to sign why not only greater than is sufficient.
OK, let's see.
The numbers are equal.
For example, let's say the numbers are.
Twenty.
Twenty twenty and.
It's been OK.
If this is the case, though, if you only use the statement greater than, OK, so for 2020 and then
obviously this condition would be false when there is not greater than 20, this condition would also
be false.
B is not greater than what would happen in this case.
We will end up in the last branch of the code and we will separate the two, which which will output
bend in this case.
So which is wrong?
That is why in this flowchart, we are writing a modification that while making this check, we are
checking whether the number is greater than or equal to.
So this symbol is known as greater than or equal to.
So if 20 is greater than equal to 20, the answer would be yes.
So if the numbers are like 2020 and then so what you will do in the first check you will check is 20
greater than equal to 20 yes, and 20 is greater than or equal to 10.
Yes, we will print a and you will.
And in this case, your output would be this number 20.
I hope you have understood the flowchart to find out the largest of three numbers, and that's all for
this we do.