Everyone, so in this lecture, we're going to discuss the problem, we need to find the sum of numbers
from one doing OK, so end will be given as input to us and we need to iterate over all the numbers
from one to N and add them up.
For example, if an as forward, we will start from one, we will add two, we will add three and we
will add for this.
Some comes out to be an OK, this is what we need to do and we need to come up with apologized for the
same.
One thing to observe in this problem is that we are repeating a task.
Again and again, OK, so what we are doing, we are maintaining of some the the some is initially zero.
Then in the next step, we are adding one to it, some becomes one in the next year, adding to do it.
In the next hour, we're adding three to it in the next hour, we're writing for do it again.
So what is the word that is getting repeated?
I think the current number, that is what we are doing.
And finally, when we reach for, we stop and we print out the smartest thing we need to see how we
can implement the repeal statement using of logic.
And when will you work with programming languages?
We will see that there is a concept of a loop.
OK, so there is a follow that is a while loop, so there are different ways of implementing the repeat
instruction.
OK.
So let us see how we can repeat some work inside a flow chart.
So we'll try to draw flowchart for the team.
We will start.
OK.
And the next step would be to read the well, you often will read the value of an.
And now what we want to do that was and is for someone to look in and is for what do you want to do?
You want to have the value of some in the memory that is in the beginning, OK?
What you will do, you will create a bucket called some inside the memory.
The value of the sum would be zero.
So how do we do it?
OK, we have something called as a some.
And the value of that sum is currently zero.
And I also need to know what is the current number, so we know that we are starting from a value that
is equal to one.
Let us see.
I denotes the current number and the value of the current number is one.
So will initialize that we can say, OK, we have the current number that is equal to one.
We want to do certain work repeatedly.
So what we will I'll show you how to implement a loop.
So here we will put a decision box and we will check if the value of I.
If this is less than equal doing.
If done that is, yes, then what we will do, we will add this item or something.
OK, so what we will do, we will say OK, some equals some less I.
We have added the wealth I to the son and we will update with.
We will talk, I know, becomes a call to I +1.
And again will come back to this particular point.
So this these three boxes, they will formal, OK, we will see how, but if done, there is no that
means the value of the current number has exceeded the value of and then what we will will print the
value of some.
And then we will stop.
Now we will stop.
Now you may ask how how this is going to calculate the sum, OK, that this part is called as a loop
inside the loop.
There are other things.
So this thing is known as the stopping criteria.
It tells when to stop this loop.
This is the work that we are doing.
And this is a big statement inside the loop.
OK.
And these are the initial values that we have decided, OK, we will start from equal to one.
The sum is zero, so let's see what happens.
Initially, Summit zero is one.
Here we come.
Here we take is one less than equal to Ford.
The answer is yes.
We update our sum.
So sum becomes, well, how much?
Some blasé.
So the new value of some is no.
One, and I become like, Where do I +1?
The new value of I is now two.
OK, this is some.
This is a.
Now again, we go here, we check, is Eliza inequality doing?
The answer is yes.
Two is less than equal before the Sun becomes one +2 three, and the value of AI becomes a plus one
that is also three.
Again, we go here is three less than equal to four, and that is yes, the sum becomes six and the
value of AI becomes four.
Again, we go here is four less than equal to four.
The answer is yes, then becomes six plus four 10, and the value of AI becomes five.
And this is where your condition will break.
OK, this is weird.
Now, the value of AI is five and the value of an is four.
So what we will do will come out of this front, so we will enter this code.
This branch of code, we will print the sum the value of some bucket of been.
This value would get printed as an output and we will stop.
OK.
So this is how easy it is to implement a loop using a flowchart.
So any time you're implementing a loop, take it off three three four things the initial condition,
the stopping criteria, the work that needs to be repeated inside the loop and the update.
OK, that's all for this video.
I hope you understood how to implement a repeat instruction using a loop.
That's all.
Thank you.