Everyone in this example, we will look at how do you handle multiple inputs inside a flow chart, OK?
The question is taken would end.
So we have to first read the value of an OK and followed by inward numbers.
So for example, in this case, we had first given the value of and that is food, then we are followed
by four more numbers that we have to read.
And then we have to find that sum.
So this some is nothing but one one zero.
OK.
The end could be anything, if any, stent.
We have to read 10 words.
If an is 50, we have to read 15 words, OK?
Now you cannot create and number of buckets to read.
Such numbers, okay, so what we have to do, we have to read and process the Sun as we go through the
input, okay, so we have to read.
And update some.
Simultaneously, for example, if I give you a number 10.
So in your mind, you create a bucket called sum, OK?
And knew is initially zero, then you know the sum is nothing but 0+ and that is equal to and OK, next
time I took it, read the number 20.
So you add 22 years.
So the sum now becomes thirty years during what is the current sum?
Then I ask your grade.
The next number that is 30.
So you are 32.
The sum, it becomes 60.
Next time I ask you to read the next number, that is 50.
So you added tourism and it becomes one, 110 or so, do you think will require a use of loop?
And in this loop, we are also going to update this, OK?
Let's see how many buckets we will need.
So one bucket we will need to store.
What is the value of in that is food.
Another bucket we will need to count, which, no, we are doing OK, so the first number, the value
of I is one when we go to the second number.
The value of I is two when we go to the third number.
The value of our history.
When we go to the fourth number, the value of his food.
So I denotes which number we are eating.
OK.
So another bucket.
I denotes which bucket we're reading.
Another bucket.
We need to know the value of the current number.
Suppose I is one.
What is the first number that we are reading?
The first number is nothing but 10.
So this will go ahead.
OK.
Another bucket to ensure.
What does the sum belong to?
The sum till now is zero.
Then we read, then we add 10 to the sum.
Then we read 20.
Then we add 22.
The sum.
OK.
So I hope you're getting some idea of what all buckets we will need to create.
And now let's see how we can create the flow chart.
OK.
So first of all, we will have start.
As usual, then we will read the well, you often will say, OK, let's read.
The number and.
Then what what next?
We need to know the count.
OK.
So we need to say, OK, we're going to read the first number, the value of this one and how many numbers
we want to read.
We want to read and numbers on what is this some now, some below zero.
OK.
To tell what point we are going to read.
Let's see.
So we are going to read a little.
I is less than equal to and because we are going to read let us defend his vote, we are only going
to try and look four times.
So if I is less than equal to end, if the answer is yes, we will take it.
Read the current value.
How do we read it?
We read the current value.
We read it.
And now what are you going to do?
You can do two things.
One thing is you will update the sum, OK?
So you will update the Sun so you can see some equals, some less value.
OK, next thing, you will increment the count.
You will talk, I equals I +1.
That is another thing that you will do.
And then again, you will connect back here.
You will again going to back it.
And if the answer is no.
Then you know that, OK, I have computed the sum I can print it.
Do you will talk rent the value of some?
And then you can simply say exit.
Now, let us brighten this code for our given input.
So the input we are given and is Ford, OK?
And is Ford, and we are given some numbers, let's say 30, 50, 20 and later than that, these are
the numbers.
If what is I is one.
Is one less than equal when one is less than equal, the 40th will read the value.
What is the value that we will read?
The next input that is available from the keyboard that will go into the value to the value is 30.
The value is 30, and we update about something as simple as value, so sum becomes zero plus 30 to
some becomes 30.
All right.
I becomes what I becomes to who is less than equal to for.
We will redouble you to the next number from the keyboard and productively that will go into the value.
The values 50, some becomes 30 plus $50, 80.
OK, next time I began to three.
Three is less than equal to four values, the next value that is this number.
We are reading the third number, OK?
We are reading the third number.
And we lose 20, so some becomes 80 plus 20.
That is Android.
And finally, we read the next number that is equal to Ford or is less than equal to Ford.
And we read the value that is 10.
And we update us here, so some equals.
Under less than.
Which becomes one 110, and we update.
The eye becomes five, so then I becomes five.
We again come here, which is five, then equal to four Dhanteras.
No.
We print the sum.
And what is the final value of some?
It is 110, so we get the output at 110 and we exit.
That's how we can handle the processing of multiple inputs.
Okay?
So in this example, we do not need to store all the numbers at once.
We are only storing the current number, OK?
But in some problems, we might require to store all the numbers.
And later on, in the course, you will learn about data centers to one data center that can be used
for storage.
It's called as Eddy.
OK.
It's called Azadi that would be covered in the later topics, not in this topic.
So I hope you have understood how to handle multiple inputs inside a flowchart, and that's all for
this video.