I assume now we will try out another problem.
The problem is given a number we want to check if it is a prime number or not.
Let us quickly recap what is the prime number to?
A prime number is a number that has only two dividers, one and the number itself, OK?
If you're given and and it has only two dividers, one and the number itself, then it is a prime number.
Few examples of prime numbers.
For example, seven to only one in seven divide seven the number 11, only one and 11 divide the number
11.
Or talk about the number like 13, only one and 13.
Divide this number.
So only one end to divide.
So all of them.
Numbers are prime numbers.
So what is a non prime number, so a non prime number will have at least one device it in the range
to do and minus one?
OK.
At least one device that in the range.
To do and minus one.
So why do two and minus one, because you have seen that one and then divide all the numbers, they
divide prime numbers.
They also divide non-prime numbers.
But if you have, at least one divides it in this range, starting from two up to n minus one.
OK.
If you find at least one it here, then you can see that this number is a non prime number.
OK, this number is a non brand.
For example, the number nine, so it has a divisor in the range to do it and the divide that history,
the three divides nine.
So you get to nine Model three.
This is zero.
And.
Nine is a non prime number.
Talk about the number 14.
So two divides.
14.
And this is not brain, OK?
Seven also divides 14, but we need to find only at least one device that will get one device that is
sufficient to prove the number is not brain.
Now, given a number, we need to check if it is prime or not.
Can we come up with a very simple logic?
Approval a no is prime or not.
Yes, logic would be that we can try to find out divisor in the range to do and minus one phone, find
out or devise it in the range.
It will do and minus one, if the device that is found, if you are able to get a device it.
Then, yes, the number is not prime.
OK.
And if the device that is not found.
Then you can set the numbers right.
OK.
This is how simple it is to prove a number is primal, not knowing what you can do is you can take a
pause and try to think of a flowchart approval numbers game or not.
OK, so let us try.
The first step, as we discussed, would be a start.
Then we will try to read the value of the number that we want to prove as prime or not will read the
value of an.
The next step would be what?
We need to.
Find advisor in the range to do and minus one, OK?
That means we will need a loop in this range.
It will do and minus one.
Let us take.
I'm currently at the no I initialize my eyes to.
I will.
OK, I used to.
And now what I will do, I trade buildings I as less than equal to minus one.
This is my stopping point of life.
I will take if I is less than equal to and minus one.
So this will go inside diamond at because it's a condition.
If it is less than equal, then minus one, OK?
If the case is yes or if the case is no, OK, we'll see what will happen in each of these cases if
it's less than equal one minus one.
Then what we will do will try to divide and with I and find out the remainder.
We will check will give and is divisible by alternate will again put in either condition and that if
conditions, if I is if modulus I.
If this is equal to zero.
Now again, two things can happen, Don, that again, we know or the answer can be yes.
OK, now, if the answer is yes, what we can do, we can simply say that this number is a prime number.
OK?
This number is is not the prime number because, for example, talk about the number nine and you reach
three to nine.
Model three is zero.
And hence, you can see that this number is not prime, so you can print that this is a not prime number.
And Jordan.
You're done at this point.
OK, so what are you going to do?
You're going straight, go to exit.
You can safely exit the program from this particular point.
But what if, if it is not OK, if it is no, then what you're going to do?
So you are going to say, don't let it.
It might be possible that the end is not divisible by two.
It might be divisible by three.
So you are going to take it to the next place.
We are doing this.
OK?
Let us increment is a plus one.
And now what we are doing, we are again going to connect back here.
OK.
Again, we are going to connect back here again.
We will go to the next day.
We will check if that is less than equal to and minus one.
If it is yes, if it is divisible print, not prime.
Otherwise, we increment day and we again do the same thing again.
OK?
Now finally, if you come out of this direction, OK?
So in what case you will come out of this?
No direction, OK?
So can you think?
In what NATO, you will come out of it, the only scenario in which you will come out of from this blog
is via this error is when you do not exit the loop through inside this direction, OK?
That means we could not find a device that in the range to do and minus one that could divide and and
hence from here you can say OK, if it is, if I has reached this value, you can simply say print name.
And then you can simply do exit, OK?
Or you can connect to the same exit here.
Not an issue.
Now let us try to brighten this flow chart for value of any call to seven.
OK, let's see what happens for an equal to seven eyes, to the words less than equal to six or two
is less than equal to six.
Is seven divisible by two than it is?
No.
So you increment right?
So the eye becomes three.
OK, the eye becomes three.
Three is less than equal to six.
Is seven divisible by three boundaries?
No.
So you again come here are equal to eight plus one.
You again go back here, OK, via this route.
So I is known for the Xenical.
Six seven is not divisible by four.
It becomes five.
Five is less than equal to six.
Seven is not divisible by five.
Again, no.
You come here and it becomes six.
Texas, less than equal to six seven, is not divisible by six.
And that is no.
And the value of, I know becomes seven.
So when you when you now come here, OK, so I is seven, which is not less than equal than minus one.
Hence, you come out of this brand and you print that it is a premium, but hence you say, OK, the
number seven is a prime number.
OK.
And then we exit, so it would have been some of the no like nine.
So you would have been OK.
There was less than equal to eight, but nine is not divisible by two.
Make it three trees less than equal to eight and nine more, three is zero.
You come here.
Then you hit a yes, your brain does not break and then you exert.
Then guess of nine, you will print that this number is not plain, OK?
So I hope this flowchart is now clear to you and your understood how we have implemented a loop.
OK, so what barred from the loop this box?
Is the starting point of the new book, if this is just a condition inside the loop?
This is just a condition inside a loop.
OK?
This part is the starting point of the loop, which has this stopping criteria.
Here we have the update condition, and this part is the work then.
OK.
So that's all for this video, I hope you understood the concept.
Thank you.