Alright, so let us do one more problem on flowcharts and this problem, we want to find the greatest
common divisor of two numbers, OK?
And it is also known as DCD on Etsy.
If, for example, let's say there is a number that is eight, it is a number B that has led to 12.
So what is the largest number that divides both of these numbers?
OK.
So by.
And division we can do this number is nothing went forward.
What is the largest number that will divide eight and 12 would.
OK, for example, is eight and B is letter 24.
In this case, the DCT would be nothing but it because it divides aid.
And it also divides 24.
And maybe there is a no, let's say is nine.
And let's be is living in this case, the desert is one that is no common divisor except one between
the two numbers, OK?
So if you look carefully, you can see that if you have a number a, it's A and a No.
B.
We can clearly see that the DCD of these numbers and we would always be less than equal to minimum of
the two numbers.
OK.
It would always be less than equal to a minimum of two numbers.
So, for example, is it and B is 12?
You cannot have a number that is greater than the smaller number that will divide both, OK?
So you cannot say I will have a number 10 that will also divide it.
No, this is not possible.
The decree would always be less than or equal to the minimum of two numbers and the minimum value of
a number that can divide both the numbers would be one.
So we can say that the DCD would lie in the range.
Think from one to the minimum of.
A common be, OK?
This would be the end so that we know that our answer would always lie in this range.
OK, so we are trying to build a very brute force logic for computing logically.
Again, we are going to try out all possibilities what numbers can be a desired offer given them, but.
To this, we know, and if we know this, we can easily I dread over the strange using the loop.
And now we want to find out the greatest number in this range, which divides what end.
So let us see how we will build this particular algorithm.
Let's dig an example, let's say.
Is it?
And let it be is Wendy makes it to what is minimum of a.
It is, of course, it will outrage over the range.
One two three four five six seven eight.
In the beginning, we attract one.
Does one divide A and B none.
Three Yes.
And we will have we will update our decision.
OK, so what is the largest number we have seen that divides both?
That number is nothing but one.
We go to do those to divide and us to divide be the answer is yes.
So we will update our DCD studios to those three divide, but it does not divide it.
It does not divide 20 does four divide eight and 20?
Yes, it divides the four divides eight and four divides 20.
So hence the decision is for now we go to five.
Does not divide, does not divide.
We go to six.
Does not divide.
We go to seven.
We go to eight.
It divides eight.
But it does not divide 20.
OK, so that means.
And what would be the value of these hidden all these iterations?
We have not updated the value of decision in all of these arbitrations.
Finally, the DCD would be nothing but forward.
OK, the decision would be same.
That would be for.
So we've found all three numbers one, two and four that divides, what, 18 20.
Hence the largest number as forward and hence the decision is for now, take a pause and think, can
you come up with a flowchart to solve this problem?
OK, now let us discuss the solution.
Let's solve using a flowchart.
The first step would be start.
As usual, then it would be read they're doing numbers that is read and be.
And now what we are going to do, we are going to initialize what we are doing to initialize led to
AI that is equal to one.
And we're going to go to a minimum of envy, so if I is less than equal to a minimum of a comma B.
OK.
If it does, yes.
So what we are going to do is we are going to check.
If I divides and divides me also, so we are again going to put our decision box here.
Is a divisible by.
And be divisible by.
If the answer is yes, OK?
Then what we are going to do.
We are going to update our DVD.
We are going to say that what do you see is equal, do I because I is the largest number so far we have
seen that divides both NBA?
That divides both N.B., so we have to complete this brand of norm, and we have to complete this brand
of noise with.
So after updating this will do we will go to the next day.
That is I will do I +1.
And even if I does not divide and we would, then also we will go to the snakes branch and we will say,
OK.
I was, too.
A-plus.
What?
And from here, we are again going to connect bucket.
We are again going to connect bank it, so if we come out of the loop, that means we have explored
all options.
What we are going to do.
We are going to bring the value of diversity so we can bring.
The do you study the greatest common divisor, and that's it.
Not X-rated.
OK.
We are done.
Now, let us try to brighten this cold for, let's say.
Six on foot.
OK.
It's a six and B is.
Later, this is what end is will run this code from one to four.
OK, so when I choose, one is one less than minimum of N.B., so minimum of India's vote, so is four
divisible by one.
Is six divisible by one, yes, is Florida eligible were one, yes.
So what we do?
Do you think we're the ones over these three days?
One?
Great.
We go to makes no I equal I plus one, I becomes too.
Is six divisible by one for divisible by 200?
Yes, we are going to go ahead and we update a verdict.
Do you see this?
Do we go to three?
The next number that is three is six divisible by three, yes, is four divisible.
No, we do not update our duty.
We simply take this route and go to the next number.
We go to four is six divisible by four.
No is four divisible by four.
Yes.
So we don't update our destiny.
So this really remains same.
That is true.
So finally, we make is five.
And five is not less than equal to minimum of envy, so what we do, we come out of this loop, we bring
the GST and then we exit.
That's all.
That is how we have computed the OECD using a very basic solution, OK, data optimized algorithms to
do it.
That is a Euclid's algorithm, but that would be that would not be covered yet.
It's slightly advanced algorithm, and this is the most basic way of computing the DCT.
That's all for this video.
Thank you.