Everyone in this lecture will discuss the real world example of flowchart.
OK.
Just to make of it in this tiny little mode better the question as a bank is open till six pm and the
banker needs to process requests from the customers, OK?
The requests can be of one of the four types Guy's deposit, cash withdrawal, check deposit and making
or demand draft.
We want to draw the flowchart of a bank employee.
Now, the bank employee can process one of these requests, but we also need to see that the customer
can enter the bank if it is open.
So let us see how the flowchart would look like.
So if you want, you can spend two minutes to think and try to come up with a solution of your own.
Otherwise, we had the solution and we will discuss this solution with you, OK?
So the flowchart will start from the first step.
The bank gets open in the morning and in front of bank.
There is a queue and the if.
If the queue is empty, OK, and time is greater than six p.m., then we will close the bank.
Otherwise, what we will do, we will try to extract customers from the queue.
OK?
So if there are people which are standing in the queue, we will try to extract the customers OK from
the queue.
Now, if the bank is open.
So suppose you come here and the bank is open and there can be two possibilities either the queue is
empty on the queue is not empty.
That means during the time that the bank is open.
OK, so we are coming here when time is less than six.
And now if the queue is empty, then we will again go and check whether there are certain people that
have entered the queue or not.
If it is not the case, then we will extract a customer from the queue.
So in the later on, when you will learn some more concepts about programming, you will learn about
data centers, OK?
The researchers are nothing, but they are the containers that store data.
So you is actually your data sector.
So we are performing an operation that if the queue is empty or not, if there is a person here, if
there is a person here that is a person, it these people, ABC, they are waiting in the queue to get
their work done and the bank will remove the ghost mode, which is dead at the front of the queue.
Our next step would be to read the request of this person.
We will ask this person, What do you want to do?
That is denoted using this box read request.
Now, once you have read the request, you have to make a decision which content this person will give.
So there are, let's say, four different counters.
One as A1 is B, one is C, one is D, which processed these requests.
OK, so first we will check is this request for a demand draft?
If we did, yes, we send this customer to country.
If it is not, we check if it is a request for direct deposit.
If yes, we send this person to counter, we if not, we send this person to counter-sued and we check
if it is for cash withdrawal.
If yes, we send this to counter C, otherwise we take it for this guy's deposit.
We send it to we.
If it is something else, OK, so maybe we have a miscellaneous helpline Gonder.
So we send this person to that country.
OK, this is how the various requests of these persons would be processed.
Now you may have separate flowchart for each of these actions.
OK, so maybe there could be a flowchart starting from me.
OK, this is how you process the demand graph.
So humans OK, it is a flowchart read demand draft OK, and there may be some process to create a demand
draft.
OK, or something like that.
Credit or debit demand, whatever you want to do, and then maybe end or hand it over to the customer,
whatever it could be.
So there can be separate flowchart for a busy, endless what you can do.
So sometimes in a problem, the flowchart can get quite big.
So in that case, you be the other part of the flowchart like we are doing in this case, starting from
E, it'll be exit.
OK, well, we exit all, be connected to some other point.
So what we are doing is we're making these circles, so these circles are known as connectors.
Look, they are known as the nucleus, so they're combining two different products.
And there can be separate flowchart for ABC, and so.
But now we have to understand that this would be a high level overview of our flowchart for a bank employee,
it would look like, OK, it's a bank employee would wait for customers in the queue that you would
be dead if the bank is open.
And for that, that is certain time.
And yes, that's how a flowchart would look like.
I hope you understood this flowchart on that side for this video.