OK, here is a quick thinking problem for you, so you have to draw a flowchart for a bank security
guard.
OK, so the bank security guard is going to wait for the customers outside the bank.
And if they're coming before 6:00 p.m., it will add the customers to the queue.
Otherwise, it will keep on waiting.
And if time reaches six p.m., he is going to close the bank.
OK, so this was this video and think how you are going to build this flow chart?
OK?
Now let's talk about the solution.
The solution would look something like this.
The bank is open.
And the security guard is going to take every dime, is it 6pm or not, if it's six p.m.?
If the answer is yes, he is going to close the bank if it is not.
He's going to check whether there is a customer waiting outside the bank.
If yes, is going to add the customer to the queue.
OK, so this is how it goes, like at the customer to the queue.
And that's that's the work of the security guard.
OK, if you are not worried, what will happen to the customer?
That is a part of a separate flow given to enters the bank.
So then, after doing both the steps where the customer is waiting or not, he will.
He will continuously check when to close the bank.
So he's always looking at his watch.
What is their time if there is a customer added to the queue?
Look at the time.
If it is, if no customer is waiting again, look at what is their time will give.
So he's doing these two steps repeatedly.
OK, so this part is inside a loop continuously.
Look at the time.
And if there is a customer in time added to the queue, if there is not a customer, look at the time,
OK?
So in both the cases, after adding to the customer, he looked at time on other ways as well.
And as soon as time reaches six p.m., he is going to close the bank.
That's all.
That's a pretty simple flowchart of a security guard of a bank.
I hope you understood this one as well.