Hello, everyone, so we are going to start with the new module that is on character, that is strength.
And we will also discuss about the gadget today in little more detail.
What we are going to do is we are going to talk about three things.
One is how connectors work, how they are stored on what are some available functions which you can
use on the catheter Typekit.
So the part one is only about a single character.
And so we'll talk about gadget today on what library functions we can use in the park to really talk
about those new style strings, which are also known as connected areas.
And we will also look at what are the various functions available like to input output or to find the
length of the string or get these character arrays.
They're used to store things like these, either also known as string laterals.
And if you want to perform, read, write operations on those strings, and this is where the character
is.
They are helpful.
They are also known as E style strings.
And talking about the modern C++, the modern C++ support something which is known as a string class.
Which is an object oriented programming way of dealing with things will get.
So we'll also talk about the string glass and which is based on the principles of object oriented programming
more than C++.
We use the strings very frequently, but we learn this ISA style strings as well, starting from the
basics of the candidate.
All right.
So that's a quick intro of what we're going to do on to you in the next video.