Hello, everyone, so let us start off our discussion from the car today that we have already seen couple
of times the card reader Typekit is used to store a single character.
OK, so generally we represent some got us, got name of the variable, let's see it, and it is going
to hold some character.
So maybe the character is a or maybe the character is Dollard, or the character could be a number or
a single digit to Canada, but the character might be something like a space if it can be white space
with.
The character must be surrounded by single goods.
That is how you define the value of a character.
And if you try to do something like this led to God, some later maybe.
And you put something like a inside.
So it is not valid.
It is going to give you an idea because this thing is not a character.
This thing is known as a string literal, and you cannot store something with the chords inside a character.
OK?
Let me show you a quick demo of working with the character, and let's see what we can do.
Now I want to hold a character.
I'd say this should work and I can do the basic output operation as well, so it will give me as well,
right?
So if I just run, the dogs got them so I can see the later.
Is it on if you want, you can put you can also bring some special characters like new lines or box
lésion.
It's not two characters.
It's known as a Newlyn character, it's a single character.
This is how it is defined, and now the output would be printed.
So you have a new line up again, that's where you don't see this person dead symbol in this case.
And so, yes, this is known as a new line, correct?
OK, so maybe.
Again, this is what a new line character is.
And you're going to go on to print two characters one.
And one new line character.
It will give us the same output again.
Now, one thing we want to talk about is how these characters are internally mapped.
So to store these characters in the form of memory, we know that everything is a binary and that means
the characters, they also need to be converted into binary so you cannot create a inside the memory
of the computer gets into how it is going to get stored.
We have the encoding standard, which is known as the.
Now, as they correctly said, it is the first correct decision or it defines the encoding standard
and it is widely used on computers and internet.
It's a seven bit characters requisite containing 128 characters.
Look on these characters include 029, The Upper and the lower case English letters from A2Z, and there
are some special characters as well.
So you have A2Z A2Z digits from zero to nine whitespace backslash in all, including the operators plus
minus multiply.
All of these are part of the ASCII could a classic.
And the Oscars dance for American Standard Code.
For information interchange or information.
Interchange.
Now you may ask, how does it represent because of what this ask encoding does it maps?
Each letter, whether indeed, for example, the capital aid, this is mobbed with 65.
A capital B.
This is Margaret, 66, the capital theaters mob with 67 and so on.
Similarly, the smallest mob with 97, this Molby is mob with 98.
And so on.
Similarly, the digits, the operators are also mobbed with some indigent.
And since we have 128 characters, 11, which aren't sufficient to store any greater, OK, so we need
a storage box of seven bricks.
But what happens is the compiler actually gives us a standard box, which is of one bite.
OK.
One way would mean Edwards if this is the minimum allocation the compiler can do on a machine.
The what?
What happened is the characters.
They are stored in eight buckets and hence if you look at how much size each character is going to take,
it is going to be one byte.
So maybe you can to see out size of operated on you tell me what is the size of a character today or
how much storage you're using to store the letter in.
So in the both the cases, the output would be one.
So let us see what we can see.
We are getting one because what that is, the reason the ask holds.
It needs seven bits to get stored, but the compiler says I cannot allocate a box, which is less than
eight bits.
That means one byte and hence each letter.
It does take eight by itself, eight bits of storage.
That is one vital storage that is about the ask requisite are.
Now you may ask, OK, show us how how these numbers, they are represented as invaders.
So one thing we can do is we can it.
I want to print this correct.
But I want to interpret this correctly as indeed, I don't want to look this as a or something.
So let us try to understand why this is getting printed.
But it is getting stored as a 60 is why it happens to basically see out, get to know that, OK, it's
going to print some.
No, it's going to print some value.
It is going to look at the data, right?
If the data type is correct for 65, it will be printed A-Z.
But if you tell code, no, this is not 65, this is this is not a corrected what it is indeed.
OK, then it is going to print.
It does different.
What I'm trying to tell you is you can do the implicit type conversion while printing it.
So you can do explicit type cost.
You can tell to Oh no, I'm not printing uncorrected, but I'm printing something which is in.
OK, so you are saying interpret this character as indeed it and then you print it OK?
And maybe for New Line as well, we can do the same thing.
Let me first tell you the output for it, and you're going to is not printed us, but let us also see.
What does the.
Ask for a new line.
OK.
What is how is the backslash and stood?
OK, it's a new line gas.
We are printing first, the immediate bond, followed by the new line, which will actually do the work
of A..
OK, now if I do, you can see the Oscar of a new line corrected is actually so that means the box less.
It is getting stored as an inside your memory.
Let us do it for some of the numbers as well.
Maybe I can say four in the equal to zero I less than equal roulette.
Wolitzer Then maybe let me start from sixty five.
And I want to go to, let's say.
R26, that is a Pulitzer.
OK.
What I wanted to do, I want to print all the letters from A to Z.
OK, so maybe I can to see out letters and then.
And what I will do is I'm reading from Orange that is 65 to 91.
That means I should be able to see the letters A, B, C, D and so up to Z because they are 26 letters
in a b, c d.
What I'm trying to do is or you can simply say, 65 plus 26, that is also OK, if that makes more sense
to you.
What I'm going to unfold, going to print the integers and then I'm going to soak it, I also want to
see what this value would be if you try to interpret this in digit as a correct.
So here we are going to do the conversion.
Either way, I don't we are going to say, OK, if you interpret the numbers 66 as a character, what
value it would be.
So basically, I'm going to see a mapping between the numbers and the corresponding letters, OK?
Now, what you can see here is we started from 65, which is a B C D up to A to Z.
So we are able to get up to nine B.
We have actually Z.
And since 65 is already included, eight, the 91 is for the Square Records.
It's it's not for the nine days for Z, right?
Ninety one you can see it is four square records.
So maybe what you can you can rent to less than ninety one that will do the work for you.
You can also run from zero to 128.
And you can see what as the number mobbed with each agent.
OK, so if I know, then this could.
Now you can see.
Starting from zero, although there are certain numbers there, ma'am, but they might not be not printable
format, okay, so the terminal might not be able to print it.
The 33 is for X laboratory, 39 is for like single code and so on.
So you can see there are digits.
There are operators, they are A2Z and there is also a 2D starting from 97 until like 122.
OK, so this is what the Oscar table looks like.
I hope you have understood the concept of ASCII and I'll see you in the next read you.