Hello, everyone.
So in this lecture, we'll try to solve a problem where we will take input later on.
We will try to identify whether it is a whitespace or is it a letter from zero to nine?
Or is it a uppercase letter or is it a lowercase letter or it is a special symbol, OK?
That is what we are going to do right now talking or the first thing that we have to do is we have to
read some later.
Okay, so let us try to read a particular letter.
OK?
Right now, what we know till now is that we can use theme to read it.
Let's try to use scene to read it, and maybe I'll just output the letter as well, right?
And let me just try to run this code.
Sorry, we have to comment the problem statement here and now we can build it.
If I now try to show you what happens if I run this program and dodge large, identify later and the
I give in.
And I do get the output great if I give five.
OK, five can be stored as a little.
That's OK.
And if I give fifty nine.
What is happening in this case?
We are actually giving two letters and a world scene.
It's going to only read the first letter that this fight will get.
And even if you give something like a it, will read only the first letter that is h the scenes, which
means only read the first and put.
From here, that is what it is going to read.
But now suppose I give some white space.
What happens if I give a new line?
The program is still working, it's it's not reading whitespace.
If I give a little space base, it's still running, it's not reading whitespace.
If I give it to space based aid, it is going to read the first letter that is OK, that is actually
a problem with seen.
It does not.
It does not read white spaces.
It ignores all the white spaces.
Whatever problems is, we have to identify whether we have red or white space at night.
So how do we solve this problem?
In problems where you have to read white spaces as well.
Here comes a function which is known as seen or get will not use seen will use Inderjit and not good
reads all possible type of characters, including white spaces.
OK.
And generally, what happens with scene terminates when a white space is formed?
And how not good reads a string with the whitespace, OK?
So scene is just going to ignore, OK, to terminate might not be the right word.
It just ignores whenever there is a white space.
OK, so that means it will never read white space for you.
Oh, it's not great, reads a string with the white space as well.
OK, so now what we're going to do in our court, we are not going to use this statement.
We are just going to come and read out.
And we can see it equals the endgame that the scene is actually an object and objects do have methods.
It is a method built on the scene object.
And this is going to read.
A single character.
OK.
It's going to create a single character, and that character can be whitespace as well.
Now what we are doing, we are going to run this code.
Again, and let me show you, if I say.
Whitespace and but we have to build it again, right?
And let me just run this again whitespace, and so it did stop, the program did stop and it actually
printed a whitespace because if you are not sure it did bring the whitespace, maybe what you can print,
you can print the Australian white space.
Let's see if I give white space, followed by an OK.
Oh, you may ask, that is needed.
See what happens now if you don't press enter.
The data is still on the screen of the console.
OK, it's not good to the algorithm.
The algorithm reads data from something which is known as input buffer.
OK.
And currently we're on the screen.
So on the screen, you have whitespace, ABC, whatever you have, it is, it's it's still change.
Well, look, it's whatever you rated, it still can be erased.
But once you put it, the into the input goes from the screen to input buffer, which is like a temporary
storage and you're seeing audio Syndergaard.
Both of them.
They're going to read from the input booklet.
OK.
They're going to read from the input buffet, whatever you use.
So if you have ABC, both of them are going to read ABC.
But if you have, the only thing is you will need to put put a loop to read multiple characters and
interject.
It is also keen to read if there is a white space in the beginning.
OK, so if you put a white space followed by a new line, it is going to read the white space as the
first letter.
OK?
Let me show you if I put a.
So is 65 if I give symbol white space and ended.
So it is printing 32.
So 32 is the Oscar value for space.
And if I just hit a new line.
It is printing tens or then this is just like the ASCII value of backslash.
OK, we just give back lésion, but just then we give space, which is 32.
It is reading both types of white spaces.
Now the program was to identify what later it is.
So what we can do is we can see if C-H equals white space or C, it equals new line.
We can begin to see out under white space.
Is what we can begin to if.
See, it's three LS if.
The edge is greater than equal to a.
And it is less than equal to the night.
Or C, it is greater than equal to smaller.
And had just less than equal disloyalty.
OK, begin to seal it so later, right?
Maybe it's.
Later.
If you can see it is greater than equal to zero on the edges, greater than less than equal to nine.
That means it's actually a digit.
And as you can see, it's a special symbol.
It's a team that actually completes our program.
But before that, let us try to see how we have ridden these comparisons again, why these comparisons
will work.
Now suppose your letter was actually.
What we are doing, we are saying, is this greater than equal to eight?
That means two.
Whenever you have a mathematical operator, each tries to compute the individual values of these operate.
So it is going to say, OK, the letter is D, which is.
68.
And is this greater than equal to a which is actually 65?
And is it less than equal than the previous?
So it is less than equal to 90.
That is the value of the item or does it lie in the range of.
Molly?
OK, so something like this, does it lie in between these values?
Then of course, it is going to be later.
Does it lie in the ASCII values of the digits because these are also continuous values, maybe from
40 to 49, something like that.
If it lies in these in this range, then it is actually a digital gift.
I have to use the logical landed on the code has been wrote and illustrated underscored now, so identify
later.
It's a give way.
It says it is related.
I give it.
It is a special symbol.
I just think and it's a white space in that space, white space.
If I give it, it's actually a digital gift.
That means our code is working as expected, and that was the importance of using seen target because
otherwise we could not have solved this problem using the same policy.
So that's all for this video.
Thank you.