Hello, everyone.
In this lecture, we'll talk about a library that is available as a form of header file photos and type
tape, so this library provides us two kinds of functions to work on characters.
One set of is called as testing function.
Would you want to check whether the correct result digit or is it an uppercase or is it a space?
OK?
Similar to the one we have already done right.
But now, instead of writing the logic by yourself, this library adopts the logic for checking what
type of correct that it is.
OK, so we have added in our own logic in the previous problem.
Now, if you don't want to write such code on, you want to use a simple function that tells you whether
this is a lowercase character or is it uppercase character or is it a space?
You can use this library and a good reference, as you'll find on C++ dot coms, if they show you these
are all the functions that are available and the other type of functions that are available as to load
and to appear.
So suppose you have a letter and you want to convert it into uppercase or a lowercase LED.
You can use these methods which are available in this library.
OK, so let me show you a quick demo of working with this library.
OK, maybe I'll just call it as soon as you type demo or CPB, the first step would be to.
Include the header file that is if you type.
And now once you have the light, you can see.
Maybe Seattle was, too.
Upper arm Nicolas Cage and I can say is.
OK, so I'm building the good, this dual function is a conversion function, OK?
I'm going to show you the M1 for conversion function and if I go here and if I try to run, this could
start like Caesar type demo.
And let's it though later.
Is it so I get the cavatelli as my output, or if I give small b or small white, I get the capital
y as my output.
OK, so that is what this dual power function it's going to do for us.
The other type of functions they are so assigning functions you want to check if this letter is in uppercase
or is it in lowercase.
So you can check if.
So maybe you can see if is a but.
So let me just show you what what functions are there is up, but is a function on it except to look
at it.
It is going to run as a Boolean value, not is it a uppercase letter or not?
Maybe if it is a uppercase letter, so.
Maybe if is a put on, you give the little when to see out.
Yes, it's uppercase.
As if maybe you can take.
Is it lower case or something like that?
If it is lower, you can see out the vote.
It's lower case.
As maybe as if maybe you wanted to check if it is.
Digit is digit.
And Uganda sealed its digit and so on, so you can make more cases using these functions.
And it's going to work as expected.
So maybe I give five, so you can.
It says it's a digital, it's a digit.
And if I give Molly, it says it's in lowercase and by converting it into a garment, this is what the
output looks like.
So I hope you have understood how to use this library.
Very simple library, all types of functions.
One is a set of distinct functions you want to check if it is an alphabet, is it a digit?
Is it a lowercase letter?
Is it uppercase letter?
Is it a space?
Is it alphanumeric?
OK.
So this is the method alphanumeric means.
Is it a letter or digit?
It can be like one of these.
And the second set of functions we have seen, there are two conversion functions.
One is to convert it into uppercase and that is to convert Lotus.
So that's all for this video and we have already seen the demo for this one.
And thanks a lot for watching.