Hello, everyone.
In this lecture, we're going to solve a problem and problem name is shortage spot.
And it's a pretty interesting problem on strength.
There it is.
You want to go to a certain location which is located at X Como Y.
And you have to start from origin, okay, so doctors aren't zero zero.
And your friend is telling you a long way by telling the steps you should walk in each direction and
the directions are northwest, east or south.
You have to find out the shortest spot.
Okay, so let us look at one example where we have this input and output.
So let me just draw to that extent.
It's a this is not.
This is east, this is West, and this is salt.
And the first step, you have to go north to get the go one step not.
Then again, go not OK, then again, go north, which is like these steps, not then you have two steps
towards the east.
OK, and then you have one step towards West and then you have one step towards south to get this is
the final location where you will reach to get in order to reach this location.
What could be the shortest spot so you could have simply done?
You could have said, OK, I will go two steps north and I will go one step east and I will arrive at
this particular coordinate.
This is what you wanted to do and out.
What do you see?
It is north, not on these.
Other thing is, how do we find out what the final guardian index gumawa is starting from the origin
that is zero zero.
So the thing is, it's pretty simple.
So effectively, what you get is that if you're going through steps, not and if you're going few steps
out.
You're actually reducing your distance traveled along by axis.
This is your Y-axis and this is your x axis.
What do you need to do?
You need to find out the net displacement in the vertical direction and also in the horizontal direction.
You need to find out how much we have to walk horizontally and how much we have to walk in the vertical
direction.
That is what you need to do.
That means whenever you see a north or south, you will update your y coordinate, and whenever you
will see east or west, you will update your X coordinate, OK?
In the beginning, both X and Y the R zero right.
So x zero by zero.
You are going north.
That means you are going towards the positive axis.
Your Y becomes one again, not it becomes two again, not it becomes three.
Then you go east, so your X becomes one.
One, that is two.
Now you go west.
So this means you are going in this direction, so you will reduce your X coordinate by one.
It becomes minus one.
Then you will.
So that means you are going down.
So you reduce your y coordinate by one.
So effectively, you have all for the y axis and you have x coordinate as one.
Basically, your final location x gumawa is actually one to.
Now, depending on the Guardian, it took a quadrant so it can lie in quadrant one, you one, it can
lie in Quadrant two, it can lie in Quadrant three and it can also line Quadrant four.
OK.
It lies in Q1, so you will print the value of.
Not two times.
So you will see an alternate on since the X coordinate is one that means we are on the positive side,
the positive side means we are in the East.
You will be one thing if that is what you are going to do.
So output would be an any or it could be CNN and then both are fine.
And if you are asked to print this in lexical graphical sorted manner, you can print it first and you
can print and later on.
OK, so it could be CNN, or it could be in any water fine as output.
I hope you have understood this problem.
So what do you need to do?
Firstly, you need to find out the final displacement, the final value of X and Y coordinates, and
then you need to convert this into a corresponding string.
OK.
Which again, can be done using a loop.
So let us try to see how we can go this problem up in the next lecture.
And that's all for this video.