Everyone's in this lecture, we're going to look at the solution for this problem.
OK, so first of all, we have to read and put OK, until now we have not seen how do we store a complete
string?
OK.
And that is also not required for this problem.
So what we actually need is we need to stored the current direction at any point during their time,
right?
So we don't need to store everything, we just need to store.
And then the next end and then next and guess what we can do?
We can put a loop until we don't read everything until the end of the line.
Okay, so that means we have to read it in this new line, correct?
So first, let's do the first part there.
Just try to read the input and let us try to print it.
Maybe what I can do, I can say just I'm going to store it a single later on today, so I can say it,
guys.
The edge that is equal to scene.
Not great that I actually read the first letter on the first letter and I can divide.
This character is not equal to a new line, correct?
But I'm going to read the next letters I can to see it equals good.
And after every letter that I've read, maybe I can print it to show you that how we are reading a sequence
of letters or get what we can to see out C-H, maybe followed by Oklahoma it.
I hate the good we have to first save the file.
Maybe I can say shortest, but not CPB.
And let's build a code.
All right.
And let's try to run it.
Maybe I say and then and it says W. So yes, I'm able to read all the letters.
Well, I don't reach the end of the line.
OK, so I've put this in.
There is a box lesson which is not visible to us.
OK.
And since we are using the same target method, it would be able to read facial letters like white spaces,
including the box lesson.
So we are saying, OK, read everything until you don't hit the end of the line.
And every time we are reading one letter and we are printing it, OK?
And what we have to do, we have to decide an action based on every input, OK, every letter that we
read.
Now, suppose we have no four directions, OK?
We just have been that there are four directions north, south, east and west.
Your letter can pick one of these values.
OK, so you can say switch.
It's put a Switch statement on our later that maybe you can now this can take the value night.
What do you do?
So you need to go in this direction.
OK, you need to increment the way, and if you have East, you need to increment the X. If you have
West, you have to decrement.
And if you have south, you have to decremental the way.
What I will do, I will keep you variables which are.
Which are both set to zero in the beginning that denote we are standing currently here, OK, now if
I get north, that means we have to go vertically up, so I increment way and break.
If the case is south, I decrement why and break if the case is east, I increment X and I break on
if the cases west.
I decrement X and I break, OK, now we have handled the actions for each of the four cases.
Finally, when we will come out of the loop, right, then we will come out of the loop.
We will know the final displacement in terms of numbers where we want to go.
So maybe you want to see out the final XS X and the Final Y is, let's say, the Y.
It's political, and let us try to run this for a given, and let's head north, not north east.
East, west and south.
That means we have to move one unit towards the positive politics and we have to move two units towards
the North.
But just correct, OK, if it is correct.
So we had the north once out.
Effectively it becomes three minus one.
That is, it times towards night and we had to east on one west, one west.
Effectively, we have to move one two eight one times towards the East, if that is what we need to
do now coming to the second part.
Okay, so how do we convert these numbers?
Into a string, okay, so again, you will have actually four cases.
OK.
Case one would be if both X and Y.
If both of them are positive, that means we are talking about the Quadrant one.
Basically, their direction is towards north and east.
OK.
That means if access to how much east you will print, you will print east two times.
So maybe you're going to fall into some ground that is equal to zero boundless and equal to X plus plus
and you can print.
Eat these many times.
And you have also you have to also print not rights of or not.
You have to look at the count of.
So you can say.
But in count, equal to one pound less than equal to weigh less.
You see out not right.
OK, let me just build a good and as if you will have another case for the second quadrant, when X
is negative, Y is positive.
Another case and another case, OK, so I'm just going to leave these cases for you.
You can load them up.
OK.
So basically, you have four quadrants.
So in this quadrant, you go north and east.
In this quadrant, you go north and west.
In this quadrant, you have south and west.
And in this quadrant, you have south and east.
Get if if the values are, let's say, minus three minus two, it means you have to print west three
times and you have to print south two times.
OK.
So this is what you need to do in in this quadrant.
So right now, I just handled the case for this quadrant, right?
And I'm just going to commend these out, and definitely you can call them up because most of our work
is already done and we have the goal and we we I can show you the shortest, but let's not not north
and east, east, south and west we get CNN, which is the expected answer for this problem.
All right.
So it seems we are done and that's all for this video.
So the learning thing was not.
Even without storing the entire string, we could build a logic which processes each of these characters
one by one and update the net displacement in X and Y coordinates.
And from the net displacement, we're able to make up a list of characters that we're printing in the
output, and that is the shortest bad problem for us.
Thank you for watching this video.