Hello, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to solve this problem where we have to print the burden of the following
form on for a given value often, for example, and it's forward for this example.
What we need to do, we need to print multiple rules on each row.
Has multiple letters, OK?
Let us try to break this pattern of every problem.
Every pattern problem follows the friend of a brick and make gift.
So how we are going to break it and let's see how we are going to make it.
So how do we break this rule?
So first of all, we have this big part, and the first thing that we can break is we can break over
multiple rules.
We can talk.
This is rule number one.
This is rule number two.
This is row number three and zero four.
Each row follows a certain formula.
The one thing that we can observe is that.
Every row begins with a.
That is what we know it.
And then we have some number of letters in every talk.
So, for example, in the first row, we do have two letters, OK?
One letter on one more letter.
And in the second row, we have two letters which are increasing.
They come here, we go to B and then two letters which are decreasing, OK, in the third row, we have
three letters which are increasing, followed by three letters which are decreasing.
And in the third row, we have four letters which are increasing on four letters which are decreasing.
Basically, the second observation is that Inayat row.
You have a number of letters which are in the increasing order and you have a number of letters which
are in the decrease in Iraq.
And these are letters.
They always begin with.
But what about the decrease in letters a day, basically a resume from a value where we left it?
So if we talk about equal to three, we had eight.
We made it as b, then we printed T.
I'm in the memory.
Like, when you're printing three letters, you will make an update.
Always, OK, I'm going to the next letters and the next letter is supposed to be B, but you only wanted
to print three letters.
OK?
Now you again, you want to resume printing, starting from C.
Look at this.
You want to print C, you want to go one step behind B and then you want to print it.
OK, so again, you have three letters which are in the decreasing order.
What I'm going to tell you is maybe you have a loop that runs three times and every time you print some
value later, the value was initially unusual.
Let me bring the blue and I do value plus plus.
That means if you increment a three times so it becomes you print the increment it, it becomes B,
you print B increment, it becomes you print C and increment it.
And this letter or this character in the memory will be actually D.
It will not be C because every time you print a letter, you increment write this incremental letter.
We are not printing, but we need this value to generate the next letter that is actually C.
Effectively, what I have to do is when I'm putting a loop for decreasing letters, I have to reset
my value by going one step back.
That is what we need to do, right?
Let me start building the code and then you will observe what is happening.
So let us go here and we will try to write the code from these observations.
So first we will read and and then will build our part.
I guess we need to print some number of rules so I can afford and I to one.
I less than equal to any idlis, plus this look is for roads, OK now in each row.
What I need to do, I need to print numbers which are in the increasing order.
So I need how many numbers I need I numbers or II letters in increasing order, starting from a.
And then I need I letters in decreasing order, starting from the last printed letter, right?
That is what we have.
If I need to print I letters, I can put a loop that runs.
It aims to count less than equal to I count.
But that's OK.
But what about the value of the letter?
OK?
Do I need to print account?
No, I don't need to bring the account.
I need to print a letter which starts from me.
Maybe I can see card value that is equal to each and every time I'm printing the value.
I'm going to increment it OK to the value now gets implemented.
Let me build the code.
And let me just show you the intermediate output we had in this problem.
ABCD partner.
If as a fault, OK, we just forgot to add a new line every time we're going to the new.
We should also present a new line.
If it is full, so we get a b, ABC, ABC to be great.
We are getting the letters in the increasing order and the next step is we need to print the letters
in the decreasing order.
OK?
The first let me show you what is the value of the letter after the end of the loop.
So maybe just printing like this, so the loop ends and the value is actually value, right?
So let me show you what this value is.
So I read it for an equal two foot when the loop ends.
The values actually be the blueprint.
Maybe you increment, be it become C to the loop and the value is.
But in the actual output you need to print be after B, right?
That means you have to take one step back.
You have to say, OK, well, look, we'll do voluminous.
And now you can start printing letters in the decreasing order.
So I'll just copy this loop.
I will be.
Do I need a loop that runs eight times and every time it brings the value?
And the next letter is one less than the currently.
And we can do well.
Luke will do value minus minus those since characters.
They are stored as integers.
So these increment agreement operators, they would work perfectly fine.
And that's all we are done with the good.
So now what we can do, we can run this on now.
If I give any call before you can see I'm getting the expected output.
All right.
Two.
Well, that's all how we could solve this solution.
If you're not there, I just give you a break.
We have our outer four loop, which works for those we have in there for, which brings letters in the
increasing order.
For example, if I is three, it prints a b c.
And value is what holds the value of the letter that is getting printed.
And so when we come here, the value is actually what do we want to start printing again?
Clumsy.
So we re initialize our value add value minus one to the value it was.
D it now becomes C.
So we printed and we reduce it.
So we make it be reprinted and we reduce it.
We make it.
So we printed and we reduce it.
It becomes active.
What?
We don't print it.
So after this, we hit the new line and the same thing repeats for the next byte as well, right?
That is the big can strategy for our Biden problem, and I hope you like this video.