Everyone, so in this, we do have a small video quiz for you.
And the question is, you have to guess the outputs I will type in some good on.
You need to tell me what the output is going to be, OK?
The one thing we're going to do, we are going to do C out C C-H plus one.
OK.
So, you know, tell me what line number nine is going to print and then I'm going to do C equals c
h plus one.
And then I'm going to print cottage.
OK.
That is the second thing you need to tell me.
I'm going to build the code, the positive you do it and think, how line number nine is it same as
line number 10?
Will they produce a different output or will they produce the output?
So just by this, we do anything.
OK?
And now I'm going to discuss the solution, so we know that C it equals it.
So is actually stored as the number sixty five.
That is what is actually stored inside the memory.
And when I'm going to run this school, this line will produce 5:54 and this line will actually produce
the number, be it.
And let me show you why and how this is happening and why it is true.
Maybe the Eiglarsh gets the output.
And yes, you can see the output is 66 and be, as I said, and the watching is why, why it is.
So let us look at line number nine right at this line, we are doing an Operation C-H plus one to see
it is as stored as 65 and we are adding this God with in trade.
So it is actually a higher rate as compared to got any operation you do of a lower rate.
With the higher rate, it will get converted into a higher rate and also the plus operator.
This is a mathematical operator, so it will assume the numbers are indeed doing this operation, it's
going to produce an integer and CO2 does not know CO2 only sees this thing as indeed it does not look,
there was a character.
It was dead, but before the addition, OK, after the addition happened, this is actually an integer.
Since it represents the numbers, 65 zero plus one would be printed as an integer that is 66.
All right.
Now let's look at line number 10.
So we are doing the eight equals CSI Plus one.
So here also it is an integer, but now we're putting it back inside a data type.
That is Scott.
OK.
That means now we have the number 66.
That is stored in a guard type of bucket.
And here we are seeing the old catch, the old will look at what value is this?
Of course, this will lose 5:54 but it is also going to look at what is a rip off.
See it.
See, it is still look at OK.
That is why this number will not be displayed as 66, but it will be displayed as I hope you found this
pretty interesting and you also got to learn a concept that adding an integer with a character leads
to an integer.
And if you put it back inside a but that would be printed as a character because the edge looks at the
data type of the number or the value that is we are getting, we had that we are going to print, OK.
I hope that's clear to you now.