Everyone in this section, we will talk about multidimensional areas.
OK, so we have already seen whatever linearity or one dimensionality.
But now we're going to talk about what is a multidimensional array, OK?
So one day it is something that we have seen.
It looks like this one on a multidimensional area.
That means it has more than one dimension to it can be étudier.
It can be 3D at, it can be afforded.
It could also be the end dimensional.
OK, so beyond 3D areas, we cannot visualize how that it would look like, but you can assume that
the data exists in and dimension.
That's something that actually exists in the memory.
And we do also have some applications of energy at IS, especially when we talk about machine learning
and deep learning, OK?
So if you go into those subjects and you will find that the data is often represented as these end dimensional
eddies, that will give you a few examples in real life where these eddies can be useful.
The one data we have already seen.
Maybe you want to store the marks of any number of students, then maybe you can make an dimensionality,
OK?
So you can have a.
So one day.
Let's say you have a one degree, let's suppose, let's say you want to store the marks, OK, maybe
there are 10 students.
So you create a mock city for 10 number of students.
But now suppose the marks are there, but they are in three subjects.
OK, let's see.
There are three subjects, and for each subject you want to store the marks of the student and maybe
what you can do is you can actually measure two degree returns.
And number of rows.
And it has three columns.
OK.
The first column later denotes the marks for physics, next for chemistry and the third for mathematics.
Maybe you can say I have a student as one or stored 10, 15 and 18 months.
I have a student as to who's told 11, 13 and 22 marks and so on.
OK.
So basically, I can say OK if I want to get the marks off.
I had student, so I can say I will pick Dietro, and that will represent all the marks of the eight
students.
So if I want to get the marks for the physics, I can simply write it would be nothing would say of
zero if I want to get the marks for chemistry again to say off one.
OK, on the device format, it would be off I off so we can use the square bracket notation to find
out the particular rule and a particular column.
For example, let's say this is at or x ungual invite.
The marks would be available at s off x comma y.
So this is how you can say a data can be represented in the form of a duty matrix.
Let us also talk about really metrics, OK, so where we can see a 3D matrix?
So very real life use kids would be images, OK?
All the images that you see on your computer, on your device, on your mobile phone, those images
are nothing, but those are a matrix of pixels.
So if you zoom in to an image, you will find that the image does nothing, but it's so good.
OK, so image is nothing but a grid.
If it is a and white image, then it is a 2D matrix.
But if it is a colored image, it is actually a 3D matrix.
OK?
So I will tell you why it is a 3D matrix.
Let's say you have an image in which the first.
Pixels, let's divide, let's add this this color is white.
White is represented using IGB colors, OK, so they're there for each pixel.
OK, let me let me try try to show you how each pixel is stored, each pixel has three components one
a component of red, and that a component of blue and another component of green.
So it would have added value, it would have a green value, it would have a blue value.
So when you mix these values together, you see a gold.
OK?
For example, the black pixel is represented as zero zero zero.
OK.
Similarly, the white pixel is represented at 255 255 255.
And maybe a gray pixel would have something like 100 100 100.
Similarly, red pixel would have.
So the first number represents the component of red that can represent blue and represents the blue.
OK.
So red, green and blue.
So maybe if I want to have a deep red pixel, then it would be the maximum value that actually it can
take.
It has to be five for red.
Red would be full, green would be zero and blue would be like zero.
OK, so these numbers can be stored in a 3D matrix and then you store images.
OK, so let's say you have an image which takes Automator bytes of memory.
Then how is this size calculated?
So this is calculated by finding the number of arrows in total, the number of columns in two three.
OK, because you're storing these many integers roles in two columns into three into the size taken
by each.
Indeed, the let's say each.
Indeed, it is eight bit into the let's say it's a eight billion budget.
OK.
Why?
And he did because the maximum value is 255.
And we can represent this data using Edwards.
OK, because do this to the voters who have this.
So we just need Edwards to represent one and bidder effectively.
We would end up getting these many bids.
And you can convert this into megabytes or kilobytes, and you will obviously need an image which has
a high resolution or higher resolution image.
Basically means you have more number of rows and a. number of columns.
OK, so basically it's a a 4K image would occupy four times more space on your SD card or on your drive.
OK.
Because the number of pixels have also increased by that particular factor.
OK?
So maybe if the board wrote in column that increased by four times, then it would occupy 16 times more
space on your SD card.
OK.
So basically, this is something that you can see that these days a year that actually related with
the day to day life.
And then you will go into machine learning.
You will also come across the full 4G data.
So if I give you one example of auto data, I give you one example of image what example?
You have a sequence of images.
OK, maybe sequence of images is nothing but a video.
Basically, you're getting one image, but second, let's see.
OK.
So what is going to happen?
Each image is a 3D image, and we're adding another dimension that there are multiple such images behind
us.
We have another image, then another image.
So basically, we have added one more dimension the dimension of time.
OK.
Or the number of frames if you want to store VIDEO.
So we would be nothing without kind of a 4D matrix, you can see.
OK.
So yeah, so that's a little bit about the multidimensional areas.
And in the next lecture, we will discuss the details.
How do we create multidimensional?
How do we take input output and how they're stored in memory?
That's I'll see you in the next.