I in this lecture, I'm going to show you how you can actually work with the two dimensionality.
So let us start by creating it already.
So let's say we have it in which we can have a $200 on an columns, and maybe then we will ask the user
to give us the number of rows and columns and we will take put the number of rows and the number of
columns.
So and the notes, those on the note columns, and you can use any any video, but the one thing you
may ask is we have to find the initial days 100, so only in most questions it would be given the constraints
would be given.
Look at maybe the maximum value of an could be 1000.
In that case, you can just make it as one thousand five or something like this.
So.
OK, so now what we're going to do, we're going to take input.
Either we can make a method, not take input or we can directly dig input here as well.
Let us directly take input four and I call the zero I less than an A-plus.
So we are going to iterate over those and then we're going to iterate over the columns.
And we're going to take input on store the input in if I comma, Yeah.
So let me tell you what we are trying to do.
So the indexing of the city?
This should be a.
J.
The indexing of the Eddy died from index zero, OK, so if I have.
Something like this.
Then this index would be zero one one zero zero zero zero column, OK?
And this is again zero one two three, so this would be zero one zero two zero three.
This would be one zero one one one two one three.
On those zero two one, it will do on two three.
So effectively, you're going to be hard to reduce.
And we had four columns, and the last index is nothing but.
And minus one and minus one, it goes from zero zero, the metric starts from zero zero and it goes
still and minus one minus one.
That is why we have redone less denim and less denim.
We are going to iterate Roberto and we're going to take input these values.
And once we are done, we can also do the printing.
So let us write the print function and we before this, we are going to write the function print and
this will teach you how you can posture to the it to a method.
I can say, OK, I want to pass and it already.
They're not going to bother to read it, but I think the number of rows is optional.
But you must pass the number of columns.
The number of columns that we have defined it is under.
This must be fixed.
And then we pass in the value of an ID. Because from this information, we don't know how many rows
and columns we actually have.
OK.
So really, what is happening now is the ad is actually pretty big where we are just using a small part
of that.
Maybe we are just using this part of the edit and we are telling the method that when you are going
to ETRADE, you just iterate over this part of the.
OK, so we are not going to iterate on the entirety.
So that's why we tell, OK, we have number of columns and we have a number of rows and ideally the
data is actually big.
It is under cross.
We are just going to use, let's say, three cross.
Something like this.
So let's see what we are going to do now.
So it would be similar.
So we need to nested loops one the loop for which goes from zero less than an A-plus plus the first
we are on the we said bird always zero and then we get rid of all the columns of that particular rule.
So Jake was needle less than him C++.
And here we are, going to print the raw code at Delphi and be followed by some space.
And once it is done, we can simply do lead.
OK, the let's build the gold and now let's call the function.
It's Brenda.
And let me show it to you.
I can say Brent Eddy, which has andrews and gold.
So then you're passing this eddy.
It is again possible evidence that means we are sending the address of the area.
We are not making a copy of that.
So this is again like a one be added.
This is also passed by reference.
Any changes that you make here would be reflected in the mean as well.
This is something that you should note.
The let's test of record dodge slash its two DNA basic, a three rows, four columns, and I'm going
to give the input to input either we can give one by one or we can give Roberto.
OK, so it doesn't matter, or we can give all the elements in a single room.
They need to give 12 elements, maybe only to last for eight zero zero zero one.
OK.
I think we.
Forgot to.
While the print method now should work fine.
Three rows, four columns.
Yes.
So we can see this is the eddy and we are actually able to see to the area.
The one thing I want to talk about is how these areas are actually stored inside the memory so we can
see the output begins.
He is in the form of a 2D array because we have given a new line corrected after every rule.
But what happens in the memory level, how they are stored, so is memory to the other dwindling?
So basically, there are two ways in which the memory can handle the storage of two DNA.
OK?
This is something that you don't need to worry about.
This is something that the underlying paper takes care of.
So there are two common notations.
One is known as ruminated form, and another is known as column major form.
And let us talk about what is the difference between these two forms.
So Ramita form basically so stored everything that is in one room that is stored together like this,
then the next row is kept adjacent to the first row or the next row is like this one.
This is the room we have actually triggers for that.
But if in our case, we have.
Area of Let's 100 cross under, but we're using that four columns in that case, the columns are lying
and we are just using this part of the memory in the next 100 columns are lying here and we are just
using this part of the memory and so on.
OK, so this is what the dummy bombers, if this addresses, let's say, one zero one, this is one
zero four.
This is one zero eight, this is one one 12.
And the next day address this will be nothing but one one six.
OK.
Because it is part of a linear remedies.
This address is going to be 120x and this is going to be 100 immolated.
This address will be nothing but 132.
So I hope you understood what Rumi did promise in some systems, depending upon the architecture, the
array might be stored in the form of a column ID as well, in which each column is stored in it all.
And then the next column is water just into each this one, then the next column and so on.
So, yeah, so this is how these are actually stored in the memory.
But this form is the most common and most computers are going to use that only did form.
So that's it.
That's all for this lecture on.
Thank you for watching.