I in this lecture, we're going to talk about a problem in which we have to put internet in a spiral
order.
So let's see what is the meaning of spiral print and then we can solve this problem.
So let's see this example.
It says right in a function that takes in and cross-boundary cross-community on print, all the elements
in a spiral or that we have to start from the top left corner.
And we have to go towards right and then proceed in a spiral pattern until every element is OK.
So for example, in this case, we'll go from here, then we will go down and then we'll go hit and
then we'll go hit.
Then we'll go here, then down and then hit.
If you look at this order, it is one two three four eight 12, 6th, 16, 15, 14, 13, nine five
six seven 11.
And we are actually following this or that.
OK.
So I hope the idea is clear what we need to do, and now we need to think, how do we do it or how to
do?
OK, so what is clear and how we can do it is something that we should figure that out.
Basically, what we can do is in one iteration, we can define one nitrogen as one complete boundary
reversal of daddy because a boundary means let's in one iteration, we complete this boundary.
Then in the next iteration, we complete the inner boundary.
OK.
Basically, we're going to look like this.
So basically, in this case, we can then do alterations.
We can print all the elements in this barrel or that maybe if is a bigger matrix, approximately what
what is happening is if it has, let's say, in columns and number of rows, then we would need and
why do.
Iterations, roughly approximately, OK.
So let us assume desert and grassland matrix, but it can be an awesome matrix as well, so we will
see what happens when we have varying number of laws and columns.
But let us see or try to figure it out how we can actually solve this problem.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to the north, I'm going to north down.
I'm going to take a few variables later.
There is a variable that denotes what is the starting role in the current iteration.
In the beginning, this would be my starting role.
OK, I can dig in little variable that will tell me, what is the column that I want to print in the
right?
So basically, I can take the ending column.
This could be an undeliverable that will be responsible for printing the last column, and we will not
print forward again because we have already printed.
Then we also need a variable to denote what is the ending row?
OK, so this will denote as a ningo, and then we will also take a variable that will denote the start
column.
OK.
So what is the idea?
The idea is first, you will print the starting role.
Starting from what index?
Starting from that column.
In the end column.
OK, this is what we will do.
In the same situation, we are also going to print the end column.
OK.
In order to print every element what we need, we need the raw number and we need the column numbers
of, he said.
We will keep that number fixed and we will iterate from start column at the end column.
OK, then for the end column, we can say we will iterate from start to.
Plus, one L, what is the ending?
OK, that's it, then we will see we will iterate on the end rule.
Starting from what we're starting from this point, this columnist and column minus one bill, what
they'll start column.
OK.
And we are going to read in this direction.
Then we said, Will I read on the stock column starting from where Andrew minus one?
Well, what a start problems one.
OK.
This is what we are going to do once we're done with these, these four loops, which are also part
of our outer loop.
OK, so in the outer look, we will have.
This we will also do repeatedly.
OK, so these are the inner loops, and we also will have our outlook as well.
It is very clear what we need to do in a loop.
And once these four steps are and what we need to do, we need to make these pointers point to the inertia
problems or the inertia problem would be nothing, but the start starter would be incremental by one.
So we will have start problems plus.
The end goal would be detrimental by one, so we will have an cola minus minus.
Then we can have Andrew decremental by one Andrew.
Minus minus.
And this column will be incremented by one.
It will come here, so we will have that column.
OK, so this is what we are going to do.
So I hope.
On a high level, the logic is clear.
And now we're going to implement this logic in the form of gold, and we will also see what other conditions
we need to write.
While discussing the gold?
OK, so let us jump in Dover gold fail.
And we are going to write some go ahead now.
So let's say we have a function wide friend and we are getting this to degree.
Maybe we can have a be at as well.
We are getting the number of those and we're getting the number of columns where they said we will take
four variables.
So these four variables are start rule that essentially zero the Andrew Card is nothing but the number
of columns minus one.
The.
But the number of those minus one.
And we are going to have the start column that is zero.
And we're going to have an column that is a number of columns minus one.
OK.
What we're going to do, we are going to put out a look.
That will reverse.
Everybody.
Using foreign loops.
So while certain conditions, we will look at those conditions a little later on.
But let us ride the inner cold.
So inside this first step is to traverse the starter.
We discussed the Star Trek will go from.
Let me close to start column, and it will go till the end column.
And we will do column plus plus, though here we can write.
The old adage of Dietro and the columnist ending that always fixed the column is changing, that's what
we do.
And this completes the printing of.
Yeah, so this this part, we will feel a little later on.
And then what we can do, we can say, let us bring.
This column.
OK, so what we are done, we have printed this rule from here to here.
Now we want to print this column, which we should start from start row plus one bill, Andrew.
OK, so surplus one billion.
And this column is and column, so we need to fix the column so we can see who is going to change.
The Ford and Raicaldo starter last one row less than equal to Andrew Ajio plus plus and began to see
out Eddie off.
Rule and end column, so and columnist fixed it, always changing, and we are done.
Now we need to print this part of the city.
We are going to start from Angola minus one and we are going to go to start to start column.
OK.
This is what we are going to do and we will change.
So so the column will change.
So we are going to print the Andrew Bell and heroic Aldo Sartre study and column minus one.
And.
No, sorry, we are bringing the end Russo column is going to change, so for column called.
And column minus one and column is greater than equal to start column.
We are going to do column minus minus.
And we can see the old adage of.
Andrew and the column.
That's it, and then we are going to print this part of the.
So this part is going from here to here.
Let's see.
So it is the starting column that will start from Roll Call to Andrew minus one and roll greater than
equal to start row last one American zero minus one.
So here we can see sealed area off the door and the start column.
That's it.
And now we need to update these variables so that they point to the inert Biden.
So update the variables to point to energy, Biden.
Everything will change where value of one.
So we need to.
Increment the starter, we need to decrement the Andrew, we need to increment the start column and
we need to decrement the end goal right now.
The code may say complete, but it is not complete yet.
We are left with two things.
One is this condition.
So when should we stop?
OK.
This is an important question.
When should we stop?
So we should stop when these variables are gone.
Let's say we have five number of columns.
OK, let's see.
And now what will happen is after two alterations in the secondary iteration, the column star column,
is it the end column?
Is it?
And after the desired direction is done due to the update condition that we have written it, what is
going to happen?
It is going to happen.
Both of both Start Coleman and Column will point to this one.
Both of them, that column and the column will point it if they write a condition like this.
If that column is less then and column, then this column will never get printed.
OK.
What if I write this condition?
If that column is less than equal one column, then this column may get printed twice way once it may
get printed while going from top to bottom in this direction, and another name would make it printed
in this direction.
OK, so it may get repeated as well.
So in both cases, there is a certain problem which needs to be fixed, but we definitely want to print
this column.
OK?
And but the problem is what we can do is to avoid double printing.
So first time it is going to print in this direction.
So we have when we are doing from top to bottom.
This will definitely get printed.
But what we can do is here, we can put a check that if we don't print this column again, then we are
going from bottom to top.
OK.
So for this, what we can do, we can actually put a brake statement.
We can check if that column.
Is equal to and column.
Then we can break this loop.
This will actually avoid duplicate printing of elements, avoid duplicate printing of elements.
The same thing is valid for roads as well.
So.
It may happen that the number of rows is less than the number of columns, OK, so what we want is,
let's say we have.
Rigorous five metrics.
We have a large number of rules, but we have less number of rules, but we have more number of columns
in this case, the columns will convert late, the rules will convert early.
OK?
We also need to stop if you have finished either the number of rows or the number of columns.
If one of them is finished, then we should stop printing.
So you print this rule, then you print digital, then would start and end broken to hit.
And we do not want duplicate printing at this particular rule.
OK, so same thing will happen for the rule as well.
So while you have the number of rules and you have the number of columns only, then you should print
elements.
So we would modify this condition.
While this third column is less than equal to and column, and this title is less than equal to Andrew.
Only then we should bring the number of elements because if and are different, then the value of it
is smaller.
That is, the number of rows.
If it is smaller, then it will convert first.
If the number of columns is smaller, then it will convert first.
So we should also put an addition here if DIETRO becomes equal to Andrew.
Then we don't want duplicate printing.
We should break this loop.
OK.
And I think we are done now and we can now test our code.
So this was a corner case, and it was a little tricky, I guess.
But if you think if you try to visualize what is happening is, let's say you have a large number of
your less number of rows where you have more number of columns than you will bring this row.
This column, this through this through this row and both.
Will come in this room.
So one will try to print like this and other will try to print like this, where the elements are saying
they will get repeated, OK, if we don't put this particular condition.
So this this is going to happen when the value of photos is art or the number of columns is.
So we will also try to run it for our number of rows and columns as well.
But yeah, so.
Let's let's run this code, so we have dot dot slash spiral print.
OK, we forgot to call the function spiral print.
OK, this is Brent only.
So we can see a print error and we give.
Water and food and.
OK, we should also give us base.
Between every element.
So that it looks a little nice and we can verify our output as well.
So we are getting one two three four five six seven eight nine, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16.
If you go through this one two three four five six seven eight nine 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15 16.
That window record is working perfectly fine, and I hope you really understood this logic.
And that's all for this lecture.