Everyone in this lecture, we're going to discuss a problem in which we had given it already and this
to is sorted along the rows, and it is also sorted along the columns.
And what we want is we want to search for an element.
That is given, OK, so basically, we want to do some kind of searching on this building matrix.
So let's see this example and we have this tool, the matrix.
And let's say someone is maybe you want to search for an element 33.
Maybe you want to search for an element.
Twenty nine, how you are going to do it.
So we are going to discuss multiple approaches.
The first approach is a brute force approach in which we can simply iterate over the entirety robledo
or column by column and begin to look.
This is where this particular element is president, because that is going to take an interim name.
So we are going to traverse the entire matrix.
So this is nothing but a linear search on it already, and this will be a brute force technique that
Ken would be.
Daniel, do something of this sorted property.
We are not using this information that is sorted.
Can we think of something using sorting?
So let's see.
We had learned that we can use binary search on coordinates.
OK, so what we can do is we can say, OK, why not do binary search on each little on each row what
we can do?
We can say, OK, we can do a binary search.
OK, so maybe we do binary searching that is going to take log of him time.
And we have a number of rows.
We can do binary search on all the rows.
And in the worst case, it is going to take all that off and then do log of empty OK because binary
search takes logarithmic time complexity.
So this is another way.
But can we still do something better?
There is still some information that is present in this ocean, and we are not using it to get this
binary.
That would still work if the edit was not column by sorted.
OK, because we are not using this information, the error is all sorted across the columns.
OK.
So every problem you have to carefully analyze what information is given on how you can exploit it.
In the first method, we did not use this information that is sorted.
But when we use, the error is sorted.
We came up with a binary search idea.
But in this binary, totally just assuming that rows are sorted on the column that also started.
So can we think of something using which we can still reduce the complexity of the search?
OK?
So maybe what we can do, maybe I'll say, let me start with this element then, and I want to find
an element 33 in which direction should I go?
And that is not very clear, because if you go right?
OK, so you want to move towards a bigger element are the 33 from 10, if you go right, the date is
increasing.
If you go down there, it is.
Increasingly it is very confusing.
We cannot start from this point, OK?
But if you look at this point or this gardener, one of these, any one of these you can pick.
If you look at this point and you know, we are at 40 and we want to look for an element that is 33.
That means 33 is going to be smaller than 40.
OK.
So what we can do is we can move in this direction from this if you move left.
The data is going to decrease if you move down.
The data is going to increase in which direction should be moved.
We should move left because we want to find it an element 33.
Now we're at 30 and we want to find an element 33.
If you go one step left that it is going to decrease, so you will go one step down.
OK.
So at 34, you will see where should I go now?
You should go left because 33 is smaller than 35.
So you go ahead at 25, you want to go to 33, so you should go down.
So you come here at 29, you again want to increase your value so you will go down and you will end
up at 33.
So this was the key element.
And now we're able to figure it out in just a traversal like this.
OK.
So what is the worst case for this?
So we we can say in the worst case, we are traversing one row and one column, OK, so that means from
a quadratic complexity, we have reduced our complexity to linear.
We can solve this problem in order often.
And since this forms a kind of a staircase, but this algorithm is also known as staircase search.
OK.
I hope this idea of staircase search is clear on what they want.
As you try to implement this idea in your code and in the next lecture, I will show you the solution.