I so let us discuss the implementation of staircase search.
And let's begin with the coding part.
What I need is I need to write a method that returns the indices of the given element like in there,
done maybe a bit of intent.
The bed is a very kind of fertilizer that can store two entities.
So we are going to return up it from a function, our staircase search, and we are getting the matrix
that is at a.
And we are getting the number of those and we are getting the number of columns and we are getting the
key element.
So what we can do, we can assume that.
The smallest element in the area would be this one, and the largest element would be this one.
If your output is not lying in this range, then we can say we can return a bit of minus one and minus
one, OK?
This case we can handle later on later, if the element is not present, return a bit of minus one and
minus one.
So maybe we can say if your key element is less than this one element that is added of a zero zero.
The key element is greater than the largest that is at the off and minus one and minus one.
In that case, you went in little diner minus one and minus one.
That means the element does not only.
Otherwise we can implement a staircase search.
So maybe I can take a call to zero.
I'm cold and minus one, so that means we are starting from this element that this is so this should
be.
And minus one.
OK.
We are starting from this element.
And what we're going to begin to while is less than.
And and there is greater than equal to zero.
Basically, your surge is going to start from here.
In the worst case, your surge should not go beyond this boundary, OK, so we should not cross this
at all.
And we should not cross this column.
So that's why we're saying it is less than an OK.
Because this is the truth, and this does not we should not go beyond this point because we are coming,
we are going backwards and downwards to downward limiters and and the backward limit is minus one.
We should not cross zero and we should not cross and minus one that that is what is the meaning.
So now I think if at the current index, I have that particular element, if my divided equals to my
key, then I can jump on the bed.
I got my g.
Otherwise I can see as if of.
Is greater than my key.
That means we need to move one column backward, so we are going to do a minus minus.
Otherwise, we are going to do.
Increment the A-plus, plus, that's it.
And.
We should be done, OK.
If we somehow had hit that, that means again, the element is not present and we can return minus one
and minus one.
Now, let us try to underscore.
Maybe I can say, although I maybe I to bed of internet coordinates equals double staircase search.
I give it, I give the end and maybe later is 33.
But this matrix is nothing but the ad itself.
Yes.
So.
Let us run the good and see the output has been.
One last step is we need to bring these coordinates, so a bed is a special kind of a structure which
has two attributes.
One is known as forest and that is known as second.
I want to bring coordinates, start first and coordinates start second and followed by end.
So I want to see the output for, let's say, 33.
Then let's run this code and we can to we're getting three comma one.
Let's build it once and we're getting three comma one.
That means zero one two three.
Third row on the first column that is working perfectly fine.
Maybe I want to search for, let's say, 27.
Let's see the output.
Zero, get second row.
And as you read column there, you can see how easy it is.
So this is the staircase search algorithm, and I hope it is clear to you.
That's it.