I in this lecture, we will talk about variables.
Let's see what variables are so variables as you know, they are the buckets that can hold data.
And now this data can have different types, so the buckets will also have different right to.
Some buckets may require a larger space.
Some buckets made it quite a lesser space.
So us because I love this concept.
But before that, let's talk a little bit more about the variables, OK?
So when you're creating a variable, you give a name to that particular ribbon.
So a name is just a label or a memory location.
So, for example, you create a bucket called monks and you say, OK, so this creates a bucket.
And when you're creating this bucket, you also need to define what kind of data this bucket can hold.
So we will define or get this bucket can hold in indeed the type of data.
So this is how you create a video, but then you also have some value that you can put inside that bucket.
Maybe you want to store wind inside this bucket.
So you will see OK, marks equals 220.
Creating the bucket is one thing holding balloons and the bucket is another thing.
OK.
And third, third content storage.
Where are these variables stored?
They are stored in the part of memory that we call it azra that's stored in the random access memory,
which is again a hardware unit on your system.
The first thing is declaration announcing a variable at the beginning of the program.
So here we're announcing that within this program, we would be using a bucket whose name is MOCS.
So this thing is known as declarations, and we have declared a variable and we have told the compiler,
you reserve some memory for a bucket called marks.
And when you're creating variables, you also need to define certain rules or certain rules that define
you have to name the variables according to those rules.
OK, so those rules?
We will see what those rules are.
And last but not the listing assignment.
So giving variable a value to this statement that we have written here, we are putting some value inside
the variables bucket.
So this is known as assignment.
OK, this equal was known as assignment operator.
So this is how you put something into the bucket or you assign some value to that particular bucket.
Now let us discuss the various rules that you can follow.
You will have to follow while naming the variables before naming a variable.
We can use an uppercase or a lowercase letter, or we can use digits from one to nine.
But the first character must be an underscore or a letter, or you cannot have a variable which starts
from a number.
For example, this one, this is a invalid variable name because it starts from a number on C++ is a
strongly typed language.
What does it mean?
It basically means with every language or with every variable.
You need to define the type of that particular look so it cannot figure out automatically.
You have to define what kind of market it is to every variable needs to be declared before using it.
So you create a variable simple interest, student age, flawed student percentile and so on.
And so every variable is declared and every variable is declared using a data type.
And very soon we'll discuss about the rapes as well, right?
So that's all what you need to know about variables.
And yes, there is one more thing that initialization when you just declare the variables and you don't
store it anyway inside that particular area.
So you simply say, I'm declaring a variable B at this point.
This B is going to store garbage.
So what is garbage?
By default, the memory is going to have some random collection of bits.
And this can can be can, can be any random number.
So we call this any random number as garbage.
So by default, the variables, if they're not initialized, if they're not assigned any value, they
will contain garbage.
We can also assign a specific value from the moment when the variable is created.
So this is known as initialization of the variable, for example, this at this point, we are declaring
the variable and at the same time, we are assigning it some value.
So doing this declaration plus assignment at the same time, it is also known as initialization of the
variable because we are defining what this variable is going to hold initially.
This is known as initialization of the variable.
So I hope you have understood these concepts related to the variables, and in the next lecture, we'll
talk about the rapes.