Everyone's in this lecture, we're going to talk about the storage of collectors, OK, so these are
some of the possible connectors that you can have in your C++ program, and the way you can create a
character is defined, not gather today and create a bucket that is going to store the character or
give, for example, akin to got some bucket.
And this bucket is going to store the later the characters.
They are defined in single codes.
And what you need to know is the size of the character is one bite, right?
That means a bit.
But let us try to understand how this character is actually stored inside the memory.
It's not like that.
You are actually storing it inside a bucket.
No, it's not the all characters.
They are mobbed with integers.
OK.
Three-Word Table, which is known as as their table.
So it's international standard that defines a mapping between each character and its numeric value.
For example, the capital is denoted using the value 65.
The Capital B is nothing but 66.
ABDEL-ATI is nothing but 67 and so on.
Similarly, the small is denoted using 97 small ways, using 98 and so on.
OK.
So talking in total, look at the set of characters.
OK, how many numbers we will need?
The total debt of this.
Is less than equal to 255.
That means if we have the numbers from zero to 255, that is more than enough to represent all the unique
characters that we can have inside the C++ program.
OK.
So.
So what what does it mean?
So we need to represent 255 unique combinations, zero to 255, that means we need to represent 256
unique combinations, OK?
And how many boots would be required to store these many combinations?
Of course, if we have eight bit bucket, we can make 256 combinations.
That is, to raise the debilitate.
We can have 256 combinations and these combinations will represent different characters, OK?
And that is why the characters are going to take one bite of memory because each character is going
to be mapped with their own budget that indeed there is going to get stored inside the memory.
And when we are going to read that number, how do we know whether it is a number or is it connected
to it will be known through this data type.
OK, so if I say see out this bucket.
I will see the answer, but if I took put the contents of this bucket into some endangered bucket,
OK, let's say my bucket and this is equal to the bucket.
And if I see out my bucket what I'm going to get, I'm going to get the integer value.
Let me show you.
Let me show you the output here.
If I now.
Bill, that's good.
And if I try to run it, you can see the correct that is.
But if I try to put this insider in the bucket, it's only going to copy the integer right?
Both the buckets, this is bucket and this is my bucket.
This is of the type God, this is of the type, and this is starting 65mm and I'm doing put this number
here.
It is a whopping 65.
But when I'm saying will get Brent this bucket or the old this bucket?
So it is actually showing the output as a because the database got the day-to-day was telling this CO2
statement, OK, isn't entered as a God.
You don't bring the integer value of it.
What do you print what this character represent?
So this represents.
OK.
Similarly, here, the data they put into that is where we see the output as.
That is how the characters are stored.
And I hope you got an idea.
And you also get to know that there are maximum 256 unique combination of characters that we will need
and that can be represented using eight bit bucket and hence the character takes one bite of memory,
at least in C++.
OK.
In other languages like Java, Java, the set of characters, the support Unicode characters with which
is it also supports different characters like the characters from other languages in Java.
OK?
So you can use the Hindi letters as well so you can create strings using the in the letters or the rupee
symbol or rational position in Java.
The character actually takes two bytes.
OK.
It means it has 16 bit.
So again, it's a language specific thing.
In C++, we have a smaller set of characters and that is for that aid, which are sufficient enough.
So that's all for this video on.
Thank you.