Hello, everyone.
And now we are going to see the storage of the bullion there today because we have seen in the world
God.
And this time we are going to see the storage of bullion, right?
So the thing with bullying is you can represent true or false, which would ideally require only one,
but OK.
But but that being said, the actual storage is not one bit, it is actually one bite.
OK.
That means if you're studying something like true, true is being stored, something like this.
Zero zero zero zero zero zero one two one two three four five six seven eight.
So you're using it, but the stored this value true, and we're talking about false.
It would be stored as lots of euros, OK?
Now you may ask why why the compiler is doing this, why it is allocating one by one byte is actually
the minimum unit.
In which you can allocate memory to it as the minimum unit, or it is a minimum size of the bucket that
can be allocated.
So that is why even though the Boolean requires one bit, the compiler allocates the minimum bucket
size that is one, right?
OK?
But examples of what you want to buy bananas will get.
Maybe you can buy four bananas.
Maybe you can buy eight bananas, but somehow you just want to buy 8.1 bananas.
You can and buy two 'cause you have to buy at least one bananas.
So the minimum unit of this memory allocation happens to be one bite, and that is the reason the bullion
does take one bite of memory.
Talking about the code, we have seen that this Boolean.
It takes one bite, and I will just tell you one more thing about the billions.
If you store something like this, let's say boolean some value.
And I put this as a non-zero value.
The non-zero value in C++ is rated as true.
OK.
So it is not going to store five, maybe let's see what it is going to store when we see out some value.
This should be treated as true.
And if I underscored.
Well, guess what, you can see this value is being stored as one only that means any non-zero value
is being treated as true by the C++ compiler.
OK, this is how it is getting stored.
It is getting stored as one only.
So this value this one.
This is how the truest or it.
And similarly, you can see what files it is stored as 0nly.
That's all for this video.
Thank you.