Everyone, so in this lecture, we are going to talk about consent to consent, as the name suggests.
They are the values in programming which cannot be modified once they are defined.
That means they are read only values.
They cannot be changed.
So there are two basic ways of creating consent.
One is using a preprocessor directive, which does create something which is known as a symbolic constant
OK.
And using a guns reward, this actually creates buckets in the memory, which are read only I took it.
So we'll talk about it always and we'll show you the demo as well.
We'll get these buckets are read only.
That means they can be created and initialized only once.
So what example Gonzales float by?
So you can use Gonski with a flawed guide on any other day today?
That means that particular bucket is read only.
We're not going to upgrade the value.
So if you try to upgrade the value of that bucket, you're going to get an error.
OK.
And.
Another thing is you cannot create a book that is concerned and later you're going to say no.
So this is not a valid operation that means you're forced to create a consent without defining the value.
Initialization is must for consent only then it will get some value in it, OK?
And another way is using a preprocessor directive.
So I will tell you the difference between the two types of constants in the code demo.
So maybe let me go to this code and going to find something like how you define.
And Isaac, my name is ready, or maybe I defined something like religious faith.
OK.
This is actually.
This is also known as a macros, we have created a macro.
So what does it means if you do something like out radius in the radius?
OK, so this is just by replacing this text with five, it is not storing five in the moment, it is
basically doing a calculation.
In this line, when gold is going to get executed, it is going to replace the value of already with
the fight.
So five is actually a replacement text.
It is not a bucket in the memory.
It's a replacement text for the word.
OK.
That is also one way of creating Ogun state, and this type of consent is known as a macro.
The other way of creating a consent is using a Gonski.
Maybe you define launched by Gonski, flawed by.
OK, so you have the data type, you have the variable name, and then you look at this should be three
point one four.
And this value of BI will not change.
If you do, bike was two by plus one, you're going to get an error.
OK, so you're going to cannot assign a variable by with a new value because it is of the type concept.
So this is a invalid operation, so you cannot do this operation on a constant value.
And what are you going to do?
You can use this constraint in some explanation you can see out.
Not yet, but we can do it see out by into radius and do radius.
Maybe something like this.
So if I run this code, I will show you the output as well, right?
Now you you can see that this is actually OK, we should also give a new line here.
And the list for new line.
So now you get audited and audit.
We are multiplying the cent and we are getting 25.
And this is defined using a macro.
And here we have used what we have defined by which is a consent, which is a read-only.
Consent created in the memory you get to by is actually a bucket.
It's it's a variable.
It's a constant variable.
Whereas this oddity is just a macro and where it supplies the replacement text when the program is being
getting compiled, this is similar to writing by into five into five look at it is not a book it.
Wherever buys a bucket to buy is a read only book it will give when I generally mean ActionScript.
It refers to this country to get drivers to the Gonski world.
I don't use macros that frequently.
I use one cent more frequently.
Macros are helpful when you want to define some shortcut, maybe you want to define that a little.
The meaning of a well means the keyword long.
Long.
Maybe I don't want to write long, long to create a bucket.
I want to write a little so I can say l l some big number and that is equal to one two three four five.
So what it is going to do, it is going to replace L-l with with the replacement text that is long long.
What if you have values which are constant?
I would recommend you to go with the Gonski, which I hope that clarifies the difference between the
two things.
And that's all for this video.