Hello runs in this lecture, we're going to talk about basically tribes in C++.
These basic data types, they're also known as primitives, that me, that means that the most similar
data types and these data types cannot be broken down further.
OK.
The first step is is a Boolean, so it is denoted using the keyword model, right?
And suppose you want to create something that stores only true or false.
Maybe is five greater than three.
You just want to store the result of this expression.
Yes.
Five is greater than three.
So you want to store this as true.
So it is not a string, it is not a number.
OK, it's a special day today which we call quality as a Boolean, and it does denoted using.
It is written using the bool, keyword or GIF.
So maybe you going to bowl, maybe some, some Boolean X and that is equal to true.
OK, or you can also say that some bullying like that is equal to false.
OK?
Or you can also put expiration later.
Some bullying did.
And maybe you can call the function is whether any is in this function might return, whether the weather
is rainy or not to get so it does something and then return to value true or false.
OK, so the return type of dysfunction should be brought forward, but maybe you're going to boil some
W. That is equal to five greater than three.
This is this is a exploration.
This is an exploration that is that will evaluate to true W, Wells told the value right.
It's a Boolean as one of the basic right, and maybe I can show you in the gold as well.
But before that, let us try to go through all of these data types one by one.
The next data type is as a character, many are dying.
You might require to store a single letter.
OK, so for that, you will use the gladiator type.
So, for example, maybe you just want to store a value in a single.
OK, so you will say, OK, I'm creating a bucket, which is of the type God and you give give some
name to this bucket.
Maybe you're going to later.
And what is the letter?
The letter is nothing, but a letter is a bucket that is capable of holding nothing.
The letter that's in the letter is OK.
It cannot store multiple letters and single letters in C++.
They are written in single codes.
OK.
They are written in single words.
There can be others in the letters as well.
Maybe you want to store a dollar, or maybe you want to store a.
Rupee symbol.
OK.
I mean, we want to store L.
Maybe you want to store Adelaide.
So all of these odd examples of characters, OK?
And in C++, the character work, it takes one bite of memory every railway, and Willian also takes
one bite of storage.
We'll talk about why this storage is this much.
OK, but before that, we'll talk about what all other data types that we will see very frequently.
So we have integer integers.
You have seen that, OK, I want to store X, which is led to one zero eight two four.
It's a number.
OK.
And this will be stored inside a bucket.
One zero eight two four.
And this bucket is of the type integer, right?
We also have floating point to floating point are the numbers which which have some, but after that
as when, for example, the number three point one four, which is the approximate value of the bay.
So maybe you can say I have by and it is of the type float.
It has been restored 3.1 for.
The floating point numbers.
They have less precision.
And if you want more precision, OK, that means you have a lot of digits after the decimal.
Then you use a type called double, so double has a higher precision than afloat.
OK.
So double means double floating point.
It has double precision.
We'll talk about how precise these numbers can be, but maybe double has a better precision.
You want this door?
Maybe three point one four two eight six nine.
The double would be would be a better choice in that case.
OK, it has.
It can accommodate more number of digits in the decimal place.
OK, so you have and float double and maybe some by double, OK, and maybe some bigger value off by
more.
It will actually give you more precision in calculations where precision matters a lot.
Go double.
Otherwise, float is also fine for most of your calculations.
OK?
So these are for you right now, and we will see in our code as well, right?
And maybe I can give you a quick demo.
So let's see the demo, so for example, I want to start with a Boolean so I can see Boolean X equals
two true.
Or maybe I go into Boolean is whether any is a variable and it tells, OK, this is not really so it
is false.
And maybe I can print what is X, followed by Endless Andela's for going to the next line.
OK?
I don't want that the output to appear in the same line.
And then I can say is whether any and that we are going to build this code and we are going to run it.
Let me run this not like a demo and we're getting one n0.
So basically, when you're going to print a Boolean, it will be printed as one or zero.
So it is true, it is printed as one and it is false.
So it is printed as little while.
It happens because in the memory, the Boolean, they're being stored in the form of words.
And this is how true is represented and this is how the fold is represented.
OK.
So they are stored as eight bit integers and the decimal equivalent of this number is going to be one.
And for this number, it is zero.
So that is an example of a Boolean.
It's a we have X, which is five one two or if I went to it.
And so this is an example of in we are flawed, some number by which is three point one four two or
double by which is three point one four two seven eight nine nine eight seven.
That's it.
And let me store the same number here as well.
And maybe I can say by Underscore D, so I can see out what is the value of pay and tell me what is
the value of buy that is double?
OK, we we cannot create hexagons, and when I'm building the code, I'm getting the error, the definition
of X X, we have declared at least maybe I can make it Y.
And now I can run my good.
And I can say the old way as well.
So let's run this.
And now you can see that you're not getting the exact.
Precision and gives off flawed and double OK.
To know this, this is happening because by default, the C++ brain statement is only printing up to
four places, OK?
So you might want this to show up up to maybe up to 10 places.
OK, and you also want to show this up to 10 places.
It is actually easier to get.
So right now we're storing more places, but we are printing only four places, right?
The story is it is happening for higher precision, but the printing is happening only for fortresses.
If you want to show a lot of places like I want to show you the exact number in the memory, let's say
currently there are eight eight numbers after the decimal point.
Maybe I can call a function, which is present in the header file called I up.
The function is known as set precision.
OK.
So if I use this said precision and I tell this the old statement, I want to bring this number up to
10 precisely 10 places.
So let's see if there is a difference now.
So we are doing it both for the floating number and we are also doing it for the double number as well.
And this is this number is exactly same what we have stored in both of them, right?
So that decision, right?
You know, we have I had this region right?
And now maybe I can run the good.
Now what you can do, you can see different, OK?
You can see the difference.
The floor does not able to store the exact number, whereas the exact number was.
Point nine, eight seven.
And the floating sporting a just an approximation, which is nine seven five two.
That means it is not able to store the exact digits that we had and the exact digits they're stored
by double digits.
That means double is more precise.
And another thing that we will see is that height is the box height is the size of the bucket.
The more number of bits that bucket can store and the higher the precision would be.
So flawed is actually 32 bits in most cases.
Again, most systems and double is 64 bits, which is eight bytes.
OK.
The double is going to take up more storage.
Double the storage as well.
But it is going to be more precise when it comes to storage.
OK, so that is what you wanted to discuss it on the last day today that we will take up is the gadget
today.
Maybe you want to say it got a little z letter equals to a look out and maybe get dollar equals two
dollars so we can talk this out.
What?
What is the letter?
And I will tell the old what is their dollar?
So let's build a road and see what output do we get?
So, yes, we are getting the letters and in our output, that is the concept of basic genotypes that
you will see very frequently while writing Gordon C++.
And that's all for this we do.