Everyone in the last lecture we saw.
There are different data types that we can use to create buckets, and these buckets are of different
sizes depending upon what type of data they are storing.
In this video, I'm going to look at what is the actual size of each bucket.
And for that, we are going to use inbuilt function in C++, which we call the size of the size of data
needed.
So I ask this function, tell me how big the bucket would be.
So it will tell me, OK, it's going to take four bytes.
Four bytes means 32 bits, basically on my system, this individual bucket will take 32 bit in the memory.
And that means 32 bit, 32 zeros and ones can be stored in a zero bucket in this particular in the bucket,
right?
Let me show you in the demo how we can use this size of method.
Either you create a Bucket X and then you give the name of the variable to the size of the function.
It will tell me, OK, the X is going to occupy four bytes, or you can also give the data type.
You can see how big the integer bucket would be if I created one.
It would be, again, four bytes.
So let me run this code and you can see the answer is four and four.
Similarly, we can do the same thing for other data types as well.
We can talk.
How big is the guy bucket?
So it is actually going to come to be one byte.
The bull market, it is all going to be won, right?
The float market.
Maybe it would be around for four bite and a double, but maybe it would be.
It bites.
So.
Let us see and try to underscore, right to build a God.
And I'm going to run it.
So you can see God is one who lives one loaded four and is it?
Now we are going to understand how increasing the size of the bucket affect how big data we can stored
in this particular bucket, or why one boat is sufficient enough to store the correct, but why one
vote is required to store the right to one by means Edwards.
OK, and this means 32 bits.
And this means 60 for Edwards.
That is why is it that your double can store a greater precision as compared to float suitability known
as double floating point number and float is a single floating point or double has a higher precision
than float because the bucket size of the ball is twice as big as compared to float.
So this is a double bucket.
And this is a fluid bucket.
OK?
The fluid bucket can store less because it can store more number of.
So let us try to understand the binary number system, and someday we will try to estimate what bucket
sizes recommended for each of these data types.
That's all for this video.
Thank you.