Everyone in this lecture we're going to talk about binary numbers is done.
The reason why we're going to understand this by new numbers is because it will help us to develop a
better understanding of how machines work at the very lowest level, OK?
And we have seen differently types as well.
So different data types are also stored as binary number inside the memory of the computer.
So on any source code that we have written, right?
So we would generally write the code in a programming language that can be C++, Java or Python.
Then that code goes through a application that we call as compiler or an interpreter.
And this is going to convert this into machine code in case of C++.
OK, the compiler generates a machine called this machine code is in the form of zeros and ones, right?
So this is what a binary number looks like and all the instructions that we write, they are converted
into binary instructions that the processor can execute and all the data that we have that is also converted
into binary data for storage.
So learning about that, this number will help us to develop a better understanding of how machines
work.
And yeah, so generally what we have until now, we have frequently worked with the decimal number system.
We, as humans write.
And.
So what what we have seen in decimal number system is that we have 10 unique, did it OK if I talk about
the decimal numbers, we have 10 unique digits from one to one zero two nine eight zero one two three
four five six seven, eight and nine.
So we have 10 unique digits and we say, OK, the base is also 10, right?
And what is the meaning of this dom base?
Let us take an example of a number.
Let's say our number is 234.
The meaning of base is that this number is multiplied.
It is generated by combining the powers of.
So by combining the powers of 10, Richard and Bob Zito and Bauer, one and then Bob.
So what happens?
Each each place will be multiplied with the power of 10 to get get the contribution of that place,
OK?
For example, I will multiply two with 10 squared and I will add three multiplied with 10 power, one
plus four multiplied with end poverty.
So this becomes equal to 200 plus 30 plus four.
And this is how the number 234 has been generated, OK?
With each place, we have a power that is attached to that particular place.
And this is what we generally work.
As with this number system we'll get right now, we are going to talk about binding numbers system.
So let us try to interpret a number in the binding base.
Let's say we have binary means two zeros and ones.
And now why only do two digits OK?
The reason is the computer hardware, as I discussed it, made up of small, small electrical cells.
OK, and they can store some judges if a cell is storing some charge.
We said this represents one.
And if it is not storing any geometries, it is representing the number to any data that we have to
stored inside the heart of it.
It must be converted into this form in the form of zeros and ones.
OK, so let's take an example of a number that is written in binary and we will try to interpret it.
Let's say one zero one zero one one later.
This is the number.
And we are storing this inside a certain cell in a set of cells.
It's a.
Now.
What this number is going to represent, so here the basis.
OK.
That means if you want to find out what this exact number is, you have to multiply the corresponding
bits.
With powers of trade, so does this this places do but zero to power one.
It was quicker to kill two powerful.
And two par five, OK.
Similarly, if there are more, but the higher powers of two will be used to what we will multiply to
power five with one, we will multiply zero of it to power, four will multiply one with two skill,
then two square into zero, then two power one and one, then the power zero into one.
So we are multiplying these two, these two, these two, and adding that by adding them up.
So this will actually give us up in digit.
This is going to be nothing but 32 plus eight plus two plus one, right?
So this number is actually the number 43.
That means if you understood the number 43 inside the memory of the computer, this is how it would
be stored, OK?
This is how it would be stored.
That is a brief introduction about the binding number system.
And in the next lecture, we will dive into more details.
And that's all for this video.