Everyone, so we have already seen how the binary number system works on in this video, we are going
to talk about how the integers are stored inside the memory, OK, so basically of it integers that
are.
The first thing that we need to know is that given and indeed it how it is converted into the binary,
or because we are going to discuss an algorithm that will help us to understand how to get the binary
representation of any number.
OK, so we have already seen how do we convert a number from a decimal representation from a binary
representation into its decimal representation?
OK.
So for example, this is in the binary and you wanted to get the.
Decimal equivalent of this number, so you generate powers of two.
So you said this is 2.0 to cover one two squared, two cube to perform and to qualify, and then you
multiply and add the terms.
OK, one quick way of looking at it is that you can also directly say that I will just add this power,
this power, this power and this power, because only these powers have corresponding words as one.
This is to power five 32.
This is eight.
This is to power one that is two.
And this is to facilitate this one.
OK, so this number is 42.
But now suppose you want to do the other way around.
You want to get the binary of the number 42, so you want to convert a number from decimal number system
to a binary.
So first, we will look at an algorithm that will help us to generate a binary or a number on CNN.
OK, so what we are going to?
We are going to divide this number repeatedly with the number two, and we are going to find out the
remainder.
When you divide 43, which do what you get.
You get 21.
And what is the remainder to the remainder is one, right?
So basically, I'm saying that went to 21 plus one is what 43 is right.
This is the remainder and this is what is the quotient.
I'm writing these two terms here, right?
And we will do it until the number.
And it doesn't become zero.
OK, so now do unto our 10 as 20 and the remainder as one right?
And we're going to divide 10s or two into five is 10.
The remainder is zero to is for.
And the remainder is one right into one is to the remainder of zero and two and to zero is zero.
And the remainder is one because we will stop when this number and it becomes zero.
Now what is the binary representation of this number?
Basically, if you look carefully, if you go from bottom to top.
And if you interpret these reminders right from bottom to top directions, that is one zero one zero
one one.
This these numbers represent the binary representation of the number 43, OK, so we have got this number,
which is nothing but 43.
OK.
This is the pen and paper method of getting the binary off.
Any possible integer?
OK, so this is one way that you can do it, so it is kind of a division method, you can see.
And we'll also talk about there any shortcut ways of doing it.
They can beat you one shortcut as well.
So maybe what you can do for smaller numbers, you can have powers of two lets.
Let's do par zero to power one square or cube 2.4 2.5 lets it or what you want.
You can write these powers as one, two, four, eight, 16 and right.
So I fill these.
These are better because we don't need to compute it.
I suppose someone says, give me the number 43.
OK, so how you're going to do it?
So you need to make 43 by combining the powers of.
So first of all, you will look at what is the largest power I can use.
Obviously, we can use the 32.
OK, then how much is left so you are tired or category two plus something makes the number 43?
Of course you are left with the.
The number 11, right, so you want to make you want to add 11.
So how do you get 11 to what is the largest power of do?
That is less than 11?
That is it.
OK.
And then what is left?
So you have added three is left to what is the largest power of two.
That is less than three.
So you take eight.
How much is left?
You have already reached to less than what one has left.
So you make this bet as one, the rest, everything would be zero.
This actually gives you the number 43.
OK.
Let us try out another example.
For example, you want to generate the number 29.
OK.
What you will do.
Which power you will choose.
So you will choose.
16.
OK.
You will choose eight.
OK, if you have reached one before, you will choose four.
OK, you have reached 28 and you will choose one.
You have reached 29.
This number represents 29.
OK, so that is another way of looking at how do we get the binary off any given?
I'm like, OK.
And what?
We will write the binaries of the numbers from one to 10.
And we will try to observe one button that would be helpful for us.
OK.
Maybe up to 15, we can write.
OK, so I want to write the binary often, so you can verify this is an adequate one.
What is it?
It was one zero.
What is three one one?
What is four one double zero?
What is five one zero one?
What is six one one zero?
What is seven oil ones?
What is it?
One triple zero.
What is nine one triple zero one?
OK, you're adding one to it.
What is then you're adding two two eight eight plus two, so you will add one zero one zero.
What is 11?
Riding one 210 hit what is 12?
You're adding four to it as well was made by combining eight plus four, so it will be one zero three
one one zero zero.
OK, what is 13?
Add one here.
What is 14?
So one one one zero?
What is 15?
All went right and what is 16?
So what 16.
You you need actually more than four, but you need five bits.
It would be one, followed by four zero three eight one two four eight six.
Yes.
What?
What is the pattern that you are looking at?
Basically, as the number is increasing, right?
As the number is increasing.
The requirement of boots is also increasing the requirement of boats.
Is also increasing, so if you need more more space, right, if you need to store a larger number,
it will required more, but it's basically the large numbers required.
Woodward's.
OK, now it is to think in terms of your program, what is going to happen to suppose you created a
bucket index and you stored the number in it?
OK.
And later on you thought, No, I want to make this say, seven hours, maybe seven to eight or seven.
We know it only requires three bits, but 72 might require more number of books.
OK.
But on the hardware level?
Right.
And if we are storing some data, except maybe we are storing X there, we are storing some way.
Right here we are storing Z.
If you were storing a little tribute and when we updated Overvalued 72, maybe we acquired six bits.
Let's see.
OK.
So we we need tribute.
But maybe now we require six bits.
So is it possible that?
We dynamically expandable storage.
The answer is, no, we cannot expand the storage because.
The memory might be occupied, right?
So we cannot do it.
So how do we handle this situation?
This is the reason that when the compiler allocates buckets for integers, these buckets have fixed
sizes.
OK?
These buckets are fixed.
Say this.
So by default, the size of it in most systems, this is going to be four bytes or bytes means 32 bits.
That means you are given a bucket that can hold up to 32 bits.
OK.
And if you're required.
Something larger than this, and there is a concept of a data type modified which gives you a bigger
bucket, which is of 64 bit, which is of 64 bit by default.
Indeed, it would be stored as a 32 bit numbers.
So even if you're storing two, it would be stored as zero zero zero one zero.
So there would be a lot of zeros followed by one and you.
This is how the number two is getting stored.
So that is why understanding the binary was little important to tell you that the larger is the indeed
it more say that it is going to take on the dog in more detail about this in the next lecture.