Everyone's in this lecture, we're going to talk about one important concept, which is known as data
type modifiers in C++.
We have something which is known as auditor type modify, and it allows us to expand or decrease the
capacity of the boxes or the buckets that we have been allocating for integers, OK, or for other data
types as well.
So some of the data does work.
So let me just tell you what example is the boys wanted to create an integer and by default it gives
me 32 bits.
OK?
It gives me a 32 bit bucket.
I suppose I wanted to create a larger integer, so we know that it will not draw a number which contains
more than that.
But there is another option to either modify it in front of it that we call as long long.
It gives you the biggest budget, which which will contain 64 bit sugar.
That means you can store a number up to 64 bit inside the bucket called long, long.
So this long long is a data type modified OK.
Or you can alter this shortened.
Maybe you you're working on a concept where you're storing some data that only requires age of the person
to be stored.
You know that to age must be in the range, let's say, zero to 120 years, OK?
Now what this will do, it will give you a smaller size bucket, OK, so what is the exact size we can
check on our machine?
So the way we can check it, we are going to go to our order.
And we are going to say, OK, let me create a shortened.
Maybe shot in.
Age.
And I can say, OK, give me the size of each.
How much memory you're going to allocate for this shortened.
So let us verify by running this code on terminal and.
We have built a gold as well, so dodge slash.
Size of demo.
So short, you're going to hear this taking two bites, that means it is allocating.
How much it is allocating estimates for this number?
Similarly, you can verify for long, long as well, right?
You can verify for long, long as well.
It may be long and so and long, long and let's.
What happened in this case?
Maybe I can give how much memory you allocate if I create a long and digit or if I create a long, long
integer.
OK, so let's run this code.
So bored and gaze of longing on long, long, it is giving me aid bytes of memory.
That means it is giving me 64 bit basically in this system, the longest seem as long long will.
And these things are basically your system dependent.
So that's why we are checking how much it is.
But the idea is that long would give you a memory that is greater than equal to the memory of the individual,
OK?
On short will give you a memory that is less than equal to the memory of integer bucket.
And by having a larger bucket, you can also increase the range of the largest number that can be stored
in that particular bucket.
So very soon we will talk about what is the largest and what is the smallest number that can be stored.
But before that, there are two more things that we would like to cover.
There is also a concept of a signed integer under unsigned integer.
OK?
What is the meaning of signed on unsigned to by default, all integers are trying to get if you write,
OK, I am talking about assigning digits.
That means that integer is capable of storing both the positive numbers and the negative numbers.
If you say X is plus five, it is going to store it.
If you don't know, my X is minus five, it is also going to store it because.
All integers, by default, they're capable of storing both the designed positive numbers and the negative
numbers, OK?
Now how does it differ?
OK, how does it differ?
The one one difference between the positive numbers and the negative numbers is that if you have a 32
bit bucket, OK, then the 31 bits they are used to store the magnitude of the number, let's say the
number is five.
OK, then the remaining bits that the first bit, which is also known as the most significant bit.
This is actually used as the sign read, OK, this is actually used as designed by the convention.
If the sign was zero, it denote a positive number.
But if this sign is one, it denotes a negative.
OK, if the sign is one, it is going to denote the negative number.
So that is the idea of a signed integer.
But if I talk about an unsigned integer, OK, so what happens in an integer?
All 32 bits are used to store the magnitude of the number.
It only stores the numbers, which are greater than equal to zero.
What example if you want to store a roll number of a person?
OK, you might use an unsigned integer, do you using A. There is also fine, but rule numbers cannot
be negatives.
Are I just created an unsigned integer bucket?
OK.
But for most use cases writing the regular rate, it is going to work fine.
And it is only very corner cases where you might require to work with an unsigned integer.
OK?
But for all your programming, you can work with the regular integers as to let me just tell you the
difference between the signed integer and unsigned integer so you can have signed end.
Or in what are seen.
OK.
And if you want to go get no, I don't want the first bit to denote the magnitude of the number or not,
the sign of the number, then all 32 little bits will be used to denote the magnitude of the number,
OK?
That means if you have one hit or something, something something like this, then this number is going
to.
This one is going to contribute to raise to the bar 31 in the answer, OK, but hit the first bit as
a result for the sign.
If it is one, then you have some numbers, then this does not contribute to raise to the bar 31 dedans
that it contributes a negative sign.
It means it is a negative number.
OK, and if the first bit of zero, then it means it is a positive number.
OK, so this number has the first zero.
It means that as a positive numbers, it represents less fate.
And what does it represent?
We will discuss very, very shortly, but we will also talk about the storage of negative numbers,
how the negative numbers are stored.
It is unsigned integer, OK.
You can also add two more modifiers you can unsigned, long, OK, unsigned long.
And what it means Create a bucket of size 64 bits.
And in this book, the first bit does not represent the sign.
It also represents a power of two that isn't meaning of one's own logic.
That means you can store a bigger number inside this bunker.
OK.
And we'll discuss what is the range of these numbers, how big the number can be.
And yeah, very soon in the next lecture that was all about this video you can also use.
Along with other data types like Double, you can say I want along.
OK, so I'll show you the examples in the coming lectures.
That's all for this video.
Thank you.