Everyone's in this lecture, we're going to talk about the storage of negative numbers, OK, well now
what we have discussed was how the positive numbers are stored.
And we also discussed that integers by default, they are signed on signed integers.
The first bit represent the sign of the number OK.
If there is a 32 bit bucket that is divided into two parts, the first bit is used for the sign and
the remaining 31 bits.
They are used for the magnitude raid.
This is what we have already discussed it.
But if I talk about negative numbers, there is a special.
Convention that is used to store the negative numbers, OK.
And it is stored in the form, which is known as Dos Complement Foam.
I'm going to tell you the reason for it.
OK.
Why they're not stored directly.
We've overridden a number like a lot of zeros and followed by one zero one.
So undoubtedly this number is five.
But when it is stored in dos complement foam, it is not exactly fake.
It is something else, right?
And we have the sign, but one note that this number is a negative number.
OK.
So you can interpret this number as minus five.
But if it is stored in those compliment form, then it is not minus five.
It is something.
So let me tell you that, how do we interpret, but how do we convert a number introduced complement
form and why this one is needed?
OK, now let's talk about an operation on numbers like an addiction.
For example, you are doing, let's say, five plus three.
This will definitely reduce the output rate in order to simulate this operation.
You need additional hardware, right?
So there must be hardware for doing addition.
And that's as good as known as the circle of elders.
So this is built inside your processor.
But now suppose I want to do five minus three.
And this should produce two.
That means doing the subtraction would also need additional half of it.
That is special circuit that specializes in doing subtractions.
Now, the people who designed this hardware, they.
I saw some challenges with building this attracted.
One is they will need additional hardware.
Apart from the added to do the subtraction.
So what that orders instead of doing this attraction will not do the subtraction.
We will only the coalition will say, OK, we are adding minus three to five.
And this should reduce the rhetoric to.
This should produce the result, you may ask how this is possible, this is possible when there's no
ministry.
This is stored in those complement form.
If you are storing something and don't complement foam, you will not need to do subtraction.
You can just do addition and that will behave as a subtraction voter if you're adding you're adding
a negative number to do some of that number.
OK, so that is where this does complement farmers help.
So that means inside the memory, the actual bits, they are going to represent those complement form.
If the first bit S1, OK, and this is true for those assigned integers only OK, because there is no
concept of negative numbers in case of an Iranian leaders refer to the integer or assigning digit the
but one remaining which they are going to be stored in to compliment form.
Now, how do we get that huge compliment form off of any number, OK?
There are two steps you need to perform.
The first is suppose you are given a number, let's say you want to generate minus five.
OK.
And let us assume that it is stored in our forward memory, though it would be attached to a good memory.
And maybe you can take it as a bit memory.
So how is the number five stored?
OK?
This is how the number plus five would be stored.
What do you need to?
You need to invert all the bits of any number.
So if you want to suppose you have a number X and you want to generate the number minus X?
OK.
Do you want to generate the lowest compliment of minus X, so what it means you will invert?
All the bits of X.
OK.
And you will add one to it.
I won't do it.
So this is going to be a binary edition.
We have the number plus five and we want to generate the number minus five from last week.
So we have written the binary representation of plus five, which for now it's eight, but indeed it
just to simplify our additions, right?
So we will flip all the bits so it becomes one one one one one.
And zero one zero eight.
And now we are saying we want to add a one to it.
So let me add one here.
What this number is, it is a zero plus one one one zero one one one one.
We have five one zero and one.
And this number?
Is the way the minus five is being stored, so we have performed these two steps four step in all bits
of X and add one to it, so we have inverted all bits of five and added one to it.
So this gives me the number minus five.
Now you may ask.
Show me a demo of doing a subtraction.
OK, so let us try to subtract five minus five, so we know that this should produce an output of zero.
What we will add five with minus five.
OK.
And this should produce a zero.
But let's see.
What does it produce?
So what is five survivors this number?
So I'm going to write it here.
We have lots of zeros.
Followed by one zero one, what is minus five?
We have one one one one one zero one and one, right?
And now we are going to add it.
So before doing the addition, let me also tell you about the rules of Binary Edition.
OK, how the binary audition happens.
OK, now, if I add zero plus one to that is one one plus zero.
That is also one.
If I have zero zero, that is zero.
If I have one plus one, one plus one is two.
And how do you rate two in binary united?
Like this one?
OK.
That means here we are.
When we're adding one plus one, it is going to produce two.
We are going to put a zero hit and one would be over Kerry to one plus one.
It does zero here and one would be over.
Kerry one plus one zero hit one get one plus one.
Then one Kerry won best one one one one one one one one plus one, then one get one with one 10.
And one good note what you can do is you can see is that this one?
Getty It is going outside the boundary of a big box in case of a 32 bit ball total.
Similar thing will happen.
It will go outside the boundary of the 32 bit box and hence this Kerry would be discarded.
Again, this will not get stored because it is going outside the boundary of the bucket.
And what is this number?
This number is nothing but the number zero that means this will complement form actually works.
And this is how the minus five is being stored inside the memory of computer.
This number is not minus five.
If it is stored in those complement form, this is something else.
OK.
So I hope this edition using does complement form is clear.
I will also show you one thing the both of you want to figure out what?
What does this number OK?
What is this number?
Let's say I have written this number and you want to figure out what is this number?
I'm curious to know what number is being represented.
OK.
So let us say that, OK?
And this number represents some negative number that is minus X.
OK.
And doing all those compliment.
Means we are negotiating a no.
OK.
It was a compliment, means we are negotiating a no.
OK, if I take a compliment one more time.
So if I say, let me take those compliment of this, so minus of minus x this year produce plus x.
So what I will do, I will flip all the bits in order to take those compliment.
OK.
And the.
We have zero one zero rate, and I'm going to either one do it.
So I have zero one one one one zero one one, right?
This number now you can interpret it using powers of two.
Because design zero, that means it as a positive number, and you interpret this number by combining
the powers of two and whatever it is, this number, this number is just a negative of this number,
OK, because we added a minus sign in the beginning.
Let me give you another example, but if I have a number in which everything is just one, let's I have.
One day, right?
So first thing, I know it is a negative number, but I don't know what this number is.
So if I say, let's say this number is minus X and I negated.
That means I take a dose compliment of it, OK, so that means flip all the bits, make everything as
idle and you add one here.
This number is now zero zero zero one, right?
Basically, magnitude wise, this number is one.
And since the first bit was one, it was a negative number.
So this gives us X two x is one and the number was minus X and hence the actual number.
This number represents minus one in its twos complement form.
OK.
So this is how you interpret a negative number written in those compliment form.
You negated to get the magnitude and you see the sign read was one and hence it was a positive number.
OK.
Now, given any number in the.
In the 32bit format.
OK.
The way you're going to interpret that number, so firstly, you should know, is it stored in the signed
form?
OK, if it is stored in the signed form, then you look at the first bit.
If the first bit is one, then you find that those complement of it to get the magnitude and sense of
usbut was one, it was a negative number.
But if the first bit of zero, you can simply interpret this number as double our zero plus two per
one plus two squared plus two Q.
And this number is nothing but eight plus one that is nine.
So this number is nothing but nine of the first 10 zero.
And if there is, if it does contain no look at that, then it becomes easy for us.
It is a positive number.
You simply combine the bubbles of two like we did here as well.
You get what that number is, OK?
I hope that clears out the confusion.
The difference between signed and unsigned integers.
And that's all for this video.