So you have got some idea about how storage works in this lecture, we're going to talk about how you
can calculate the range of data types, okay, how big number can be stored inside an integer or some
other bucket.
So we are going to talk about what is the largest possible range that the integer can hold together.
If I give you a box that can only store two bits.
Can you tell me what is the largest number that you can form?
OK.
The largest number, let us talk about if it is an unsigned one, right?
That means there is no no concept of a binding.
There is no negative.
No.
The older two, but they represent the magnitude.
The clearly the largest number that you can form is all ones, which is three and the smallest number
is all zeros.
Which is it?
So you can store the numbers in the range zero to 0.3 in a double box?
OK, that is zero zero zero one one zero and one one.
So these are the four numbers that are possible and that makes sense because a two-bit box you can have
arrested about that is you can represent only four numbers, right?
OK, if I give you a vote box, this is why this number is still zero for the largest number is No.
15 eight.
That means starting from zero, you can store up to do this to the devour for minus one, right?
Similarly, if I give you eight bit box, the largest number would be zero and it would be to raise
the bar about eight minus one.
Two days to debate it is 256 to the largest number can be 255, right, so the road to 255, right?
So this number is to activate the Rangers zero to two days to deliberate minus.
What we have seen till now is that we have in the works.
We have a long integer and is storing 32 bits.
OK.
The range of integer in case of unsigned and be it, it would be starting from zero to do this today,
about 32 minus one eight.
This is this value approximately two ten point nine.
So that means if you have a number that is containing candidates, you will not be able to store it
inside and be it, you will have to go with the long and long resolved that long and has 64 bit than
what the case is.
I'm talking about unsigned and unsigned.
Long, long, right?
In this case, the Ranger's going from two to do this trip over 64 minus one and which is approximately
two into 10 bullet hitting right.
This is what the ring is, that means if you have any digit in which you can have up to 18 digits that
can be stored in long up to eight benign digits that can be stored in integer right.
And you will not be able to store a number which has more than 18 digits in the regular data types.
You will have to use something like a big integer or you will have to do something like, Hey, we are
not going to talk about that yet, but in the long depths of vision for most of your use cases, OK?
Now we have only talked about unsigned Intrade.
But what happens when you also have a signed integer?
OK?
What happens if you have a sign in digit?
Let us look at that as well, right?
So let us.
Look at that as well, right?
Let me create two boxes, one for design and one for the unsigned.
Again, I'm creating a box for the signed and unsigned.
Oh, this is it's a this is.
Long and this has later entered into enters a smaller box.
So led to this is your unsigned long.
OK.
And this is your.
Signed long.
That means it has 64 bits.
This is your unsigned int.
And this is your.
Signed into right.
Other discussed inside integers, the first bit is reserved for the saying OK, and the total capacity
is 64 bits here and 64 bit right.
Reverberates said as well, right?
And here it is, 32 32bit.
And had already started to engage over, indeed, because it is a four byte bucket and what it means
two words.
Now the first bit, you know, is reserved for cyanide.
So in this case, it is very simple.
All the 32 bit are used for the magnitude.
So we have seen if you have 64 bit, the smallest number is zero.
The largest number is oil ones.
So that is of.
The order to raise to the bar was 64 minus one, which is approximately of the order and barbarity and
internal interchanges of untainted.
It does.
The minimum is zero.
The largest is to raise to devour 32 minus one.
But hit what what is going to change here?
You don't have all the 64 bit available to represent the magnitude of the largest ballot.
I would be you have only 63 bits, and the largest power would be of starting from zero up to two six
to eight.
Of this one, we're talking about what are the largest number that you can store with 64 bit the largest
number is of the order to the 64.
This in this case, the largest number would be to this to deprive a 63 and minus one, right?
That is what it is going to be.
And obviously, we can store the numbers from zero.
But we can also store the negative numbers, OK, if we can also store the negative numbers, the the
smallest negative number would be minus of two days to divide.
63.
OK.
What actually happened is that age gets divided, half of the numbers are positive and half of the numbers
are negative.
If you talk about how many numbers you can represent using 64 bit, the number of numbers, the number
of number, the stories to the politics differ because at every place we can have zero one that is doing
to 22 multiplied by six multiplied 64 times.
So we have 264 possible combinations.
Out of which these many combinations, including the route, is to the bar 63, which are greater than
equal to zero and starting from minus one minus two days to 63.
We have these many which are negative to combining these two.
It becomes 2.2, rated by 63.
Just do this to the do so effectively.
We have these many combinations.
These many numbers can be represented using a 64 bit, indeed, similarly, for a 32 bit number, the
largest number is to this to divide 31 minus one because effectively there are 31 bits for the magnitude
and the smallest number is minus off to this department at 31.
OK.
And we have a zero in-between as well.
Guess so we can store the positive numbers as well as negative numbers.
That is where the slight difference comes in.
So here the range is slightly higher towards the positive side and there is nothing on the negative
side.
But in case we have equal number of numbers on the positive and the negative side and the ranges.
Less by a factor of two.
On the positive side of that is the difference between the unsigned ones.
And the sound once again, so I hope you have understood this concept of the range of integers, and
that's all for this video.