Everyone, so in this lecture, we're going to talk about the storage of floating point numbers, especially
especially turned up, it's OK.
So the storage is a little more complex than indeed just because floating point numbers are a little
tricky to handle.
For example, if you have a number like thirty point one to five, you have the magnitude.
You also have floating port and you also have the sign.
OK, so if you have a floating bucket, which generally takes 32 bit odd, if you have a double bucket,
which takes 64 bit, OK?
There are three parts.
Those to store the numbers.
So one part is for the saying, OK, which can be zero or one, which you can look at.
Another part is for the magnitude, let's say the number is 30 so that you can convert into binary very
easily.
So that part will go ahead.
And then we have a part for the procedure.
Wizard Double is known as double precision, and fraud is known as single precision, so you can see
23 bits that deserved for precision and float on about 52 bits.
That is old for precision and in case of double.
That is why we said that double can handle higher precision.
OK.
And if you have scientific calculations which need a lot of precision, you should go into double digit
type instead of going with floor to get that being.
This gives you a high level idea of how floating point numbers are getting stored.
Apart from it, I will tell you one more thing for example, how the numbers after decimal they're actually
stored.
What example you are storing something like, uh, let's say, twenty three point six seven five.
OK, something like this.
Now how?
How is this number stored?
223 we know.
So 23 is nothing, but it is.
If I just make something like one two four eight 16 to 23 is sixteen plus four plus two plus one.
This gives me the integer right of twenty three.
But what about this number, OK?
We discussed that this is two bar zero two bar one.
From this point, we start to get the negative powers of two.
OK.
So we have to go over minus one two by one minus two, 12 or minus three to power minus four over minus
five to power minus six and so on.
So what is to power minus one, which is point five?
What is doable over minus two with one one four, which is 0.05?
What is doable minus three one one eight, which is 0.05 one two three.
What you try to do is given a number.
Let's say you want to represent the number one seven five.
So how you are going to represent, OK?
You are going to say, OK, I'm going to take this power of two, which is blind faith, and I'm going
to add.
This power, which is one to five.
And this gives me the exact number.
Won't do so, we will put one one hit and rest, everything would be all zeros, OK, we're now suppose
you have a number like one seven five eight one.
So what you will you will try to accommodate powers so that you reach a value that is either equal to
or the closest possible look at.
Maybe you're acting very small powers.
It's a point to five, then maybe plus something something point zero.
One zero two five zero zero two five something like this.
OK, so you're going to generate a number that is very close to this value.
Maybe your starting point seven seven seven eight two five zero zero.
This might be the actual representation in the memory.
And when you're going to rounded off, you might get something close 2.7 five eight one eight two something
like this.
So that is why we say the floating point numbers they they have, they don't store the exact values,
but they're a close approximation of given values.
That being said, if you use a type like double which has high precision, OK, that means you can have
more options so you can reach a more closer value because you also have very small numbers, very small
deltas that you cannot and you can reach close to that value.
So that that is why we say they're double has higher precision, OK?
Double has higher resilience because.
It can support a lot of small values that you can add and add together more equity, it places, you
know, because that is a high level idea behind the storage of floating and doubles.
And that's all for this with you.
If you are interested, you can learn more about I triple standards and how this is actually done using
the concept of Mendoza and Exponent.
But I've given you a very high level overview of the storage.
That's all for this video.
Thank you.