Hello, everyone, and this lecture will discuss the implementation of global Typekit, so what we do
is because last time was in the last video died, we will have two loops.
The first loop will repeat some process, so that process will go on and minus one times in every such
iteration.
What we will do, we will pick the element at the front and it will push it towards the end of the edit,
OK, or to the suitable position where it can fit.
So we can see the far end times equal to one times less than equal to and minus one time C++.
OK, and every time what we need to do, we need to do repeated swapping and we need to push the element
in the right direction.
OK?
So do a repeated swapping.
So for that, we said we will take a variable G that goes from zero.
And for the first iteration, what it is going to do.
So what we discussed was led to be of a five year, five four three two one.
So what we will do will make comparison with for what it will become like four five three two one and
then we will compare 5.3.
It will become four five four three five two one.
Then we'll compare these two.
It will become four, three, two, five and one.
Then we will compare these two, OK.
So if you have any elements which are not sorted, OK, then you only need to go to the other index
and minus two.
OK.
This is then minus two other, and this is the minus one other index.
So when the value of time does one, we effectively want to go model in minus two, so that that means
they should be less than equal to end minus times minus one.
If.
And we can see jobless plus, and since we have generalized this, this will work for all.
All right.
Okay.
So we can check if the correct element that is AIG, if it is greater than the next element, a jobless
one, then we are going to swab them so we can to swab edgy and plus one.
That's it.
And this is how we can do bubbles or together.
That's the entire algorithm.
And we are just going to repeat this work and minus one times, OK, repeat this work and minus one
times and you will end up getting us started at it.
As we discussed.
Now, let us try to print all the elements of the city.
OK, so we can to see out air and maybe followed by a comma.
Well, the cold.
OK.
This should be.
A let's make this as a and.
This is for this is for.
So this should be void.
And we are done now if I run bubbles out here.
So this should be ex.
And now, if veteran rebels are dead and you can see we are getting this minus 12 minus two minus one
one three three four five six.
We are getting all the elements in the right order and we also have the breeding elements, negative
elements.
Everything is working just fine, OK?
So I hope this court is clear and now we will discuss the next sorting algorithms in the next lecture.