Everyone in this lecture will talk about elections, our algorithm, so it's again, a very simple algorithm
and based upon the very basic idea that we every time what we will do will find out the minimum element
from the unsorted part of that, and we will put it to the beginning, OK?
So if it is not clear like this, let us go through one example to understand it better.
For example, we have added like, let's say, three to one five on foot.
Let's say I want to sort the city using selections out so I can break this error into parts.
Let's say currently, I'm at this particular position and the rest of the error is unsorted.
Eddie, let's say two one five foot so we can see we will pick one element that is minimum from the
unsorted part and we will bring it to the current position, OK?
So what is the element that is minimum in this part?
We know this element is one.
So we will iterate over this unsorted, but we will take one element that is minimum and we will bring
it to the fact we know one is minimum.
So we will put one here and we will swap with three here, OK?
So now we know that at least this element is in the right position and we can go to this particular
element, okay, so now what we have, we have one comma two.
This is the position we are talking about and the rest of the is not sorted.
That is three five foot.
We figured out what is the minimum element in the rest of the body, including this element.
We can see the minimum element unto itself and it means it is in the right position.
We don't do anything OK.
So next time what we do, we know we have one two which are in the right position.
We are the position of this element.
Three.
And again, if you see what is a minimum in these three elements.
So it's again three, we will not do anything.
We will move on to the next element.
We have one two three that in the right position.
We move to the next element that is five.
This is in the current position and we have this part of that is underwater right now.
We take what is the minimum element in this area.
So we know this is for two weeks rapid with the element, which is the current position.
So we get one two three four.
And if you start n minus one elements of the three, that means you have already figured out the N minus
one elements that should come in the first and minus one positions.
Then automatically the last element would be in the right position.
OK?
So this is the whole idea of doing this election.
So OK, so it's a very simple and easy algorithm to implement, and in the next lecture, we will discuss
the implementation of selection talked.