Everyone.
So let's begin the implementation of selections, OK, so what we discussed, we will go from a position
that is initially zero and we will go till the second last element that is equal to N minus two.
And we will do position plus plus OK.
And every position we know what is the current element.
So the current element is nothing but area of position, that is the current element.
Let me draw one example 02.
Let's say we have a reverse order that is five, four, one, three and two.
Let's say this is how that it looks like.
So currently this is the position the entire date is and.
We will find out what is the minimum in this IndiaToday.
And we will put it to the front.
So we will say, OK, -- Variable G, that starts from position and it goes till the last element
and we do J Plus Plus.
So what we can take, we can find out the minimum element, OK, so using this loop to find out the
minimum element.
OK, so first we will find the minimum element once we know which is the minimum element we will do
swapping outside the loop.
OK, outside the loop, we will do the swapping so we can say, OK, the minimum sulphide is let's have
five, so we can initialize the minimum element.
So let's imagine a minimum so far we can see.
Or let us simply compare with the current itself, OK?
OK, let me just do something good if I can to area off.
Gee, that is the current element.
It is less than than sort of storing the element.
We can actually store the position, OK?
You can store what is the position of the minimum element.
So we can say this is a variable which will store the index of.
Minimum living, OK?
They need to define this variable.
So I can say in the beginning, the minimum position is same as position, but if you find an element
that is smaller than added off main position in that case, you can update many position as.
OK, so what is going to happen?
You move on to the next this element.
You see, this forward is smaller than what is at often positions.
I don't mean bush in his faith.
So you update your main position to this variable.
So your main comes here next time you go to one.
You take closely.
You go to bed.
Five is for less than five batteries.
Yes.
We update your mind.
Next time you compare one less, then forward because you have already updated main position.
So you are comes to this point.
Next time to take is three less than one.
That is no, we will not do anything.
Next time you check is to less than one Dhanteras.
Finally, your main position points to one and your position points to five.
You will strap five and one.
OK, so we can see outside the loop we are going to swap array off min position and area off position.
That's it.
And if you keep on doing this for all positions from zero to and minus two, this is in minus one.
This is n minus two, as we discussed in the last video.
We only need to do so at this point because if you thought and minus one element, the last element
would automatically get sorted.
OK.
So that's the whole idea of doing selection type.
So what we can do, we can then this court, and if it is not clear, we will do that right and also.
OK.
So this is it.
Let's build a code.
OK.
This this should be selections.
Art.
And now we are going to go.
And you can see we are getting this already, and this is working fine as well.
So that's good.
Let's quickly try it, and this could lead to five four one three two later.
This is the eddy.
In the beginning, position is zero.
We are here.
We start from day called opposition day LA than we are outraged over this.
Indeed, Eddy and we find out where is the main opposition.
OK, so we get to know about this element.
This is the minimum.
And after we know the minimum, we swap out of main position and position.
So we swap one in five.
It becomes one four five three two.
Next time we have this as untitled eddy, this is position the Sasman position as well.
Then we iterate on this part and we see what is the minimum.
So we see this is the minimum we swap for and do so it becomes one two five three four.
Next time we have this part, we see what is the minimum three is the minimum, so it becomes one two
three by foot.
Next time we have this part, this is position and this is in minus two.
We see what is the minimum in this part because it's for what we do one, two, three, four and five.
And that's it.
OK, we saw you worked for N minus one element and you can do this loop is actually running and minus
one times, OK, so from zero to n minus two, we have and minus one iterations.
And this element is automatically sorted.
So that's selection's out for you.
Let's let's discuss intelligence art in the next lecture.