Everyone in this lecture will talk about insurgents art, just another sorting algorithm.
So and I know it's difficult to remember so many algorithms, so that's why I'm trying to relate these
names with some examples.
The idea of intelligence art, you can say, is inspired from playing off cards like a card game.
So, for example, if you have certain cards in your hand and let's say they are already sorted, you
have a card five, you have a card, seven you have a card eight.
And maybe now if I give you a card six and I want you to insert it in the right index right place.
So what do you do?
OK.
Let me start from the right and let's see.
It is very good.
So maybe put it aside in this big side and maybe create some space here between five and seven and you
insert this card at this particular positions or basically becomes like five, six, seven and eight.
OK.
So this is exactly what we do in insertion site.
And if you remember this example, you will never forget insertions are in your life.
So we need to see how this algorithm is going to work on own dietary.
So the idea, as I discussed, is to insert a card or a number in its correct position in the sorted.
But what is this sorted by?
What is this uncharted part?
Let us look out through one example.
It's a we again have a five, four, one, three and two.
Let's say this.
Is that it?
What we will do will divide this error into two parts.
Let's say this part the first element is sorted, but and this part is uncharted part.
OK, so an array of single element will always be sorted one.
So now what we're going to do, we are going to pick this number.
We are going to start from, let's say, equal to one.
And we are going to see at which position we can place for, OK, so we have a guard five.
Where do you want to place for?
So obviously, but what will come before faith?
So what we will do, we will keep forward in a temporary memory.
We will do OK.
I have kept out for one three, two a lang.
As it is.
We are not.
We are not touching them as of now.
We are doubtful.
And we said, OK, go back and create a position for four.
OK, so we we can do five is greater than four, so we will copy five.
OK, and we try to go back now.
We can't go back any further.
That means four will come here.
OK, so now we have two elements which are sorted and we have three elements which are not sorted.
Again, we will pick one and we'll say, OK, let us try to put one in the right position.
So we see what we do.
We put one in a temporary memory.
Let's say we put we copy one somewhere and we create this position, OK?
And we have Warren year, and obviously five is greater than one.
So it will move one step ahead like this.
We go back and check.
Gone is for greater than 1.3.
This support almost one step ahead.
And finally, we end up at this position.
OK, so we have moved faith.
We have moved forward and this position is empty.
And here we are going to insert one.
OK, so this is how we get three elements which are now sorted.
OK, next what we will do.
We will talk.
We have one, four or five or decided we have three two, but just not started.
We pick this element.
We try to insert three in the right position.
So what we do?
We got between a temporary memory.
We make this empty.
We have a five year and five is greater than three, so it moves one step ahead.
So five comes here and we have we come back one step.
We have a four year forward is greater than three.
So four comes here.
And one one already is here.
OK, so we can create an empty slot at this position, OK?
So we basically copy forward to the next position.
We copy five to the next position and we have already copied Trina and Brittingham.
Now we see we added one is one bigger than three.
No, it's not.
So we stop at this particular point.
At this particular point, we the point that is our dislocation, OK?
And we say, OK, let's put tree hood on.
This is how we insert tree in its right position.
So similar thing we will do for two.
So we have one three four five.
We copy doing a temporary memory and we keep on moving these elements one step ahead.
So five goes here or was here.
It becomes four.
Three goes it.
It becomes three.
One will not go ahead because one is not greater than two civil potato here, so it will become one,
two, three, four and five.
OK, so I hope that it is clear that idea is very simple, and in the next lecture, it will become
more clear once we discuss the implementation.
So this is interchanged, let's see in the next little.