Hello, everyone.
In this lecture will discuss the implementation of indigenous art.
So I'm going to complete this method intentions, art on what we learned this every time we perform
this process of insertion.
What happens is we start from this index and we try to insert in the next location, then we try to
enter to in the right location, then we try to insert one in the litigation and then we try to insert
six in the right location.
So basically from one to n minus one.
OK, so we start from index one until index and minus one.
We want to place these elements in the right position or get placed these elements in the right index.
The right position, you can see.
So what we're going to do?
We are going to.
See, Ford and I quote one I less than equals and minus one or less than an A-plus plus, so effectively
we're going going to run this loop and minus one times because if and minus one elements are in the
right index, then everything is sorted.
So our current element is nothing, but it's at Delphi and the previous element, which is just before
current, so that there's nothing word that isn't index a minus one.
I will give you one example.
Let's say you have already you have already started this array.
Like, let's say you have.
Two, three, five.
And what you want is you want to insert one in the right index.
We'll start from the previous.
Does this previous and this is the current element.
So we have already copied one in a bucket called current that we have created a copy of one.
And what we did see, while this previous is greater than equal to zero and ADF previous is greater
than current.
So what we will do, we will say, let's move these elements one step ahead.
So I can say area of previous plus one that should be equal to ADF previous and previous should go back
one step.
So if you just execute this loop on this?
On this state of the river, what is going to happen is the rent is already equal to one.
And this is previous.
This is also previous plus one.
So we are saying, but if this is greater than equal to zero, yes, and at previous is greater than
good.
Yes, five is greater than current.
So we move, we copy five at this particular index.
OK, so here we now have five.
OK.
And if I draw using a different color, so we are putting a five year and previous goes, one goes back,
one steps.
The previous comes here.
We check if reversed is greater than current.
So what is correct?
But on this one, so is three greater than one.
The answer is yes.
Yes, it does.
So we put out of previous plus one equal the previous insert of this five, we pull the trigger and
previous comes back one step which is still greater than one than today's.
Yes.
So we say, OK, reverse +1 should be equal the previous.
So we put a two here, OK?
And previous goes back one step.
OK.
Finally, we end up either index that is actually minus one.
So in that case, what we are going to do wherever the previous stops in the next place of doubt, we
are going to put the element that is equal to current.
So finally, after this loop is over, begin to erode.
Previous This array of previous plus one should be equal to the current element.
That's it.
So what we did, we put one from here to here.
Now, if you see what this added becomes, this now becomes one, two, three and five, one, two,
three and five.
OK.
And maybe, let's say, instead of having a six year, you had afforded OK, in that case, what you
will do your first copy this dual current.
OK.
And then you will think previous, it's five greater than four.
Yes.
The previous plus one is this index.
You put a five year current already as forward and you move.
Previous one step back revise.
Comes it OK and add this step you take is three greater than four dancers, nor does not.
So we break this loop.
We come out of this loop and we still get off.
Previous Plus one should be equal to current.
So this is previous.
This is previous plus one.
We could afford it and we are then we have inserted forward in the right index, so it becomes one,
two, three, four and five.
I hope this intermediate step of inserting an element in its right position is clear and this will do
for all the elements from index one, two and minus one.
And this will do insertion site under.
Entirety.
OK.
That's what we're doing.
We're using this loop to find we are using this loop to find the right index.
There, the element current should be inserted.
So that's it.
That's how the insurgents are.
That's going to work.
Now let us save over cold.
And let's build it, and let's try to run it as well.
And, you know, we are getting those artillery.
That means our insurgents are working perfectly fine.
So that's all.
Thank you for.