Everyone in this lecture will talk about this auditing algorithm, which is known as binary search,
OK?
So what is this binary search?
We'll discuss.
So it's an algorithm that works on sorted at is guess what that means?
So that means the elements that arranged in alphabetical order order.
If it is integers that either increase arranged in increasing order or in decreasing order, OK.
So let's see.
Let's take the same restaurant example again.
Suppose you go to a restaurant, but this time your menu is arranged in the order in which the items
are in alphabetical order.
Let's say, OK, so maybe we have a burger.
Maybe we have Coke.
Maybe we have a dosa.
Maybe we have.
Maggie, we have let's appeaser in, let's say these are the items we have on, let's say, something
we assume as well.
Now you can see these are arranged in alphabetical order.
So we all took all this as a lexical graphic, Auchterarder.
And maybe you want to search for an item?
Let's appeaser.
OK, and some other randomly, you insert us today trading from the index zero.
You certainly look at you directly.
Look at those, OK, and you know, the menu is arranged in a proper order and you want to go overseas.
So what you will do in that case, you will never scan this list.
You know, if it is arranged in a proper order, then be the most come after those.
So maybe what you do use, can you start out reading from it?
OK, maybe you saw it in this particular bite.
So this is the whole idea of doing binary search.
We let us discuss the exact algorithm, and it will help us to save time if the error is sorted out.
OK, so let's say this is how the array looks like and what binary search will do.
We will.
Binary means two.
OK, so what we will do, we will divide that into two parts every time by the middle element, let's
say we are looking for an element that is led to nine being OK, we want to search for it.
19.
So what we do, we know this is the starting point of daddy, this is the ending point of day.
We find out what is the middle element and that is the middle element is.
Eleven, so we will divide the city by the midpoint.
Now if this is the area, so this is the middle point, we are looking for 19 and this that is a ordinary.
OK, so this should be 30.
Just, uh, there is a small mistake here.
This should be tightly.
This should be dirty, and let's say we are looking for.
19 to 19 must lie to the right of the merits of what we do.
We discard this part of the body or get out of an element.
We reduced our problem to a size, often by two.
Next time, what we're going to do, we are going to say, OK, you should surge only in this part of
the body.
That means the start will come here and we are not worried about Desmond and this diet.
This is now obsolete for the next iteration.
What we do again.
So we again do the same work.
We find out the midpoint this time.
We have a smaller ready 19, 29 and 30.
OK.
We know this is the midpoint, and we are looking for 19, OK, and this is and this time.
So we're looking for 19, that means this must come to the left of the mid.
Well, guess what, we discard everything that is.
They're on the right of the murder, including the murder itself, because murder does not equal to
90.
OK.
What will we bring our end to this particular point?
So Visa, OK, and now we have this is the first iteration.
This is the second iteration in the third iteration, what we have.
We start, we have end.
Both of them point to nineteen.
OK.
And what we are looking for, we are looking for an element that is equal to 19 to be final, the midpoint.
And we see this midpoint exactly contains a value that we require.
OK, so we actually redone this particular index.
But suppose instead of 19, we were looking for 20.
OK, so now the first step would be seen.
One of those 11 go to right.
We will get the city in the second step midpoint is twenty nine.
It will go the left and we will again get 19.
So at this point, what we will do, we will say we're looking for 20, where the middle point is 19,
that means it must come to the right of this particular element, OK?
So what we do is simply do the article to make plus one.
OK, start the column.
In that case, what is going to happen and is going to remain hit?
The start is going to come here, OK, the start is going to come here.
OK.
So as soon as this happens, that means start becomes greater then, and that means this element does
not present, OK, so that means if this happens, then we can see the element is not present inside
this particular area.
OK, so what will happen?
You start from an area of size in and then it will reduce to NY two, then it will reduce to end by
forward, then it will reduce to end by eight.
Eventually, it will reduce to one.
If that element does not equal to what you expected, your are condition will get it will get either
end will come before the start or start will come before.
And in that case, we can see Element does not present.
Okay, so that means we reduce it to a size of zero.
That means not found.
And here we can see the elements formed.
We will return the index for the index we have this may or may not happen.
OK, going from one to zero may or may not happen, OK?
So this is what the binary search algorithm is all about.
OK, so now let us summarize what we discussed.
OK, so algorithm summary we will need a start that is set to zero.
We will need the end to end minus one in the beginning, and we need to do certain work again and again.
So we will have while what started as less than equal to end, OK?
That means when start accedes end, break this loop, find the midpoint.
OK.
The midpoint is very easy, you simply do start losing by two I and you do a combat zone.
The admit no comparison.
At the midpoint.
And from this comparison, you can have three things either the element can be cold, homemade or it
can be greater than meat, or it can be less than right, OK?
Accordingly, you will move left or right.
OK.
In the next few days, we will see the exact quote, but this is the this is on the high level what
we are going to do in the algorithm if we are out of the loop, we consider done minus one.
And if it is equal, we're going to say are done.
And my point, OK?
This is what we're going to do.
So if the if the midpoint is greater, OK, so if it's OK, if the midpoint is greater than what is
expected, let's say we're looking forward to OK, in that case, what we will do, we will move this
end from here to here because that means we will move and towards maybe minus one.
But we're looking for 19.
That element is greater.
We will move over start from start to less one.
That's what we're going to do.
So let's see the goal in the next lecture.