Everyone, now let's look at the implementation of binary search algorithm that we have just discussed.
So what we said, we said we will get the eddy we will get and and we will get the key.
So creativity was one important that is zero one is four and that is and minus one.
And why I'm baking in minus one because and minus one is the index of the last element, OK?
So if you have an element in entry, then last element desert and minus one.
So then we said we will do some work while star does less than equal doing.
And if that exceeds the value of end, this will break the loop.
We will come out of the loop and begin there, done minus one.
That means the element does not present.
So first, we will compute the midpoint that is dog plus end by two and then we can do a comparison.
If at F Med equals e, that means it is equal to the element that we are looking for.
Then our answer is nothing but the index made.
What if it is not the case if at f made?
Is greater than what we're looking for.
OK, so let's say at the middle, we have 15, but we're looking for an element three.
In that case, what we should do, we should reduce this part of the tree.
That means the end which is binding, it should come here.
That means end should be equal to maybe minus one.
So let's see and should come to the minus one.
Otherwise, the area of mate is smaller than what we are looking for.
Let's say the middle element is 15.
And we're looking for 20.
In that case, what we should do, we should discard this part of the tree and this diet should go ahead.
This dog should come to mate plus one.
So let's start equals mate plus one.
That's it.
And this will go on.
And finally, what we will get will get the correct index builder called on.
Let us try to donate their dogs like binary search.
Let's search for an element, let's say 30.
So it should be are indexed to.
Yes, it is correct that search for 70, so we have zero one two three four five six.
So it should be at Index six, which is fine.
Let's search for eighty nine.
Index seven.
And led search for, let's say, 77.
It says 77 not found that means all equities are working as expected.
The one last thing I want to talk about is how much work we are doing in terms of time.
So we are going to talk about time complexity.
How many iterations this loop is going to take?
So we have the first iteration, we have Eddie, which is our size, and we can say this is nothing
but and divided by two race to Dubai to zero.
That is one in the next iteration.
This Eddie is reduced by a factor of two.
OK.
We're digging this area by factor of two.
So that means let's say this is iteration number iteration zero iteration number one.
It does end divided by two ways to divide one.
In the next generation, it will become in by foot.
That means it would be end by.
It was good.
Attrition number two.
And after later, k number of iterations.
OK.
The addresses would become.
And by.
It would to park again, that should be called the one case after calibrations, it would be equal to
one because we're left with one element or zero elements after calibration, it would be to rated.
And it must be equal to one.
So what we can see, how many steps, how many times this loop is going to run?
OK, so we are doing a concerned world.
This work does not depend upon the value of N, but this loop depends upon the value of it.
OK, so we can say it in my duty to the basket.
This is equal to one that means and is equal to do this to the park and begin to gaze the equal the
log often.
OK, so this loop is going to run long and times, and that is why you will come across this dome that
the time complexity of binary searches are that of log of often.
So this look is going to take long and hydration look, if, for example, if it is off size 16, then
it will become eight.
Then it will become four.
Then it will become dull and finally it will become one.
What is log of 16 to the base?
Two?
So it is equal to four in exactly four steps.
We can find out where this particular element is present inside this particular area.
That is going to be the worst case.
For example, of one thousand in log of one thousand, the base two is approximately 10.
OK.
That means in an area of size 1000 in just 10 iterations, you can figure out where a particular element
is present.
A binary search is very fast and efficient algorithm, but it works only if your works.
Your search phase is a sorted search space, OK?
So the only condition required is your search space should be sorted.
But in other terms, we can see the search space is monotonic.
OK?
The monotonic means the values should be either non decreasing, you're going to have a service like
this or there should be on increasing OK, the the values should either decrease or they should remain
same only then the binary search will work.
When they're done, it means not decreasing.
Or non increasing.
So this govt is a non decreasing of this as a non increasing.
Okay, so in this example, we go into all the values are in increasing order and we could use binary
search in this particular example.
I hope you understood the concept.
See you in the next lecture.