Everyone.
Now we will discuss about the full sorting algorithm that is what told.
So what is the expectation of the sorting algorithms or assorted algorithm will take input underwater?
That always looks like this.
And you can see these numbers that are used in any random audit, but we want to output those numbers
in let's increase increasing order audit can be in decreasing order.
So if it is an increasing order, this is how the output would look like.
So this is what is the input and output of every sorting algorithm.
Now let us talk about what first algorithm that is known as bubble type.
So it has a very basic idea, like it's it's inspired.
You can say it's inspired from the idea of forming bubbles when you hit the water.
Or maybe you can use this example to remember, but holidays algorithm works, they'd say I have a beagle
which contains water.
And let's say Porter Bernard here, and we need this, we hit this up, OK?
What is going to happen?
You will see at the base of the beaker, small small bubbles will form.
As these bubbles grow in size, they will move to the top of the beaker and explode.
The similar kind of idea is there and bubble or what we do, take the larger element or take the larger
element to the end of the eddy by repeatedly swapping with different elements.
So I will show you how this actually works.
So let us take an array of, let's say, four elements.
Five, four, three, two and little one.
Let's say we have an equal to five.
We have five elements in the city.
And what we will do, we will.
Take the first element.
OK, we will take this element and we will compare with the neighboring elements, so we see if five
is greater than four.
We will do repeated swapping with the neighbor.
So Ford will come here and I will come here and we will still have three, two and one.
Next time we are going to compare firing three and this five will move.
Forward.
OK, so we'll have four, three, five, two one next time we will compare these two and we will see
it becomes four, three, two, five and one.
Next time we will have five and one, we will compare and it will become four, three, two, one and
five.
So you can see this five was a little bubble and starting from the beginning of the edit, it moved
towards the ending of that.
This is what happened.
And let's see our first iteration.
OK, so when you used to nested loops one for the number of times we are going to do this work, OK?
This is the work for the first time.
What we did.
OK, what would it be isolated from an index?
Let's equal to zero.
And we went to the index and minus two.
OK.
And every time what we did, we did a comparison between e.g. the data element and its neighboring element
of G Plus one.
OK.
So this is what we did.
Let us talk about what will happen in the next iteration.
OK.
Let's say we now have these elements.
We have this eddy.
Now the Element five is already sorted.
OK, the Element five is already sorted.
Now we have a smaller eddy.
We don't need to make comparisons to land.
Even if we make it will not change because five is the largest element.
And it is always at the end.
So we will have four three two one.
This is the eddy.
That means we need to start from index.
I can see.
We'll start from equal to zero.
And we will go till this index that is n minus three will come before entry.
It becomes three for the when one will compare four and it will become three to four and one, and then
we can compare four and one.
And it will become, let's say, body builders index.
This is n minus three, OK?
This is in minus three years.
And minus one and minus two and then minus three, yes.
So we will go to this element three to three.
This is three, two, one and four.
OK.
Yes, we are going to this particular index, which is in minus three, the first and we went all in
minus two.
So I'm talking about the days going from zero till and minus three because we all need to go to the
second last element, get in the city.
That's the whole idea.
So what we did, we built the bigger element that was fought and we pushed it towards the end towards
correct index.
OK?
So it is now in the right place.
This is what we do in the second or take a iteration of of the outlook that we're going to put.
We again did the comparison between Egypt and Egypt plus one.
Let's see what happens in the next iteration.
Now we have these elements, which are like four, three, two and one, OK?
We have three who earned one because in two alterations, two elements are already sorted.
We have five in the right place.
We have four in the right place, OK, four and five.
They're already in the correct position.
We're not going to talk about them.
So this is an minus one.
This is n minus two.
This is then minus three.
But we will just run the look till end minus four because at this position, we need next element to
compare because we will not go to this element to get this element will always be considered because
of this vector 80+.
What we will do will compare three with two two wheels.
OK, let's compare.
Three would do if this happens, then it will become two commentary, OK, and then we will compare
three and one.
What will look?
It will become two comma one and three.
So now three is in the right place and we are done for this iteration.
Okay, so this is what happens over time when we do repeated swapping.
And finally, one more time, we need to do this work.
So what we will do, we will say, OK, we now have only two elements in there that need to be sorted.
So these two elements are when one and the rest of it that is already sorted, that is three, four
or five.
Start from here.
I will say, OK, swap it AJ and AJ plus one.
If the current element is bigger, then the next will evaporate.
It becomes one commando and we will go all in minus, let's say, five.
Only only this index will start from zero, and we end up in minus five, which is this index only.
And yes, we are OK if we don't need to do any work.
So that's it.
That's it.
And this is how out the final three looks like, OK?
So one observation we need to make is in order to swab and minus one and the limits, OK, if you want
to swap and element what you do, if you simply put and minus one element to the to the right or to
the top, then the one element will be left here and that would be automatically the smallest so that
we observe that one is left it and it is automatically the smallest element.
OK, so effectively we need to do this entire process in minus one times.
And in this process, every time we need to start from zero to index and we need to go to the end minus
two minus, I attend.
OK.
OK, let's say I.
OK, so I will write these conditions in the cold.
It will be become more clear.
Let's say this is the number of times the loop is running post and the loop is running.
So we are going from zero to n minus two.
Taking them to look is running.
We are going from zero to n minus three all time, the loop is running.
We are going from zero to n minus four and fourth time.
We are going from zero to and minus five.
Effectively, we are saying that your inner loop.
Okay.
So we have a loop four times and we will have a loop four g.
The day will go from zero to end minus a minus.
Something like this and minus one minus.
Something like this.
We are going to do OK.
So if the value of times is one of a loop will go from zero to end minus two.
If the Times is too of a loop will go from zero to and minus three.
This is the whole idea of bubbles right now.
I hope this algorithm is clear to you and in the next lecture we will discuss the good.
They don't.