Hello, everyone's in this lecture, we're going to talk about conditional statements, so conditional
statements are required when you want to execute some code based on a certain condition, OK?
For example, you want to go out and you want to dig in.
And if the weather is rainy or you want to go out and you want to dig sunglasses if the weather is a
sunny day.
The best ones are environment variables.
You want to do some actions, OK?
So for that, in every programming language, we have a concept of a if block.
OK.
So what we are going to do, we are going to say OK will define our condition that evaluates the bullet.
For example, we said, OK, the marks is 90, and if Marks is greater than 80, then we will do some
work.
We will print, let's party.
We having to do a bite if we get more than 80 marks.
So this is a condition that evaluates tubulin.
OK, so this is an expression that gives gives us the value to it can also give false.
So if it gives false, then the corresponding block of code, OK, this block of code, this will not
get executed, OK?
So you can have one or more lines inside the f block.
So let me show you in a good night how you're going to execute this code.
So maybe what I can do, I can see ink marks and I will take input the marks from the user and if marks
greater than 80.
OK, so I will print.
Let's party and see out.
Yeah, something like that.
So we are actually executing two lines of code, right?
So, OK, that's very good.
I let it out as well.
So I can say da slash if demo.
So it is waiting for the input.
I can say, OK, I got 92 marks, so it says, let's party on you now.
One more thing I want to inform you here.
If you have if you don't want to put this block, then this gold will still get compiled on a vote on
this code.
And if I get something like 70 now, you can see you're getting the output right.
So what actually happens?
What happens if you don't put curly brackets?
So basically, what happens if you don't put curly brackets?
So by default, one line of code, it is included with the f block.
OK, so if you don't put curly brackets, then this statement is assumed to be inside the block and
anything that is written outside it.
OK.
That is the second line or the third line.
It is assumed that it is outside the f block.
OK, so this line will always get executed.
What we saw is when we give a value of marks, that is 70, the second line of code always got executed.
OK, so this code or if you have more lines of code code always executed both these lines?
Yeah, and always executed this output.
You will always get printed irrespective of what is inside your inside the f block like arms so you
can keep.
These two lines are always getting executed.
So that means if you have.
A work that is a single instrument statement inside the block, you can skip working locally brackets,
but I would still recommend you do in these brackets because they are more clarity.
You get what you are trying to do inside the f block.
That's about half block in the next video I will teach you about the block.