Everyone, so we have already seen how to write a blog on how to write conditional gold using give,
so if we also have something which is known as if as blog, OK, now suppose your condition is not true
and you want to execute something when the condition is false.
So that is the L block comes into the OK.
So what we have seen in this index, you if followed by a condition followed by a block of code, you
write one or more lines.
And if the condition is true, the block will get executed.
But suppose if the condition is false and you want to do something only when the condition is OK, so
you can put as block.
So maybe either you want to, but let's party if you get more than 80 marks, and if you don't get more
than 80 marks, maybe you want to print it, work out next time.
OK, so this can be easily done using an inverse block.
So let me show you in the code as well.
So maybe I can say is work hard next time?
OK, L's work hard next time.
Now, one thing to remember is that as we do not give any condition OK, so as cannot be used independently.
So if we can see that if Block can be written independently without writing the S block, but the ALS
block itself cannot be independent, it has to glove with the last f block, so it will get connected
with the last f block.
OK.
And there is no condition that you will specify in the S block, so it basically it gets executed when
this condition is false.
OK, when this condition gets voids, the control flow will come into this line and it will execute
everything that is written inside the ALS box.
Let us run this code and maybe put something in.
So this court has always executed irrespective of we are in the f block or we are inside this block,
we get into s block.
This code will always get executed.
So let me show you the output.
So maybe I got 92 monks, so it seems let's party on the flow of control and the control flow jumped
to line number 17 because we executed line number 11.
We did not execute this block because this condition is false.
This condition is true and this is this will not jump into the S block, so it will come here, OK?
And similarly, if I give something like 32.
So it will work hard next time and the code is always executed.
So this condition is not false.
So we execute what is written in the block and we come here, OK?
So that is about the first block.
I hope you understood this concept.