Hi, everyone.
So we have seen the blog.
We have also seen the health blog in this video getting to see something known as a live blog.
OK, so now you might require to write a code which behaves differently on different conditions, OK?
So basically, what we're going to do, we are going to define a new type of block that is as if we'll
get another.
One thing I will tell you is if you're writing a f block, OK, then after each block, you can write
multiple live blogs.
OK, you can have a live blog you can have in a live blog.
You can have another live blog as many as you want, OK?
And finally, you can have as blog, which is again optional.
If you want to do something in this blog, you can do otherwise.
You can skip this blog.
Know why this is useful.
So when you have a structure like this, OK, and it basically executes the first blog where the condition
gets so you can do your writing or condition inside if blog.
They're also writing organization ZAYDA as a blog, OK?
Now, for example, if you get 70 marks, so we know that this condition is not a total matter, not
greater than 80.
So this will not get executed.
OK.
So we come to the next blog and we get the deletions, which is much greater than sixty nine is yes.
So this blog will get executed.
OK.
And if none of these conditions is true, then obviously that is and the blog that will get executed
if none of these conditions is traded.
So basically, if you have a blog intro like this where the first condition as far as the next as follows,
and I suppose this is right, let us assume that this is also true and this we don't care right now
what what is going to happen.
It is not going to execute the two blogs, which it is only going to execute.
The blog, which is forced to write the blog, which got forced right.
So in this case, this is the blog which got first drew, then coming from top to bottom.
So only this blog is going to get executed.
OK, so that means in this call, if I had something like as if Mox greater than 50.
And I thought, OK, great or something like that, dialogue will not get executed if they put this
block below this block below the edit.
Let me show you a --.
And that would offer you more clarity.
OK, so let us jump into the code and show you the demo here.
So what I'm going to do I have if Mark's greater than 70.
OK, maybe I can put some grades here.
Let's party.
We got greedy and sealed.
Maybe very.
I would grade B and as if it's a marks greater than 60.
And what I'm going to do, I'm saying, okay, see, okay, um, keep it up and I can do great.
Let's see.
Now I've made this call, and I'm going to run it.
So let me show you.
Now I'm waiting for the marks, so I give something like, let's say, when do I get there, done grade
B and then this line of code is always executed.
So what is happening?
So marks 72, right?
And if I talk about this condition, this blog will not get executed because it is false.
And if I go on to the next block, which is this one?
Yes, I got 72 marks.
And this is true.
And this will get executed.
OK, now, although the below below this one, this block, right?
So this is also true, but it will not get executed because the only first elusive block in the gene
that will get executed, OK, I'm similarly this will not get executed.
None of these conditions are going to get checked as well.
So nothing below the block where the condition is true, it is going to take longer to execute it.
OK, because now when you use as it blocks, all of them are connected.
All of them are part of the same view.
So that means only one of them will get executed.
And once this block gets executed, nothing below these blocks, which is part of the same floor, will
get you will get executed, OK?
So that is why even you got the marks when you do this block of good will not get executed, although
this condition is true, but it is not going to get sick because we have already executed this final,
because that is what you need to remember about, as if only the first block where the condition becomes
true will get executed.
OK?
So that's it.
That's all for this video.