I it's one common thing that people mistake while working with defense, they sometimes try to use multiple
lift blocks.
OK, so I'll give you an example of multiple, if so, for example, in the code that we have written
down.
Suppose you forget to use Eldred and you end up using the if blog every year to do this or it is correct
and it will compile.
But it is not logically because I will explain away.
Now what I replaced as if blog.
If blog.
And now if I go and try to learn this code and let's run it.
So now suppose I give again the same input 72 and OK, it is giving me.
The answer, OK?
We are running the wrong fight, so the file name is multiple live demo, so we should not large multiple
if demo and now if I give 72 as input for 72 marks and actually getting two great great be on Grade
C.
Well, that is not expected.
Now let us try to analyze why this is happening.
OK, so when you write multiple statements did not the part of the same floor, OK, each block is treated
independently.
So now this block is independent.
The second is block, this is independent.
The third block, this is independent, this is actually combined with the last insider.
Now, if you give something like 82, then this block would be checked and it will get executed.
This blog again would be checked because it is independent.
It will also get executed.
And talking about this, so again, in this case, the last health is combined with the if statement
is cannot come alone.
It has to get combined with the if block.
So this is combined with this block and hence out of these two, which is going to get executed, if
not because you have Mox, which is greater than.
So you're going to get great.
Great, great.
Be great.
But you you always wanted to give only one grade.
So that means when you use get involves executing one of the blogs go with the if as it structure.
But if you have to do something like two different conditions, it's okay.
So I will give you an example, OK?
I include I stream using namespace as study and main return zero.
And maybe I can give you an example there are multiple, if would make sense.
OK, maybe you're doing two different things.
Of you, your taking.
Um, how is the weather OK?
And maybe depending on the value of that, you want to do something so maybe I can sync with it.
And it is one so you can check if there is one.
OK, so this is also treated as a.
Do statement, because anything that is non-zero, it is treated as true, so again, it's okay if weather
is, why not, if that is non-zero, right?
Maybe I want to enjoy the debate and maybe the second condition is based, one marks.
So if any marks equals two 90 and same if marks greater than 80, maybe I want to do something like,
let's celebrate the result, something like this.
In this case, there are two off blocks and they are independent, OK?
So there is no relation of the statement to whether the vid mocks.
Both of them can be true at the same time.
OK, so now if I build this school and if I show you the output, if I see multiple if.
OK.
So we are getting this thing, enjoy today, and let's celebrate the.
So in this case, it's okay to have two different if conditions getting executed at the same time.
OK.
But in the previous case, it was not OK to have multiple blades being assigned to the same person.
So I hope now you have understood the difference between using a as this blog versus using multiple
blocks, OK?
And yet all of them that part of the same view, only one of them will get executed where the first
condition is true, whereas in the other case, each block is checked independently, irrespective of
the previous block was true, or it was false.
OK, so that is the main difference.
And that is the point that people do make a lot of mistakes, but I hope now you will remember this
difference.