I was in this lecture hall when the electricity bill calculator.
So what is given we are given the total consumption of household and units, and we want to write a
program to estimate the total amount as by the following table.
OK, so this table basically tells us what is the rate of electricity for certain consumption in terms
of number of units?
So if someone consumes one 200 units, then he's not going to pay anything, so the bill would be Robbinsville.
OK?
If someone consumes from 100 to 200 units, then for each unit that is consumed in this range.
That it would be number of units that you have going to jump into five rate the number of units which
are greater than 100.
Of course it every day 100 units.
And if someone consumes from 200 or 300 units, it is so bad that basically these are the difference
that as you're going to do more electricity, your by unit rate is going to be higher, which is going
to be in this range because every unit that is consumed in this range, it is 10 rupees per unit because
whatever the number of units you're going to do, for example, you're going to undo 50 units.
So you're consuming 53 units, which are in this range, 200 or 300.
They will be charged art and rupees per unit.
So that would be multiplied with two.
And anything that is beyond 300 units, it would be charged the rate of electricity.
Let me just clarify this problem.
So the slabs at five, 10, 12 and.
Let me show you something.
So from zero to 100, it is zero, but 100 to 200 it is five, then 200 or 300 it is 10 and 300 plus
it is 12 is OK.
This is the unit cost of, I suppose, someone consumes 280 units of electricity.
OK, now how is going to be so from zero to 100 units?
He is not going to pay anything from 100 to 200.
How many units you have consumed?
So of course, he has consumed 100 units.
It is willing to pay 100 multiplied with the slab rate this loud, it is five billion to be ordered
into five from 200 to 300.
There it is 10.
But he is only consuming up to 288, so that means that he is consuming 80 units.
These are the units will be charged at Rupees 10 to Darden's 18.
So the answer would be 500 plus 800.
So he will be charged rupees 300 for consuming 280 took.
OK, this is example one.
So let me take you another example.
It is on one charges 300 450 units.
So again, zero 200, it is zero 100 to 200, which is hundred units.
So it would be handed into five, 200 or 300.
OK.
It is, again, Joe.
We are going to charge 400 units at the rate of rupees 10, which is like thousand rupees and what 300
what we have.
We have only 50 units.
These 50 units will be charged rupees by unit.
So it is 500 plus 1000 plus 600, OK.
So this comes out of group is 21.
So that would be the total bill of the person.
So given an input, the number of units we want to output, what is the total bill that would be generated
for that particular person?
Now it's your time.
Pull this video and try to think how you can hold this up, OK, how you can build this algorithm that
will work like this.
Alright, so I hope you have given a talk.
Now I'm going to show you the implementation.
OK?
So I'm simply going to use the conditional statements to decide in which category the person is lying
and will generate a formula for each of each of the particular categories.
OK?
So maybe I can go ahead.
So first thing is, I need to store the number of units, so I'll create a bucket.
I will declare a bucket, which I will take as input from the user, and I will try to generate a formula
that OK, if the number of units is less than equal to 200, then how much would should be my cost?
Maybe I can create a bucket called cost, which is let's not defined.
And if your unit is less than equal 200, the cost is also legal.
OK.
As if if this condition is not true, I can put if units is less than equal to 200.
Now look, if we are not putting a condition that if units is greater than equal, 200 and units is
less than equal to 200, OK.
So I don't need this and is ready like this in business.
I don't need to write this condition because if I am coming here right, then your needs must be greater
than 100.
Because I've used as if and if units were less than 100, then we could have easily stopped this if
that means if I'm coming.
The units are greater than 100 and I am only taking this condition if they are less than equal 200 so
that as if condition by building as a block, it simplifies of a condition.
OK?
We don't need to write additional check because if you are coming at, that automatically means that
this block was not true and only then we are landing up here.
OK, so I'm just going to avoid this check.
And what would be the cost?
OK, now let me give an example.
Let's say someone is consuming 170 units, which is less than 200 from zero to 100.
He would be charged to deal with 100 to 120.
He is going to pay for the 70 units, OK?
Basically, this is what the unit is.
So you have to subtract units minus hundred and you have to multiply with the slab rate, which is five.
OK, so we are going to say the cost is zero for up to 100 units on four additional units.
It is.
The units minus 100 into the slab cost.
The cost is five.
That's it.
That computes our cost.
Otherwise, if units is less than equal to three.
OK, so the ending, I do not need to check if they are greater than 200.
It automatically means overcoming it.
They're greater than 200, OK, otherwise we would have entered this as a block.
So now the cost would be for up 200 units.
It is going to be zero from under two 200 units.
How how much we have already consumed.
So this bag would always be 100 or get.
That means there is a fixed cost of a unit that is unloaded, multiplied with the slab that is five.
Now we know that we're somewhere in the middle of 200 or 300 later.
This is what the unit is.
So how many units are these?
These are nothing but units minus 200 000 plus units minus 200 multiplied by the slab rate.
The Slabbert is done.
OK, that computer cost.
Otherwise, we know that we have consumed more than 300 units.
And in that case, again, we'll up 200 units for the next hundred units.
It is five for next 200.
Units like up to 300 are destined for anything beyond.
It is 12 rupees, 12 rupees, but unit eight.
So now we have it cost is zero 430, up 200 units, then from 201 to 200, right?
It is our units multiplied with five from 200 to 300.
It is again 100 units multiplied with 10.
And anything that is beyond 300.
How many units.
So units minus three hundred OK.
Multiplied with 12.
Because this is this is going to the formula for anything that is beyond look as if it is not clear.
I can just explain this part again, this part because it includes everything, right?
So zero, 200, 100 or 200, 200 300.
Maybe somebody is consuming 800 units.
OK, so now for zero two hundred, we have already ordered zero done, but 100 to 200.
This will all discharged are to be safe.
So these are under units, OK?
From one zero one zero zero 200 from two zero one to 300, it is again 10 rupees per unit, so 100 multiplied
with five hundred multiplied with 10.
And from 318.
How many units are these?
So units minus 300.
OK, so this data is 500 multiplied with 12.
So this is actually going to add up and this is going to give us the final answer so we can see out
the final cost that is this much.
Now let us try to renovate code and I can say da large electricity bill and I give OK to it the units.
Thirteen hundred great.
This is what we computed 350 units.
Oh sorry, 350 units.
Do we get 20 100?
This is what we computed, OK, and maybe 800 units.
And the answer is 75 500, which seems good.
OK?
So that's all for this video and you can see an example of using as if these reason may be used as if
because only one of the number of units will only fall in one of these categories.
Okay, so they cannot fall in to three different categories.
The answer would depend upon whether the units the final units end up.
OK, so that's all for this video.
Thank you.