Everyone in this lecture will talk about ternary operator.
So let us first see how this operator is denoted.
So this operator actually has a question mark on the column, right?
And it also has we have to define a certain condition before the question mark condition means and an
explanation that evaluates to true or false or something like this.
An example of a condition would be, let's say, x x is greater than two something like that.
So here you will define some statement.
It meant one.
And here he will define an understatement.
It meant to basically this part, if this condition is true right, then the statement one will get
executed.
But if this condition is false?
The statement, would you.
Let me try to explain you with the help of a good demo, and maybe I can that would offer you more clarity.
So what I will do, I will open up the text read and I can look in ex-model, as do it, said this is
the condition the mod operator gives us the remainder.
OK.
And I can say OK, if it is equal to zero, maybe I want to see out even.
And otherwise, I want to see out or something like this.
And what is it?
So we need to define X and we will take and put the value of its like A and B that we are taking input
and then we are checking if this condition is true or not.
So this this whole thing is one condition, OK?
And then we have statement one, which is sealed even and then we have statements he ordered.
Now if this condition is true, that means the number is actually even we will print even on otherwise
we will print it.
So in case of this part will get executed in case of false.
This part will get executed.
You may ask, why do we need this?
You may not always need this, but this can be used as a shorthand for, if else, if you have a word
that is only a single language inside the block.
If you want to do work, that is.
When comprising of only one line of code, something doing, then maybe in that case you can use an
alternative operator in case of a fence as a replacement, or it will reduce the number of lines of
code that you're using.
But talking about algorithmic optimization, it is equally good or it is equally fast as if fence OK,
so you can either use it field or you can use this one if you have a very simple defense case, OK,
if it's totally your choice.
But if else can also handle more number of statements inside if log on inside the health block as well.
But here we are, just what we are talking about.
One statement OK?
One statement for true and one statement if their condition is false.
So maybe let's build this code and let us try to run it.
Something that he operated on Dodge last.
And maybe I give the number eight going to get this, is you a number?
Maybe I give the number 11.
So I get this is a hard number.
OK.
This is how this operator is working on.
Maybe I can give you another example.
Maybe I can say.
It's a.
I want to assign a value to maybe a string.
And I can just drink whether.
And maybe I will depend.
It will depend upon the value of X. Maybe if the temperature is greater than 20 degrees Celsius, I
can say it's so hot.
Otherwise, it's good.
Let's see.
OK, maybe I can see out what is the victory?
I will give put a number on based upon the value of the number, if it is greater than 20, the weather
would get away.
Otherwise, it would get away.
That is cool.
OK, now let's underscore and we I give the number 25 get too good when the individuals are no and the
weather is hot, which is OK.
Maybe the number 10, they're going to get an even number and the weather is good, right?
They're actually both of these are examples of binary operator.
So you get what I'm trying to tell you through.
The second example is you can use this as a part of the assignment.
OK, maybe you want to assign some value to the weather based upon the temperature.
We are saying, OK, this is our condition.
If the condition is true, then this value would get assigned to the weather because the weather will
take the value hot.
If this is false, then weather will take the value.
Cool that it is a drizzle.
The ternary operator is working in this case.
I hope you got the concept, and that's all for this video.