Everyone in this lecture will talk about switchgear statement, the switch cases used when you have
to select one of the multiple blocks of code based upon a certain value and you need to execute that
block of code, OK, get will define us, which case in something like this, we have a switch, followed
by some expression that evaluates to a particular value.
So that value, let's say, is X or Y or something sums each of for each of the possibilities.
We have defined the keys and in that case will write some bits of code that will get executed.
OK?
So I'll show you with the help of a more real example.
For example, let's say you're building something to print the days of the week later.
If you input one, it should print Monday.
OK, if your input do, it prints attitudes Tuesday or three.
It prints Wednesday for Thursday and up to up to four seven four Sunday.
What you're looking at your input is is a value and or seven values if you do it using if else you need
seven blocks of AFL to get that kind of stuff can be simplified a little using the Switch case block.
And let me show you an example maybe I can to end today.
I will take input today and I will put the switch.
I'll put the expression as the value of the day.
OK, now I will have certain cases, for example, cases one, so one one would mean we are talking
about what what we want to do when the days when musically I want to print the money, OK?
And in each case, it is important to have a break statement as well, right?
That break statement takes us out of the way to look like here, OK?
But if you don't break it, it is going to execute the next case.
I'm just going to show you an example.
You have Monday, Tuesday.
Break, you have Wednesday, followed by a break.
We'll get to each statement end with a semicolon to the outage one statement.
Break is another statement, though you can have them in a single line as well, right?
So that is not the issue.
A list core business, maybe three four times.
OK.
Three.
Wednesday is Ford Thursday.
5:00 is Friday.
And care exists.
Hmm.
OK.
And we also have a default case, OK, maybe you want to give something, or maybe it was it is not
giving something like 13.
Maybe you can ask the user and a valid input.
And maybe we can have case seven for 10 days, but.
And we go to break here.
Now let me show you how this is going to work.
Maybe see I can see end of Switch, but that's not required.
Let's build this code and let us try to run this one.
Maybe the days five.
So I get done today is Friday, OK, the day is, let's say, nine, so I get and provided input.
Now what is the meaning of the default case?
So it is going to execute when none of the case is going to match, OK?
And what is the significance of the brief statement?
I suppose if I don't put a brief statement at three and I don't put a brief statement out for, OK,
let us see what is going to happen if I give the input as, let's say, three.
What?
I'm going to do it.
I'm going to get Wednesday, Thursday, Friday.
That means.
All the cases below Wednesday that executed until you find a break statement to get the marching is
going to happen today is three, so it is going to look at OK, is it three?
Is is it redone?
There is no.
Is it redone?
There is, yes.
And it is going to execute all blocks of code until it finds a big statement.
OK, so it stops here Wednesday, Thursday, Friday.
That is why putting the brake statement is important in each block of code.
All right.
That's all for this video, and I hope you understood the Switch guest blog as well.