Hello, everyone.
So in this video lecture, we rebuild a very simple calculator using which case, let's see how we can
do it.
So the idea here is you will give him give us some input so it will give input in the form and in digit.
Followed by an operator, which is going to be a character, for example, plus minus multiply or divide
up modulus on, followed by another integer, let's it later, this is it.
I would like to output 13 right in this.
Now, the way you're going to do it, input, you're not going to give it like this, you're going to
give five plus five, followed by space, followed by operators, followed by space and followed by
three OK.
We are going to read three different numbers.
We want to take everything.
Like, if you want to take everything without spaces, then you will have to create a strange object
to store it and you have to participate.
But for now, just to simplify our work, we are going to take in, put a number and it would be a connected,
which we call as operator and maybe the number, let's indicate.
So, operator, let's just call it as OPD so they can put a followed by the operator, followed by the
number B will put the operator inside the switch.
Exploration and based on the value of this operator, we will do some work, so we will have a case
for less.
So what will the old A-plus be and unbrick?
OK, if it is minus?
We will do see out a minus B and oil and break employed multiply.
Well, to see out a into B and and break, maybe another is modulus, you can handle the remaining cases
by yourself again to see out a more or less B and and and break.
OK, and for something else, you're going to default.
Please enter a valid.
Operator.
So this message will be displayed to the user if he gives invalid input.
So let's build it.
And now let us try to underscore.
So we have dodged large.
Maybe I give five plus three.
I get it.
Great.
Maybe I give 6:44.
I get 42.
Great.
I give it minus three.
Five.
OK.
On eight models, three two grades, it is working fine for the four cases that we have written.
And if I give nine divided by three, we have not handled this case.
So it gives us please enter a valid operator.
OK, so we could have done it using it felt also, but using which case made the code more cleaner,
cleaner and easier to write as well?
OK.
That's all for this video.
Thank you.