Everyone in this lecture, I'm going to talk about C++ drinks, and in order to understand the concept
of a string glass, we need to have a rough idea of a brief idea of object oriented programming will
get to do.
We do have a section on object oriented programming in this course.
But what ooops helps us, it helps us to define Real-World entities in terms of objects.
For example, you want to define a paintbrush which might be needed for a paint application in your
system.
And what?
This Bainbridge cannot.
It can have a certain state.
And it can have a certain behavior to OK, the state means the data it knows about itself.
Can you think of any dumps, I mean anything related to the crash?
Of course, a plane crash can have a certain color.
It can have a certain size.
It can have maybe some other properties as well.
Maybe the kind of connected it has or something like that, OK?
Or how what would be the stroke rate and something like that?
And it can have certain behavior like it can paint.
OK.
And maybe we can change the color of the paint brush that might be a method available on this paintbrush.
Maybe we can reset the paint brush to the default size and color.
Maybe that could be a method, right?
What we are trying to say is that using the concept of object oriented programming, we can define glasses.
The glasses actually kind of a template which as in which you can define certain properties and you
can define certain behavior, OK?
But this does not mean a paintbrush, so a paintbrush is created when you create an object out of it.
OK.
So we learn the concept of glasses and we will learn about the concept of objects.
And we will deal with object oriented programming.
So I'll just tell you how this is done.
Maybe you guys use OK.
It is a paintbrush be.
And all this brush has certain colors, so you can see we color.
This is equal to red.
OK.
And then you guys, OK, I want to paint using the red color so you will be docked, OK?
What I'm trying to tell you is that when we are going to work with strings, we are actually going to
create strings like this.
The string is a predefined glass will create a string.
And we call this thing as an object.
OK.
And this object is of the type, strings or type.
Is this like a data type, but it has some additional functionality inside it.
So this has some built-in methods which are defined inside a string glass.
And this is defined in a header file called It's up as part of the C++ standard template library framework
and will include it using harsh include string.
OK.
Now, instead of calling standalone functions and passing them the data, we will say I want to do as
dart.
Maybe it is.
Maybe I want to erase something inside this particular string.
Maybe some index.
OK, now this is weird.
Object oriented programming is going to come, so we will not have a function like it is, and we are
passing it a string and then sending it somewhere and we will do as though it is OK.
Whenever you see a syntax like where you have some variable name or object name, followed by Dart,
it is an operated and this is a function or a method.
OK.
OK, now just try to see this is actually object oriented programming, so though we have not learned
yet.
But I'm just telling you that we would be using functions in this particular style when we are going
to start with the strings in the next video.
And that's all for this video.
We'll look into the more details in the next lecture.