Everyone in this lecture, we're going to solve a problem where we have to complete this function uncomment,
OK, so what we would be given we would be given a string is and it would be no delay in the form of
a multi line comment.
For example, this string is in the form of a Maryland command, which begins with start leisure and
a start, and it does end with Dot in the box again in between.
It does have some content.
So we want to return a new string.
So the return type is string, which does not contain this command to give it does not contain this
thing right now.
How do we solve this problem?
So it's pretty easy.
One thing we can do is we can take some help from the inbuilt library methods.
One thing is we need to find out the location of star and box.
You cannot always assume that it would be odd those you don't index because there might be spaces in
the beginning, or you might have something like in the beginning.
For example, there is an empty space here.
OK, so it it gets shifted.
It is at some other index.
It does not add zero one.
What I can do, I can find out the index very easily using as defined method.
And I can tell you, tell me, where where do you find backslash with this start?
All right.
And also tell me, where do you find the last start and the backlash?
So that is a start and a box backslash then.
There are two different kind of tokens.
So we used the find function will get the first occurrence that is the index of this one and will also
get the index of this one right?
This is indexed to life, I try to show you what are these indices index one, they would be integers
as we know this is what the find function does return to us.
OK.
And let us just underscored by returning home testing for as of now.
And let me say, I want to run this function, remove comment helmet the index forward under the night
before corresponds to zero one, two, three and four.
So it gives me the starting index of backslash.
And it also gives me the starting index of this dot, which is 18 in this case.
And this is for what I want to do.
I want to remove this part of the string.
I want to just get this part of the string, which which is useful for it.
So clearly, we are looking at this problem.
We are extracting a small string from a bigger string so we can take help off the substring method so
we can see as dark.
Sub SDR, OK.
And it does accept the starting index and the Lento, guess what would be the starting index?
Obviously, the starting index would be four plus two, right?
So what is this?
So it would be six.
That would be index one.
Let's do right on what would be the length.
How many characters I do need to pick from the starting index.
That would be nothing but this index that is index two.
And you subtract.
This basically this index, right?
So you will get the length as well.
So what we can do is the length would be nothing, but if I just show you this is 18, right and this
index we got for, we don't need four, we don't need five.
So effectively from Index six will index 17, we need everything, right?
So how many letters do we have?
17 minus six plus one, which is 11 and 12, right?
We need to have 12 letters so we can do 18 minus four minus two, right?
So effectively we can set the letters nothing but index two minus Typekit.
That is the length of the string that we need.
And that's it, that's it.
So let's see if it does work as we are going to uncommitted.
And let's try to run the good.
Yes, it does work, so we are getting the output as Helloworld, which is working perfectly fine.
You can have a bigger string and you can have some dogs.
You can have some spaces.
It's if it does work in this way as well.
Yes, it does work.
It is able to uncomment the entire string.
OK, that this is how cool it is to work with the string methods and make our work a lot easier when
solving problems.
And that is why I asked you to go through some of the functions which are available on because they
are going to help you in solving problems.
That's all for this video.
Thank you.