Everyone in this lecture, we're going to work with C++ strength and word of C++ strength.
Let's look at the C++ strengths of the objects, which are created from string class, and it is available
in C++ Standard Template Library.
The C++ provides us a library of data and containers which contain the implementation of different datacenters
like arrays, reactors, Linklaters type maps and also provide various in-built algorithms like sorting,
searching techniques and a lot of other functions.
So now what we are going to do, we are going to use this library to create a string.
And let me tell you why it is powerful, more powerful than their noisy style string.
And first of all, it is continues in memory like a character did it, and it does internally use a
character ready to store some data inside.
OK, let's say we created a string.
OK, and we select stringers and this is equal to.
This is internally going to create an attack, and it is going to put Halo inside a one very powerful
advantage of using stringers.
It's dynamic.
We saw the character that it had a fixed sites.
The site was fixed, but now it can grow and shrink in size during runtime.
Now trending news and I want to dig in and put in what is Helloworld, what it will do.
It will automatically manage the space for this edit and it will allocate more memory so that you can
store a bigger string or GIF.
How and this internally happens.
We are not going going to dive into those details yet, but the behavior is very similar to how of attributes,
OK?
So again, all these things will cover when we go into the details of as a judge, when we know about
vectors, how dynamic it is growing.
So it is just a dynamic that can grow and expand during runtime.
That is what you need to remember at this moment.
And of course, they are better than corrected.
It is because correct, but it is have a limitation of fixed safe.
OK, and that might be problematic for us and does a lot of useful member functions.
No need to write functions from scratch.
OK, and this drink, it's it does come with its own behavior.
OK, for example, you have an alarm clock, OK, and you want to perform certain functions on it.
Maybe you're going to alarm or said, you say, OK, maybe I want to set the alarm for five a.m. the
way we're going to call functions.
We are going to use this dart operator, OK?
An alarm is type of an object.
And it does have a method when we use object oriented programming concepts, we call functions like
these because these functions, they are bound with these objects or they can work with these objects.
Similarly, string is an object and it comes with own functions of its own.
So you can say, OK, tell me the length of the string.
Tell me I wanted to search the string inside this particular string.
OK, we'll look at various functions, which can be which we can use, and we don't need to write a
lot of code from scratch.
We can directly use the functionality that is available to us and to make the things more natural.
They do support operators like Plus equal to less than greater than double equals and gives off character
that is bizarre, that we have to use a function like string compare.
OK.
Which compares to strings.
But here you can directly see whether this string is one in.
This two article is string as greater than S2.
You can directly use operators, which is more natural for us, OK?
And they are safer to use because they also provides methods for bone checking, for example.
I will give you an example.
Now, this is a big problem with corrected.
It is now.
Suppose you have an attic, which is of some size, and if you even try to exist this index, it is
outside the boundary of the correct that.
It still might give you some value.
That means there is no bone checking that is happening with character areas, but strings, if you try
to access a character, it is out of the bones they're going to throw you some at a rock.
Let me just give you this thing in demo as well.
Maybe it's create a string as that is.
Hello.
And let me create a character study, let's say, as to.
And I say, OK, I want to create this array of letters, I have five or letters, I have six, and
I want to initialize this with the word Hello.
OK.
Now we have initialized a string, which is part of.
The string header file contains a string glass, and we define the data type string, which is actually
a glass, and we created an object.
OK, now what I'm going to do, I want to access a particular letter so I can use s of index using the
Square Records or I can use it.
So I do the method which tell me what what letter is.
Does he know the index?
So maybe I can say we are in string and at zero the index, we might have some letter and something
we can do with the corrected three.
And I can say, OK, tell me what is their art?
Does he the Knicks right now?
What will give me the right answer because we are within the bounds of the string?
Let us try to run this Code of Nordschleife string demo.
And you can see both of them, they're the right little part of it, right?
There is one more function.
So either we can use art or we can use square records, they're fine.
So maybe.
Now let me ask, you could give me what is their art?
The A10X index.
And tell me what is did the eight index look?
Are.
Now it is it is giving me a warning, but it is not an error, OK, it is not an edit in this case,
which is OK, it's just giving us a warning, right?
Now you can see.
We got a random error.
There is an exception of the type out of the range, and this is coming from the string glass, OK,
and if I just commend escorted out if I don't use the string glass, though, it is a warning which
is generated by this caudwell children and you're going to we are getting a letter.
It's reducing the age and index.
You do have a letter.
Oh, OK.
It's not because of.
Yes, it is our date and it index.
OK, maybe it didn't.
I want to see what is there at the 80th index.
It still does work, OK, so this is actually an unsafe piece of code and we are not getting any of
it.
But here Discord is more safe because we are getting to know there is some problem that we are.
Something wrong with our approach.
So let me just show you.
And you can see the program terminate because it through an exception, because it's important to tell
the programmer that you are doing something wrong.
That is why I'm telling you that it's it's more safe.
It does provide methods for bone checking.
So that brings it will go.
And what about strengths in the next video?