Hello, everyone.
So in this lecture, we'll talk about strings on, we'll talk about how we can initialize a string or
guess what?
There are so many ways and I might be covering a few of them so you can create an empty string as one
and you don't give any value that is OK.
You can also create a string on in curly brackets, which is also known as initialize it list.
You are.
You have given a string literal to what it is doing.
It is copying the letters from a read only memory where this string little is created in the inside
of string object, which contains a character.
OK, so the halo is being copied inside a string object.
And you can also say that, OK, I want to create a string using another string object, which is OK,
so you are initializing A3 using is to.
Are you going?
OK, I want to create a string is forward in which I just want to read the first three letters.
So it is going to create a string called AGL when I return here.
Or you can do OK, I want to create a string from S2 and I only want to read from zero till the second
index, like before the second index.
It is going to store zero and one that does it and.
Get.
And there is also another initialization, which is the constructor based initialization.
So let me also show you that.
So in this case, we have as food on in round brackets we have written somewhere.
That is what we can do.
Or we can still get some long, long string and we can take only the first 12 letters of this string.
There is another initialization in which we are saying that we have created a string and we want to
repeat this x ten times.
That is what I was trying to show you here.
So repeat this a few times.
So it is going to create a string like this.
And so on, Rachel, maybe you can try to play with some of these initial positions.
And let's see how we can do it, OK?
So bring in a demo or TPP.
So first of all, include your string.
And.
We have.
A string s and maybe I can say hello, this is kind of initialization list.
And if the string is to.
And I said this is equal to.
Helloworld, that is also OK.
Again, the string is three.
And I'm saying you can make this from S2 that will also work, and I can do string as foot in curly
brackets.
I can say as to that will also work.
So if I do see S1 S2.
As trainers for all of them are going to work fine, right?
Let's build a quote.
It's getting built.
And let me show you dog's leash.
Bring them all.
String initialization demo, the halo, followed by hello to all of the initial visions, they are correct
and maybe some more ring is five and I can say, OK, I want to repeat a number eight times and the
number is.
Or the stringers, let's say hi.
OK.
This will not work, so it is expecting a corrected here, though maybe it's.
Now, if I show you it's it's repeated eight times as that is what was shown here as well.
So you can give a letter and you can repeat it.
You can also say, OK, I want something from a certain index up to a certain length, right?
So which is an example here, OK?
And this is actually instead of feeding the character, you can also give the integer value.
Maybe you can say I want string as six and I want to repeat 10 times.
The letter is it so is having a value?
Sixty five?
Let me show you show you right now, we have not printed it so out as six and.
It it will still work, it will get so many years.
All right, so there are so many ways of initializing strings.
So one thing I wanted to inform you was that you can also create a string S7 and later on you can say
this was initially high on later on.
You know, this is actually by, OK, this operation of assignment, this is supported in strings.
And it was not reported and corrected, it is what is happening is that this equal to operator is going
to copy all the letters of this string, literally from a read only location to inside a reader, this
president and say the strange object because of this functionality is part of the string glass.
It's not like a magic is happening.
It's being written for strings inside the string glass, which we have included from the header file,
right?
So now let me show you that this is actually no, but that means you can update the strings.
You can also do concatenation you can see as seven equals seven plus.
Goodbye, MacGyver, right?
Maybe something something like that.
We are.
Going back home, maybe something like that.
Or maybe you can do multiple editions as well like this.
Now we are concatenating will give you are doing the concatenation, and it's very natural, we are
doing it using the plus operator, right?
Seven, we have updated.
Let's build a God.
And let me show you the output, so maybe we are going back home so you can see this is possible because
the strings, they have a dynamic nature, they're able to grow and shrink in size because internally
that is managed by the string glass.
How does getting managed?
That is not our concern at this moment.
We are just getting comfortable with those and takes off things, OK?
So I hope you got to know how to create things, how to work with strings on.
In the next lecture, we'll see some more functions of input and output, even the next video.