Hello, everyone, in this lecture, we're going to see how do we work with input using strings?
OK, so we have seen how to input characters, how to input character at ease, and now we are going
to see how do we take input from the user and put it inside the string object?
OK, now one thing we're going to do is maybe I can string input demo and we are going to use some of
the code.
As a boss, we have created a string on instead of initializing it what we want, we want to take user
input.
Maybe I can say, bring me.
And I want you to seen me.
So let's see, does it accept the name correctly or not?
So maybe out high plus name.
And we have seen the plus operator does work with those translate.
OK, we have.
Yeah, this is fine.
And maybe I can say dodge lasting input, though, so it's waiting for names, so I can say the nodding.
And it only gives me the first word, OK?
The same issue we did solve it corrected.
It is as well.
So Sign does not read once it sees us space.
OK, so that that means we need some other method to read these strings, which are which do contain
spaces, OK?
The scene will not work.
It does not work with strings containing spaces.
It will just go into doubt and will use a function which is actually known as guideline on guideline
function can be used in two ways.
So in the first, it accepts this in object.
It uses the scene object to read something and then it tries to store it inside.
And the object that have to give because we are saying, OK, I'm going to read something from the user
and not input would be copied inside it.
Now, if you don't put it, will fix of an issue.
And if I give the name to the Ignite and it does read the entire name book including spaces as well.
Now, another way of doing it, maybe you are interested to read a paragraph, maybe.
Some paragraph which is extending multiple lines right down, there is no such way of giving this input,
so I've got a paragraph as we hit a new line.
The input reading it does terminate because what we want.
We don't want to store at the new line.
We want to stop and maybe some other character that is little toilet or not something like that.
It's totally your choice where you want to stop.
Now you can do it.
I want to read everything until I hit the dollar.
OK, maybe I got maybe some, some dollars, maybe one one two two, three, three or four or five six
on some string hello.
And then I have a dollar or it is going to read everything until you don't see your dollar.
So this little is known as a delimited.
And by default, if you don't pass anything, it assumes this to be a box lesson.
Or if you tell, No, I don't want the starboard box lesson, I want to stop at it.
It does acknowledge that, OK, so that is another way of using the Great Line function.
I hope are reading input is now clear.
So what we have seen till now is not if you want to read a character you use seeing Dot Gate, which
reads as in the letter, if you want to read a character you do use seemed odd.
Great line method, which we have seen.
And if you want to read a string you don't use, not get like you actually use a method great line which
does accept string and a fine object, which is being input to this method.
OK?
So these are different ways of reading strings that we have seen so far.
And I hope you understood this one, and that's all for this video.