I saw one very cool thing about strings is that it supports a lot of operators, which make the comparisons
very natural.
For example, you can compare two strings using equal to.
You can check if it is greater than or equal to or less than equal to all you can do concatenation.
And you can also have plus equals two, which is also a very cool operator.
Let me show you an example.
So we have two strings.
We are reading those and we are comparing them if they're equal or if one of them is greater or if that
is not the case, the other must be greater.
Because we have done is one is greater.
That means as one comes after S2 in the dictionary or a little bit.
So that is what we are writing it.
So let me show you the code and I can give you an example.
Let's say hello, and these are two strings.
Both are equal.
It's a halo, followed by word.
Obviously, halo comes before word in the dictionary.
Also, Halo is smaller, and if I have ABC, ABC, the ABC comes after ABC because this has an Oscar
value that is 97.
The smiley on whereas the capital as Osceola, 65, actually, the comparison is between the Oscar values
of the letters, and that is why you're seeing this kind of behavior.
So you can also have a string some name that is equal to, let's say, a Prateek and you want to append
something to it, either you can to name equal to name plus or not.
And that is my last name.
Or you can also use the Plus equals two operator.
To do the same thing.
So let me just show you.
So you're going to be pretty followed by noting that is what is the output?
And you can also do string name plus equals to last name, so maybe string last name that is not an
and name plus equals last name.
This is again a very cool operator, so that means you're doing concatenation.
And if I just see code name here, it will work as expected.
It.
One one critique, followed by nodding.
I hope you did understand these operators, which can which are very handy to use on strings.
And that's all for this video.