Hello, everyone, so in this video, we're going to talk about privacy, and I'll just give you a quick
idea of how we can a voice on a connectivity vs. traversal on a string.
OK.
First of all, let's I have some GoDaddy, and let's say this in this, we are storing a string, let's
say.
Inside an during the string, according minutes, and I suppose I won't do I dread over this entirely
on print everything later so I can default and I go lose it.
Tell what what lengths United, so either I compute the land of the city.
I can say I then is still alien of name.
I this place and I can to see out the name of why that is like one option of doing the iterations.
Let me just build a code and let me show you the output.
So.
We're going to we are able to iterate over all the strengths, which is what is actually happening at
the plant.
Let me just tell you.
It is during this string, hello, and that is getting stored inside your character, so you have zero
h one e two, you have the index, you have a water index, you have oil on on the fifth and next you
will actually have a which is created by the string copy function.
Now we are saying that we want to hydrate less than lend lend of this world is actually five.
We are saying that Ireland is vital when we want to trade less than land.
OK, so that means we are retreating from the index zero.
So that is what we are getting the right set of characters that we want.
We don't want to print none or the other way of doing it as you copy the same code and use it all.
I don't want to use the lend function.
I want to settle name of I.
This is not equal to.
This is also why so sometimes you will find this way of doing that reversal, and it will still produce
the same output.
Let me show it to you.
So both of them, they produce the same.
So what we are doing, we are iterating over an edit later, by later, and that's what the output is.
Now let us also discuss how we can trade over a string.
The one day theme, the string is actually a collection of characters that I've been a string object.
Or maybe I can do string name that is quoting minutes and I want to.
I trade it so I can do for intake will do zero starting from zero.
The.
I want to go tell what I need.
And so what function we will use.
Instead of calling the Stirling Albion method, we will use named Portland.
Now this is a method that is built on string object.
And this is how we can use this method.
And I can see out.
Name of a and that again, we are going to get.
The same, so we cannot use the same video, but maybe I can say name.
One named one unnamed one, right?
So.
OK.
Instead of putting it in, we should put maybe a comma or whatever.
And you and I I'll tell you one more way of doing it.
Just hold on for a minute.
We are still getting the same.
You can see that reversal is pretty much the same, right?
And there is also a loop with Disney on ice for each loop.
What it does, it hydrates over all the letters on.
Let me show you this index right now you're iterating over correct.
So you will create a bucket which will temporary hold one letter at a time.
You can say some x and I want to iterate over name one, which is a string, right?
So I can to see outtakes.
So it's all going to hold one character at to it.
It is automatically going to iterate over each element of this object of this string, which is a character,
right?
And now you're going to still we are getting the same output.
So this is a faulty loop that is another way of doing the traversal, right?
And maybe if you say, no, I don't want to iterate over this as a character that I want to iterate,
but I will interpret everything as an integer.
So you're going to index that isn't right.
Name one.
Instead of getting the characters, we are going to get the ASCII values of all the letters right.
Let me show it to you.
Now we are getting the Oscar news off all the numbers with the president in this right.
These are a few ways in which you can reverse either on the character ready or on a string, and that's
all for this video.