Everyone, so I hope you have got some idea of working with String, so I'm just going to show you the
documentation on C++ dot com and you can have a look.
There are so many methods that this string class does support.
There is a method, a pencil.
If you want to add something to the string, it can.
It can be used, OK.
So there are examples as well, so you can add a new string.
You can say, OK, I want to add up to five letters, so dots would be added something like that.
Or you can play with this.
OK, it's a very easy function that you can play with.
So our function we have already seen it gives us index are the particular letter, and we also have
some other functions like resolve or our find.
Or so I'll give you an example.
Let's talk about the sub string function.
It generates a newly new constructed string with its value initialized to a copy of substring of this
object.
What is a substring?
Even a bigger string?
A part of the string is a substring we'll give, for example.
This is a bigger string, and I'm saying, will you give me a string which starts from the third index?
So zero, one, two and three?
Basically, it starts from deep and it contains up to five letters.
That is what this sub string method is going to give us.
And we can also use the find function were to look at where a particular world is located, at what
index it is present, so we can also use that.
So you can see there are so many methods, and I would suggest you go through some of these methods
on your own.
And I will show you some examples where we can use these methods to solve problems in the next video.