Hello, everyone, in this lecture, I want to talk about a few important methods that are available
with the C style strings.
So what have been upgraded or corrected?
And what I want to calculate the length of this that, okay, how many characters it has in Bluecoat
trillion.
This is a function that is available, and they can give the name of dairy the name of the character
credit for which I want to do this work.
So if I show you the output, it gives me five.
So you can see it has five letters.
And if you talk about storage, it actually has six letters because it is also note that we need it.
Okay, so that is the first function that we have seen.
If we want to calculate the length, we can use the Australian function.
The next function is string copy.
If we want to copy one string to another, this string, we can easily do it using string copy function.
We don't need to write off our look to do the work so we can just string copy copy the value of A to
B.
OK, so the first parameter is their destination.
But if we want the word and the second is the source.
So if they copy it from the value of A to B, and if I do see Old B, you can see B them to string.
But if I print B to here, I can see it will contain the word apple.
OK.
So you can see it contains the word apple, and that's how the string copy function works.
And obviously it is doing it later, later and it is going to take linear time.
So we have seen string copy.
The third is string compared.
So string compared basically tells us whether two strings are equal at night so I can check.
I can compare.
And B So if if all the letters match, this function is going to return zero.
So let us see what happens.
So yes, it is giving us a zero because both the strings are equal and if it is not equal, it will
give us plus y not a minus one.
So let us say let us add something to the B, so maybe I can see I can use this string concatenate function
that is that goes by the name S.T.A.R.T..
I want to concatenate two strings.
Maybe I can say, let me show you one example here.
So let's say God.
Web equals do W W W and Gad domain equals to.
Letter calling minutes.
Dot com.
I want to concatenate these two into one so I can to code SDR.
Eddie and I can to web and domain, and let's see.
And you can see we're getting W W W coding minutes.
Dot com.
OK, maybe I'll put a dotted.
And now we can see.
We are able to concatenate these two things now, I can also compared this string.
With with so this this is going to output a string and I can copy this value inside me, I can just
drink coffee this drink and to be OK, so let's see what happens now.
And if I do see or be here, it would be me would take the value coding when it start going.
OK, so we ask Non-coding when it start.
Come on, I can compare this with Apple, so I can this out string compared and b now this output will
not be zero.
It would be something else.
Let me show it to you.
So this output is actually negative.
OK.
And if I change this order, become a it would be positive, I guess.
So, yes, it is minus 22 and it is plus 22.
So it basically returns a positively or negatively or a zero.
OK.
So in three directions, this string compare can go.
And if you're interested in actually knowing how this value is computed, I will not tell you, go to
their documentation and read about what more functions are available.
And with this, see style strings.
OK, go and read about it on the web.
OK.
That's all for this lecture.
Thank you for joining.