Everyone in this lecture, we will see one example how we can use stained glass.
So if you look carefully, there are a lot of functions that this string glass provides.
So I'm going to show you one example that is very useful, though string also has functions like push
back bob back.
If you want to add some character at the end of the string, then you can use push back function.
This operator is used if you want to access the iith connector.
Inside a string insert is to insert something in the middle of the string front gives you the first
character.
There are a lot of functions, but one function that is very powerful and it can be used in solving
problems.
Also, that is the main function.
For example, you are given a paragraph and you want to search a particular word inside this particular
string.
But this this whole thing is a big string.
It's not a vector, it's not a list.
It's a paragraph.
Let's see how this find function works.
So I took one word.
I dig into that word, and now I want to find this word inside this paragraph.
So what I can do, I can see out paragraph dot find and I give the word it, OK, I want to find the
location of this world inside this particular paragraph.
Let's see what happens in this case.
Yes.
So.
Look, these are warnings we can just ignore.
Or maybe let me just put it like this.
So let's see if I.
Run Discord now darts last spring, find and I give the word to isstill, then it says it is President
Dad, the 22nd and so zero one two three four five six seven.
This dislocation is the 22nd index, so this is where the world is still is present.
But now you may ask, you know, I want to find the next truck rental, so maybe I can say OK, or let's
say there is some word, but is not there.
If I say, OK, God, then you can see I'm getting a very, very large number.
So this large number is actually the largest number for fought for unsigned integer value.
OK, so this can be stored inside a variable of their type size underscored B and begin to index.
OK, this index will be equal to.
This index is equal to minus one.
If you convert this unsigned integer into assigned one, OK, you can say this is the case you're going
to see out string not found.
So this this is actually if you convert it into individuality, let's say this could build this, this
works and we are converting or unsigned long into a signed integer and that values equivalent to minus
one.
So if I say if this is the case, then it will this string not found.
So you can say, if I give God it says string not found, if I give are learning, then it is present
and I don't get any output.
So if it is not equal to minus one, then we can say, OK, it is dead.
So you begin to if index is not equal to minus one.
Then maybe I also want to find the next occurrence now, what I can do, I can do it.
We found a first occurrence at this particular location.
Then if they still find the still in the remaining part, then I can do okay.
It's pretty easy.
If your index is not equal to minus one, I can see out maybe first occurrences I did.
That is index on for the second occurrence, I can say index is equal to paragraph, not find word.
And here they give the index index plus one that means not looking one index after all.
Three.
Plus the length off.
Or maybe we can start judging from this dislocation two.
Which is fine index plus one that is perfectly fine.
And again, if index is not equal to minus one, I can to see out.
We were second occurrence that is equal to.
Again and.
So let us try to run this cold, and I can still first us it into that 22 seconds it into that 35.
This is how I'm doing it.
But now I'm going to give you an assignment in the next coding challenge what you need to do.
You need to find all occurrences of a given word inside a string.
OK, so this you will solve by yourself by using this fine method, and I'm leaving this as a homework
for you.
See you in the next coding talent.