Everyone in this lecture, we will talk about pointers and some related topics like address of operator
de reference variable reference variables.
This section is all dedicated to some C++ concept neither.
You may not find this concept in other languages, so pointers is one of the most powerful, as well
as one of the tricky and confusing things in the NCR Plus Plus language as well.
But I will try to make this easy for you so that you can understand and apply these concepts.
OK, so firstly, we will begin with a very small operator which has been noted using and you might
have seen this operator in some other places as well.
So this is an armed operator, so actually, this island comes at multiple places.
One is, if you want to do a bit why?
For example, if entry.
Then you must have seen this operator OK, so this is basically for Budweiser.
But there is another use case.
Suppose you have a variable X.
OK.
And it is storing some value that certain access a bucket in the memory under the storing some value
and this bucket may have some address later.
This addresses two zero one eight six.
This is a number.
OK, now when you are going to do something like this, let's say we are going to print and affix.
That means give us the address of the buckets.
So this is where this address of operator fits in.
So this island of X is basically the address of X.
OK.
So if you bring this value, you will get this output.
Two zero one eight six OK.
And then when you print and address or gives when you print and address, that number is printed as
an extra decimal number.
So you may see something like zero x if maybe something like this, or maybe one to something like this,
this zero x denote it's a hexadecimal number that means the base is 16 because it is written in a 16
base format.
OK?
So we are just converting one in digit that is in base 10 into base 16.
So you can this is the default behavior.
OK, so then you will do something of and of X.
You will see this kind of address output on the screen.
And I will show you one example as well.
The third use cases in creating a different variable that we will see a little later on.
OK.
But yes, there also we will see this use off.
And right now we are going to talk about this use case that is the address of a patent.
OK.
So as I said, OK, what we can do to get the address of a variable, we can use the address of a operator,
for example, index.
Then if you do and of X, this will give you the address.
OK.
And this address is not stored right now later on.
What we can do We can store this address in a special kind of a variable that is known as a pointer
variable.
OK?
I will show it to you with the help of one example.
So what's your address?
You can ask any variable by using that.
And so let's see one demo.
So let us see one example here.
Let's extend and I'm going to do Scott, and of course.
So let's see the output.
So we are going to run this large, large address of.
Yeah.
Dot slash.
So we can see we are getting this address here that is zero six, six one, maybe a foot effort favorite.
So this is a Hexham decimal address and not just integers.
You can also have some float wherever the memory.
Is there, and it will definitely have some addresses already stored in memory and all memory will have
certain address so I can look out and of and and you will see we would have a different address for
way.
OK.
The one interesting thing to note is.
They are just four bites of it, OK?
In memory, what happened is we have a bucket, right?
And we have a bucket here.
We are storing it and here we are storing afloat.
So this is taking four bites and this.
But as you can see, it is of this is 58.
This address is 58 and this is 54.
OK.
There are differences because because of this memory that is being given.
As for whites, it was this particular variable.
OK.
So I hope you really understood the concept of address of operator.
In the next lecture, we will talk about Pointer.