Everyone, so let us talk about pointers in the last lecture, we talked about the and operated, but
now we are going to talk about the pointed video, but look disappointed is a special kind of a variable
that holds the address of another variable look.
So earlier, what we saw, if we have a bucket X, this is of the type and then it has some value certain
and it has some address.
Let's say it was six eight zero four.
OK, then what we can do, we can store this address in some other bucket as well.
So this is two six eight zero four and this budget is, let's say, Expedia.
Then that means this bucket points to X or give you guys distorting the address of the budget X when
you're creating a pointed variable.
What do you need to do?
You need to have the same today as of for this bucket and put a start in between.
Okay, so you have to make the data tables instead.
If it is flawed, then you will make the point of the type lodestar.
OK.
So how do we do it?
So it's very simple.
So we have to create a x pointer, so let us define x pointer.
So instead, x pointed and it should contain some value.
OK, so either we can write it like this x point that should contain the value and of X.
That means it should contain this value, which is nothing but the address of this particular bucket
on what you can do.
So here what we have done.
We have done assignment.
We are assigning a value to this one variable.
We can also do initialization.
We can write and start Expedia.
And this is equal to and of X.
This is also valid.
So here we are using the address of variable.
And here we are using this dot to define the point that is index defined appointed data type.
OK, now you may also have seen started some other places.
OK.
So let us see where we have.
We are using start.
So one of this use gives us to multiply two numbers.
We do 515.
But here you can see we have to.
Two operators by the side, OK?
But here we have a day today, and here we have a variable name.
OK, so we can use stored as a pointer variable as well.
And one more use case that we will see is in the data print operator that we will see little, little
later on.
OK.
These are the two things we we will do later.
One is about reference variables and one is about data.
But for now, we are doing talking about this use case.
So what?
We have just seen winter.
To declare the point that we can use a streak that existed between the data type and the variable name,
here are few examples that show how you can create, appointed and hear this.
This is only the point that this is a double pointer, this is indeed the point that this is altering
disappointed regarding this basis.
You can have a space between Indian start and start and rebuild them as well, or you can ride it like
this and start followed by SpaceX and followed by VAR..
OK, so spacing is not important.
You can put space anywhere.
OK.
So that's what I wanted to tell you through this example.
So now let us see a quick demo of using appointed variable.
OK, so let's see.
I can see I want to store the address of X in a particular bucket.
The Great X Pointer.
And if I do, this is equal to and of X, this will store the address.
Now, if I do see out Expedia, then this value will be same as this value.
OK, this this these two outputs would be same.
Let me try to show it to you.
So you can see these two values are exactly same.
The one thing we can do is we can also do something like this.
We have x this list, and this is this is, let's say, ABC.
This address is stored here.
This is Expedia and now because it is stored inside the moment, and this may also have a certain address
later.
This addresses, if, I suppose, if I want to bring the address of appointed VAR. OK, then how I can
do it.
It's very simple.
We can again use the and operated followed by the name of the book.
It's the name of the book.
It is Expedia.
We can actually find out.
Address of a variable.
And begin to see out and off.
Expedia, OK, so this will give us a different address.
Now I should be willing to, if so, I should put the the.
OK, now let me run it again, and you can read the full two values, our theme, this values a little
different.
OK?
This fellow's little different.
So now you may ask or give what if I want to store this, if in some other bucket?
OK, then what?
What is going to happen?
You need to create maybe a pointer to a pointer so we can say x Expedia.
OK, so and what would be the data?
Whatever you have heard, you should have this data Typekit, followed by the start in between.
So it would be a pointer to a pointer variable.
So let's see.
Let's try to create a pointer to a pointer we can see in stats DOD, Expedia, Expedia.
This should be equal to and off Expedia.
OK.
And see out I can see x Expedia.
And.
Now, if I run this code, you can see the first to put that same, and the second reports are saying,
OK, that means in the first two outputs we are printing.
This value undervalued, these two are the same, then we are bringing this value in this value.
These two are saying, OK, so I hope these concepts of pointers are now clear to you.
We have seen how to create a pointer variable and we have also seen how to create a pointer to a pointer.
OK, so that's all for this lecture.
Thank you.
See you in the next lecture!