Everyone in this lecture will talk about the difference operator, which is also the note reducing us.
So till now, we have seen multiple use cases, a start one use case in multiplying two numbers and
their use case when you create a pointer variable look.
For example, you create data type followed by a star, followed by some pointed variable.
This is another use case, and the third use case we are going to look at is our data put in as a different
operator.
OK?
So let's see what does this or different operator does?
And we have also talked about that if you do and and of some bucket.
OK.
And of some bucket, let's say we have a bucket index.
Equals ten, so X is a bucket which contains a value then.
And this is that in the memory, and if you do end of X, this gives you the address of that particular
bucket.
OK.
So basically, this D reference operator works in the exactly opposite manner.
What what it does, it takes an address.
OK.
So you do start of some address.
And it will give you the bucket.
OK, so this is what you need to remember about and and be a plant operator.
So.
This is it, OK?
I will give you one example now, if I do, OK, if I have, let's say.
And starred retired.
Equals two and of X, that means BP is storing the value of a treasure of its excess storage summer
dress.
ABC exit this ABC is the address of X, then BP are well stored.
ABC.
OK.
And if I said what would be the output if I print out the idea?
What I'm going to get, I'm simply going to get a mixed output, but if I do see out.
Sort of pretty.
OK, now you're going to be using the start operated with address.
So Peter is address the start of some address will give us the bucket and what is the bucket X?
And if you do Code X, what you will get, you will actually get the value that is there inside the
bucket.
So you're going to get an OK.
I hope you are now able to understand the difference between doing media and sort of media.
OK, so here we are using a star to create a pointed variable, but here we are using Star as a beta
French operator.
OK?
So this is our Data France operator.
This is the meaning of beta fencing.
If you want to access a value through its address, then we will use different operator.
OK?
All you can do is if I say End of X will give me the address, and if you put a stop to it, then then
also you will get the same result.
It would be nothing but your first finding the address, then using Star are finding the bucket so effectively
this is equal to X only.
OK.
This will give you the value that is resident and X.
So if you do something like this, then you will get.
Then there's the outward, OK, so this is what this different operator does.
So what we have learned is that pointers can be used to access the variable.
They point to directly OK, so Peter was pointing to X.
And through media, I can access the value of X by doing sort of media.
This is done by proceeding the Poynter name with their data print operator stored on.
This is also known as well-appointed to buy.
So this operator is also known as well-appointed Dubai.
So, yeah, this is what beat a print operator is OK.
So one small concept that you may know also noise.
Sometimes you will encounter a null pointer.
OK.
So for example, this is an example of an elbow in the U.K. So this.
We can't do it in a dress, but it is not binding to any work, so we can see if it is not binding to
anybody.
We can put this value zero.
So by default, this is garbage, but we can initialize this pointer with the value zero or we can initialize
it with the value.
Know what can happen if you try to do a difference.
This if you do start off beat, then you may get the segmentation fault.
You cannot be different and null pointer.
Okay, so this will give you a segmentation fault.
Of it, which is a memory related error, OK, because this address does not exist.
OK.
So that's another thing that you should know, and that's it for this lecture.
Thank you.