Everyone in the last lecture, we saw one example of possible reference using reference variables.
Now we can also achieve the same thing using pointers and data frames operated and using the address
of operator as well.
So we want to build a function what we do, which gets what is the total number of views for a particular
video right now?
And here is some logic which we'll skip.
And what we just want is the view count should be incremental by a value of one.
And this return can be made void.
OK.
So this should be void.
And we want to update this value so that the changes are reflected here as well.
OK?
But if you do something like this, you call this function what we do views.
And here you write music world views, +1 and you simply do see our views.
We know that this is not going to work because again, there are two copies one in Maine and one in
watch with your method.
And I can tell you also.
So if I do something like this, I get the same output.
Now I want to make this work.
So what I can do is I can say, let me show you what we can do here.
OK.
We don't want to make a copy, but what we can do, we can actually pass the address of this bucket.
And since we are passing an address, we need to point the variable here.
OK, let's call it as views on what we can call it.
As views pointed and what we can do using this pointer, we can update this bucket so we can to start
off use pointed equal to start of use point at +1 to whatever it is the old value increment that value
by a factor of one.
Now you would think what is going to happen?
So let me build a good answer to you.
So now you're going to doubt what is one zero one, it is working perfectly fine.
Let me explain your memory level what is happening in this case.
So this is I mean, and here we have this method in the mean we have this.
Variable, which is known as views on distorting of L200.
This is our variable here.
And we are trying to update this variable via this method, so when we call this method.
Watch video.
So we have in this dark frame, this is what we do.
And here we have a variable which can store the address.
OK, so it can store the address.
This variable is known as use pointer.
Uncensored is of the type, and this is of the type in start, you can see.
That means this will point to this because when you're passing this will you?
What is happening is inside of you is one that is getting equal to and of abuse.
That means does this during the address of this object to later this address addresses ABC viewers is
equal to ABC.
And here's what we're doing, sort of ABC what is sort of ABC, if we discussed.
If you do start with some address like ABC, that means we are talking about this book.
So this is actually called this bucket, which is the actual use, but bucket in the mean, and we are
creating this by a value fun.
OK?
Effectively using this address, we are changing this bucket by a value fund.
And you can see if you know, print views here.
You're going to get an output of one zero one.
OK, so this is how Barbara print works and we are passing up instead of passing the object, we're
passing the address and using that address.
We are directly making changes at that particular address using this be different operator.
So had we used all the operators?
This is a pointer variable.
This is a different operator.
And this is the address of operator.
OK?
Either you do this or simply use reference variables.
It's totally your choice.
I prefer using reference variables.
For most examples where I need to pass the object by reference.
OK.
So that actually made makes the code a little simpler and easier to understand, and we avoid this confusing
concept of pointers.
In that case, that's all for this lecture.
Thank you.