Everyone in this lecture will talk about reference variables.
OK, so this is one last topic that I want to discuss in this particular section on the reference video,
but this is a very powerful concept in C++, and it will allow us to pass objects by different OK.
Using this, we can pass objects by reference or some other functions very easily.
I will tell you what is this?
What does this mean?
OK, so the pass objects.
But if we had to, this one is us objects.
One way uses pointers and another way uses reference variables.
OK?
These two concepts are different concepts.
They're not exactly related.
OK, but it is important we understand the difference between these two.
The first let us focus upon this concept biasing object by reference using a reference variable.
OK, so now let me tell you that we will use this object around and we have already seen that this and.
Can be used in multiple places.
So one is being a bit resigned, for example, five entry.
And there is another address of operator and of some bucket.
Give us the address.
That is what we have seen.
And the third you case that we are going to look at, it is very initializing a reference variable.
OK?
So now let me tell you, for example, if you create a bucket, let's say index equal to 10.
And then you do something like.
And why?
Equals to X.
In this case, what happened is X is a bucket which contains the Wellington unwise, another bucket
which contains the Wellington, OK.
But instead, if you do something like this in NY equal to this, then let me tell you what is going
to happen.
If you ain't aren't very cold x, then y will not be a new bucket.
That means via index, they are the same bucket.
Okay, for example, you have a name.
OK, so let's say you have some name either home and your mother also gives you another name.
Maybe your friends call you with your nickname.
OK, if I call your name or if I call your nickname, that means I'm talking about the same person.
Similarly, X and Y are not two different buckets.
They are the name for the same memory.
So basically reference variables create another name or create an alias for the same object.
OK.
For the same object.
And when you're creating a different variable, they must be initialized.
OK.
You cannot do something like this.
You cannot do something like this in any way.
And I will do the initialization.
No, this is not allowed.
Whenever you are creating this reference variable, there must be initialized.
So in this case, we can see this VI is a reference variable.
It refers to the value of OK, it doesn't point the way it is.
It is X.
OK, so why is X and X's way?
So let me try to show you with the help of a simple program.
So let us do one thing, we have a bucket that is done, we create a different variable by.
And political do x, then if I do viable a plus and if I lose, see Old X and and if I do see out Y
and then the world output, you should expect, we should expect an output of 11 because both of them
are pointing to the odd the same, but they're not pointing to each other.
Both X and Y are the name for the same bucket.
So this is this is why this was done, then I do vibe less plus.
So this becomes irrelevant.
And if I print X and Y, I get an output as eleven.
The let me show it to you.
OK, let me just save this file with the name of.
Reference Tazi BP.
The slash.
Reference.
Now you going to be are getting this output of a living.
But suppose if I do x plus plus here, then both X and Y will change.
OK, so either you operate X Audio Broadway, both are going to change and it will look good first and
you can see the values are now.
Well, I hope you understood this concept of reference variables.
In the next lecture, we will talk about possible difference.