Everyone in this lecture will talk about possible defense using reference variables.
OK, so what I'm going to do, I'm going to show you one example I want to create a function void and
that will, let's say, applied x on my income.
Let's end and go.
I'm getting some income and I want to apply a 10 percent tax on my income and I want to see what is
the income that I will get after applying this particular tax, OK?
So this function is going to change my income by applying a 10 percent tax so I can say one minus 0.1
that is basically 0.9 into my income.
OK, OK.
Maybe I can say of lowered that percentage is.
So I have a little 10 percent x one minus x in low income.
OK.
All I can say.
Income minus income and do X.
So I subtract something from my income.
I pay some tax and that takes taxes 10 percent of my income.
And this income should ideally change.
Okay, so let's say we have this function.
So maybe I take an income as a input from the user is OK, let us apply tax on this particular income,
and I pass the income as a parameter to this function.
And if I do see out income, what I should expect here.
OK, what should I expected?
Should my income change or will not change?
Okay.
What we are doing here is we are doing buyers by value.
So I will tell you, what is this concept?
So as better friends, we are doing large slash buys, but often during reference variables to my income
is under peace.
And after playing Dexter, it is still giving me OK.
And what is the problem here?
The problem here is we are actually doing fast by reference, OK?
So also replaced by value.
What happened is when you're digging in, put your income, it is stored inside a bucket called income,
and when you're finding there's income or dysfunction here, you're creating another bucket that also
has an income.
OK.
And here this value is copied.
And when you apply this formula, this income is changed.
It becomes 90.
And in the mean, after calling this function, when you try to print income, you're actually printing
this income, OK?
So basically, there are two copies, OK, and this copy is there in the call stack of applied tax.
And this copy is there in the golf star of Mean in the main.
The actual copy is not changing.
You're changing the duplicate, you're changing the duplicate what I want instead of creating two copies,
I should only have one copy of income and I should get changed.
OK, so what we can do in that case is we can say we should pass this by reference so I can write and
and and to know what is going to happen is we we have a variable called in come here.
We also have a different variable income in this particular function, applied tax that is another name
for this particular variable.
OK.
It has.
A different school doesn't come as a different school.
It exists inside dysfunction, but the memory location that is there, it is shared with this particular
function.
OK, so if I know change and come here, then it is going to change, then come here as well.
So this will become led to Nairobi.
And let us see how this is going to work.
So if I build a code and if I run this.
And if I give good, you can my income after applying tax is rupees 90, that means we are working on
the same copy of the income.
So this is known as parsed by reference using reference variables.
And this is the most important use case of a reference variable that you will find across many functions.
OK.
And maybe if you don't want to call it as income, you can call it as money.
And here you can call it as money equals to money minus.
Money in tax.
OK, so let's build a code and let's it underscored again, so we are going to get the same output.
And yes, it is working as expected.
Now what did we do?
We had this rocket and come.
So initially, the program started from women, so the main goal stock was there.
Then we made a function called Applied X.
So we added one more function in the file stack that created a different variable money.
So the name money exists inside this function, and it is a different variable for this income.
So this income gets a name money.
Then we do some calculation we updated with 100 minus and it should be 90.
And then this call is over.
And this name is also destroyed.
And finally, when you print income, you will still see the output name.
But if you try to see old money here, you will not get any output, right?
Because this variable does not exist.
You will get a compilation error.
This money only exists when this function is called OK.
So this is the whole idea of teaching you reference variables.
I hope this is clear, and that's all.