Hello, everyone.
Welcome to this section on that is in this section, we will talk about our first date as a chair of
this course that is known as edit.
And it's a very simple, very useful data subject, and it has a lot of Real-Life use case as well.
So what is it?
So you must have learned about a variable in the programming language.
So what is a variable?
Variable is a bucket that stores some data.
For example, I want to store the number of friends I have.
I can create a number, a variable of the type in digit, and this variable will store, OK, I have
five best friends that will store this inside a particular memory.
But suppose we have something complex.
We want to store marks off students and we want to store marks of Let's 100 students, OK?
What we need, we need is a collection of elements.
OK.
We cannot create 100 variables.
But what we will create is an area.
OK, so let's create an area like this.
So we called this has little marks on each index.
OK, so this area is indexed from zero.
Let's see if it does having the size of 100.
Then these are 100 buckets which are lying linearly in the memory.
So this linear collection of elements is known as the last index would be 999, and we can say we have
100 buckets which are lined linearly in the memory.
Similarly, I can say this looks like an area off.
That's OK.
Instead of having a simple data type, we are having a different kind of day where each element.
Is it is of the type God and each God can have different attributes?
Maybe a god height, maybe a guard color, maybe a guard type, OK?
But for now, let's just focus on symbol symbol.
Let's say you want to store the marks of every student out of 100 may be destroyed in God.
Eighty nine.
This God 78.
This God 32.
This God of physics.
And so on.
OK, maybe this got 84.
So what will happen is how you're going to read the city, how you're going to write this very.
We're just going to sit down and you can access marks of any student by writing marks off I.
OK.
What are you going to do?
You can access the IoT market by using this notation marks of fire so you can perform different operations.
For example, you can read what are the marks of diet student?
You can update what are the marks of that student?
You can even output.
What are the marks of the IoT student?
Let us talk a little bit about areas, so it is a collection of elements of the same type list in a
continuous memory location.
OK, so these are the two important things you should remember.
The they should have elements of the same day, but in some other languages like Python, you can have
a Google.
Indeed, as a tourist card, as a list and list is heterogeneous in Python, OK?
But in C++ and in Java these areas, all the elements should be of the same type.
That means you cannot put a string and in digit inside the same eddy.
OK.
If you want to store data like this, you also need to convert this into a string.
Everything should be of the same type.
OK?
And they are placed in a continuous memory location.
That means each bucket is, let's say, if each reader is digging for bytes and if this address of the
memory is 100, then the next address will be one zero for the next, but would be one zero eight.
The next address would be one one, 12 and so on.
OK, so that means it is light linearly inside the memory.
OK, now we will look at how we can perform different operations on it, in how we can create input
output and update.
So one more thing I want to talk about is let us talk about correct that it is OK.
So in character.
Each character has a size of one bite instead of having this memory of size for bites like we have in
the case of our invaded, this memories of the type one bite.
OK, so if this but is hundred, the next day address will be one zero one.
The next address will be one zero two.
And this is how we can store our characters inside a particular areas.
So face.
OK, give me an idea of one.
So that means that even what we have it will print me, OK?
B, as a character, look at each position, we can store a single character and this can be any character,
OK?
So in an ideal case, we will see later.
Also, these character traits should be terminated by a special character that is known as another character.
OK?
So this is something you should not forget.
You should always put no character.
At the end of the victory, so we will see why it is needed and why it is helpful.
Let us talk a little bit about invigilators first.
So this court example shows you how you can create dirty.
So here we are, creating an area and we are telling the compiler that you should allocate.
Memory of.
How much space I need 100 boxes and sensors of the type in digit, each integer takes four bytes, so
it would be four and 200.
It will allocate a linear memory of 400 bytes when your program is being.
Come by, it'll get so the kind of education we are doing, it is known as static memory allocation.
We defining the size before the program is executed.
We are not defining the size on a random, so we had a statically allocating these eddies.
And here what we are doing.
We are creating error.
OK.
And it has elements.
And the first element of the error is initialized with zero.
So whenever you do an initialization?
OK.
So what happens is this is called the initialization list.
So in this list, we only defined the first element as zero.
So whenever do do do you will do initialization of inherit?
The remaining elements of the array would automatically becomes IDO.
OK.
So what would happen in the first case?
If you render that, you will see that this contains some random data.
So we call this random rate as garbage data, OK?
We have not done initialization.
If that is not initialized, it will contain garbage.
What will happen in this case?
So we have given three elements in the initialization list.
So we would have three elements whose values are one two three and the remaining element would be zero
automatically OK.
And what would happen in this case in this?
You can see we have not defined the size of the ADI.
OK.
So if you're given the initialization list, then defining the size is actually optional.
And what you can do is you can you will have only area of size three in which we have three elements
one two three, OK.
So you can also have array of complex data type, such as a string.
The string is a predefined data type, and string itself is an array of characters.
OK, so you can see this is a linear add strings.
OK.
On each string is also an array, so it's kind of a two, really.
So we will see this a little later on in this course.
OK, so just I'm telling you, you can also create array of some complex data.
So I hope this is clear.
How do we create and edit a now in the next you to really do some coding and see how we can input output
update and print entity?