Hello, everyone.
So in this module, we are going to talk about functions to functions as an important concept, so they'll
know what we were doing.
We were writing the entire code inside me.
OK.
And as your code is going to grow longer, maintaining that code is going to become difficult.
OK?
Or let me try two related with the example of a book later.
That is a book in which you have 500 pages and there are no chapters in the book, so it becomes very
difficult to read the book to maintain that book.
But now if I give you another book which has the same 500 pages, but those pages are divided into two
injectors.
OK, so which book you would like to read?
I guess most of you would answer we would like to read the book B because it is more modular, it is
more organized and it is easier to read and maintain the track right?
That is where the functions come into picture, because instead of writing a very large piece of code,
what we are going to do is we are going to divide our code into small small chunks, which are do the
same functionality.
But now that God would be more organized, more maintainable, more easy to relate to, this is one
one block of code.
This is another block of code.
This is another block of look to each of these blocks of code.
They have a specific theme or they have a specific functionality.
OK.
And we'll look at the example.
OK, so let's see.
How do we create the function?
Let me give you an example of a sample function.
What is the function of?
Function is a block of instructions which only execute when it is called eight.
That means creating a function is one thing, and if you want to execute that function, you have to
call it, so let me show you.
So there is a function, which is.
Whose work is to play some music, right?
So this is how we we have defined a function, do we really discuss what are these?
But what is return?
Typekit is function name.
But this is what this function is doing.
This function is actually going to play some music or it is just going to print playing music in our
case, because it's a very simple function, right?
I'm just defining this piece of code is creating the function.
It will not get executed until it is called.
So that there are two parts, one is defining the function, and second is when that piece of code should
get executed.
So for that, we need something which is known as a function called OK.
So we'll we'll dive into the details of the syntax.
So let's see.
So the function definition looks something like this.
So you will have a return type like in the previous case, it is void.
Then you will have the name of the function to play music.
And here in Gottlieb, in round records, you will specify one or more parameters or zero or more parameters,
to be precise.
Then you have one job instruction.
Okay, what is this function doing?
And then you have the return value.
Does this function return anything back to the place from where it was called?
So anyone can call a function or get.
Maine is also a type of function because we have seen do function did so and mean so as the return date
that this function returns zero eight.
So that is where you can see there is a return zero statement at the end of this function.
Maine is, by default, the first function that is called when a program starts and all of the functions
you have to explicitly call them get.
They do not get called automatically to play music at the function, and it does not return anything.
So void means the function does not return anything, right?
So that is why we don't need a written statement insider word function.
But most of the cases.
Now to call a function rewrite function name, followed by two parenthesis and a semicolon.
So this is an example of a function going OK.
This is.
The place where you from, where this function is getting cold, that means when you make a function,
call the control flow, jump to the function and start executing OK.
The entire body of the function, which is inside this calibrate, gets all those instructions start
getting executed when you actually make the function good, and a function can be called more than once,
OK?
And we can call it more than once, and hence it adds reusability to a code.
For example, you want to check a number is prime or not.
And if you create a function to check numbers or not, you can reuse it for multiple inputs.
You can check if seven is prime, if it is prime, if 13 is prime, if 15 is prime.
We can call a function multiple times.
OK, so then a function can be called multiple times and it will perform the same logic for a given
input, and hence it adds reusability to our code.
So that is one very big advantage of creating functions, right?
So one more thing, you can also parse data, which is known as barometers into a function when you're
creating this function, play music you are sending or we can pass some number.
And it is telling you gambling the end of the song.
In dysfunction, OK, so you can parse data by specifying the data table of the parameter and the name
of the parameter, right?
These this data is known as barometer, right?
OK.
So what that parameters the parameters they act as variables inside a function, we can add as many
as parameters as we want and we just need to separate them with a comma.
So we have first parameter, we have second parameter, which we have heard parameter.
So we have three integers denoting the song IDs and we are playing or get song one song to song.
Again, this is how the function will be called it Play Music five six seven eight two to evolve theory.
Let us try to jump into the coding part of functions from the next read you.