Everyone's in this lecture, we're going to solve this problem.
We are given a number and which is having binary digits, that means zeros and ones.
We want to interpret this, interpret the decimal equivalent of this.
Basically, we need to write a function that converts.
A number from binary to decimal rate.
So we are getting some number, which is in the form of zeros and ones.
So let's see how we can do it.
So if the number is, let's say, one one zero one, you know how to interpret this number, right?
So we know that this number is made up of powers of two.
So this is two par zero.
This is two about one.
This is two squared.
And those two will get in simpler terms.
These bars are one, two, four and eight and we are going to multiply the corresponding powers.
And these digits?
It is eight plus four plus zero plus one.
So this number is nothing but the number 13.
So that is what we want to find out to how we're going to do it in order to do this.
What we need is we need to extract all the digits, mate.
So first, we will extract the last digit that we know it is easy.
How do we get the last digit too busy, last digit of any number?
It is involved.
10.
All right.
We got the last digit.
You need to multiply this with some power.
So initially the power is one that is to power zero eight.
OK.
So, OK, it will multiply this last digit with some power, and we will add it to do an answer.
So answer equal to 200 plus last digit into Zimbabwe power.
And that power was initially one eight.
The power was initially one.
And our answer was initially zero, but this this thing, we have to do it for every place we get.
That means once we are done with this place, we have to move to the next place.
How do we go to the next place?
We need two things.
I need to find out the last digit promised millennium.
That means I need to reduce my number by a factor of 10.
OK, that will remove the last digit.
And I also need to increase my power from 2.0 to two per one.
That means the power is getting multiplied with two.
I have to say power equals two power, and I keep wondering this is OK.
I added one in the.
One to my answer, and there is one next time I will add what I will add something to my answer, which
is zero into two that is still one standard is still one.
This is also gone.
Next time, I'm going to put everything inside the loop right next time, the next digit is this number
11.
The last digit is one, and the previous answer is one.
So is it one plus one into the next ballot every time the power is getting multiplied with two?
So this power is for one in two four.
OK, so this number becomes five.
We're going to we have processed these three digits and equal in number.
We have got this till now.
It is five, right?
Next time, we're going to remove this using an equal one button.
So the number that is left as one, the last digit, it would be also one.
So easy answer equal to under plus five plus the ballot.
The power is going to be eight when we go to the next position.
Last digit in the power.
So the last digit is one into eight eight.
We add eight plus five, that is not 13 and we discard this off.
Finally, what is left?
So we have these birds with Detlev and they represent the number zero.
So what we can see, while the number is not equal to zero or while the number is greater than zero.
What we are doing, we are going to find out the last digit.
Multiplied with suitable power of two at that position.
And for a bit, we are going to update two things.
One is the power as we are going to the next index or the next place, the power of two gets double
eight and the number itself gets reduced by a factor of 10 because we are removing one digit rate.
And finally, from there, we considered under and said now we can dig and put some number and begin
to see out binary to decimal and the number is this.
OK.
OK, we got some go into last digit.
All right.
Now the belt is successful and let me show you show it to you, right?
Binary to decimal.
OK, let's say the number is one zero zero.
So it is actually the number four one zero one.
It is five one one zero one.
It is 13.
And how about this number one zero one zero one one one zero one zero one one?
The number is 43.
OK, so our code is working fine for all the cases, and I hope you have understood this logic and that's
all for this video.