Everyone in this lecture will solve a problem, given a number, and we want to find the binary representation
of that number.
So let's recall what we discussed about how do we convert the number into its binary.
So let's say we have a number 43, the one technique that we discussed when we talked about the binary
number system that we have to repeatedly divide this number by two.
And every time we have to write the ocean and remained so doing, 221 is 42 and the remainder is one,
OK, go into 10 is 20 and the remaining terrestrial one within the five is 10.
And that even president doing due to his food and the remainder is one it wouldn't do, one is to.
And the remainder is zero and two into zero zero under him in this one.
OK.
This is what.
And this and this is what the remainder is.
And what we discussed that if you interpret these numbers from bottom to top, they will give you the
binary representation of dog.
And you can verify all this is to par zero one two four eight 16 32, effectively adding 32 plus eight
plus two plus one.
And this gives you the number 43.
That means this long division method really works.
And given this, you can convert any number into its binary representation.
OK?
Now getting the remainder this easy right?
So what we are actually doing is we have a number in with us and we want to write a function.
That gives us the binary representation letter that is also an integer, right?
Maybe I say a decimal to binary is the function name, and it accepts indeed.
And returns are indeed of this form, right integer, which is made using zeros and ones.
Right now, what I need to see is that when you're combining these numbers right?
So effectively, if I talk about this number or any number, it's a let's do it for a simpler number,
such as Letter nine, right?
How do you do it for nine?
So you say it will do four is eight and the remainder is one.
The window two is for the remainder zero two into one is to the remainder is zero and two and two zero
zero.
And remember this one, this one zero zero one.
This gives us the binary representation of the number 98.
The one thing to note is that.
We can easily get the reminders or we can easily get the reminders.
But the challenge is how do we form the no, OK, how do we form this number one zero zero one effectively
what we need to do, we need to multiply this reminder.
Because it is coming.
It is multiplied with 10 by one zero zero is coming, yet it is multiplied with 10 power one.
This zero is coming.
It is multiplied with 10 squared.
And this one is coming out, so it is multiplied with 10.
OK, so if you add all of these domes, which is one plus zero plus zero plus 1000, it actually makes
the number one thousand one right now.
What does it mean as you're generating remainders down the line?
What do you need to?
You also need to generate powers of 10, starting from 10 biocidal and per one and squared and guilt,
and you need to multiply those powers with the remainder and you need to add them went on to right.
That is what you need to do.
Only then you can get a number of is of this form, right?
What I'm going to let us see how do we get the remainders first?
Into I have an answer, which is a sum of terms, and it is currently zero.
I have some power of 10, which is 10 power zero eight.
And this is actually one and I can do while this number and eight.
So this is your number and we are doing some work while this and is greater than zero.
OK.
So while this end is greater than zero, what we are doing, we are always finding the remainder.
OK, we remainders and models to.
Well, guess we get this one, this one, right?
And we multiply this remainder with the power in order to overrun what we see under equal 200 plus power
in the remainder.
All right.
What is the next step?
We have to reduce the value of it.
We got the remainder.
We have to reduce this nine to four.
So easy and equal and divided by two.
So this but forms the update step of the loop.
But we have to do one more step as we are going down.
We have also played.
We have to update the power as well, right?
So we have to say that after the computing done to make power 10 times of the previous power.
So this is going to generate us the powers of then the remainders we are already getting.
And this is the main step we we are updating the answer by multiplying the remainder with relevant power.
Often those are both the output would have been, let's say, one one zero one.
This one was multiplied with one.
This zero was multiplied with 10.
This was multiplied with 10 squared eight.
And this was multiplied with 10Q, adding these dumps would actually make the number one one zero one
night.
Now what you can do, you can see they're done.
The answer that is going to be the binary representation of this number.
And so you're going to see out there similar to binary.
And you give the number, then let's run this code.
So maybe I can say decimated by injury.
It said the number is 43, so I get one zero one zero one one.
Perfectly fine.
I say the number is 13.
Perfectly fine if being all one's fine.
The number is 100.
Look, this is how it looks like in binary.
And you can see that we have solved this problem.
So I hope this is clear and you the next we do.