Everyone, so let me show you a quick demo of how to create a functional kit, for example, the very
first function that we want to create is to let play music.
I can see wide play music and let's say I don't accept any parameters.
And this is the body of the function where we define what this function is going to do.
We are going to see out later playing music.
OK, fine enough.
And now we are in mean we are going to build this code and we are also going to run this code right?
So let me show you.
We have dodged large function them into right now, we don't get any output why?
The first thing that we discussed, it's important to call a function if you want to execute that function.
They can call the function, play music.
All right.
Now, if it underscored study, we have to build a code first and then I can run the code right now,
we are getting this output playing music.
That means the mean is the entry point of a program, the one the program is actually compiled from
top to bottom.
But the order of compilation does not decide the order of execution.
The execution always starts from me.
When you're executing this mean you came at this line 11 me and got pause at this line, and this is
the function that started getting executing.
OK, so this got executed, and after that, this part of the code is executed, OK?
The first part again part and the third part, OK.
This is what happens when you call a function.
Right now, it's not designed.
You can call a function only once.
You can call a function as many times as you want.
For example, I call play music three times.
Now what is going to execute three times, right?
So let's see how.
And let me first show you the output.
And you can to be playing music, playing music, playing music.
It is getting all three times.
OK, so the man is executing.
It gets paused.
Discord executes OK.
Then again, at this line, this function again gets executed.
I just line it again.
Gets executed.
OK.
And then this part of the code is getting it whenever a function call happens, that means we are calling
a function right?
One analog I would try to delay.
Does that mean is is like a boss, right?
So men will always, always be the one that gets starts executing.
It's like the head of the house right on Main can call any help.
But to do some work, play music is a function, right?
Men can call, play music or get you go and play some music, right?
And this play music function can play music.
That means it is doing something inside it.
Or it may it may convey something back to the mean.
It can also give some data back to them.
So we are going to look at two things.
One is how do they boss data?
It will function and how do they turn data from a function back to the place where it is called OK?
It is not just that that man is going to call a function, a function can also call some other function,
for example, it said that is a function called, let's say.
Cook vegetables, maybe there is a helper whose work is to cook the vegetables, right?
But diet helper might ask someone else to bring the vegetables first, right?
Maybe there is another helper whose work is to bring the vegetables right?
Bring vegetables would be an added function, and this cooked vegetables might give you information,
you can bring five kids of vegetables, and this might return something back to this function, OK?
My work is done, OK?
It might look I have brought these many vegetables, or it might say true or false that I was able to
bring these many vegetables onboard and this school graduated with may tell something back to the monarchy
that we have cooked.
These many.
Vegetables.
It might give some status, OK?
The vegetables are ready or the vegetables could not be prepared, something like that.
OK.
The what what happens is two or more blocks of good, like two blocks of code.
They can communicate with each other.
OK.
And for that, what we need to do.
So we have a function one.
We have another function.
The function one cannot function to function.
Two, to execute some task and function and gain some data in the form of parameters.
Look and function to build something back to function.
One in the form of a return value in the form of a return value.
In the first case, the return values void.
That means play music does not tell anything back to the mean right.
But let me give you another function.
Where?
The return type could be a strength.
OK?
The return trip could be a string, that's a.
Void theHigh.
And it's a string say hello.
Something like this.
I'm grading two functions, the one function does not return anything, right?
And here I accept the name.
I'm accepting a name and we are just saying, OK, hi, followed by name, right?
So what we are doing, we are going to pass some data to this function, so maybe we are going to call
say hi and I give my name the right.
So let me buy this good for now, let us just comment this out.
And I will just commend this one out.
Maybe like this.
OK, let me just delete this one, right?
Now, say he's a function which is accepting a name, a string under this branding hype pretty got high
around whatever it is.
Maybe we can call this function do names.
Now, let me try to run this code, and you can see we're getting an output hypothetic Unido.
What both of these functions are doing, OK, so what?
Play music and say, Hey, is doing so?
Basically, both of them are getting a call from them to do some work right to play music.
It gets cold from the mean, right?
They also get called from the main right.
And Limerick does not accepting that, OK, so it does not accept any of it as the thehigh function.
It is accepting some great ability and it is doing some work.
Both of the functions, they're not running anything back.
They're just printing it on the screen to whatever is the output.
The output is getting printed on the console.
They're just printing on the console right now.
Anyone can print on the console.
Any function can print under and operate.
And here we have it.
What if you want?
No, I don't want to send this output on the console.
Maybe I want to send this output back to the mean, right?
That is where the return values are going to come into the picture.
So let us create another function where we send some data, like the disk.
To this function, say hi and say hi or say hello, and maybe it runs.
Let's say hello, pretty, it returns something like this.
Oh, it's our choice.
What we want to do with this value, this value is going to be with us.
So when you wanted it done something, so there can come the concept of a return type of function,
which does not return anything.
It is going to have a void return date.
That means nothing is returned, right?
There is no return value.
So now maybe I won't return something back, which is a string so I can just drink, say hello and string
name will be input.
We are creating this function, which is accepting a name like the followed by what value you want to
return.
So maybe I want to return a low plus.
Name it.
If I call this function, say hello, right?
And I give some name, let's say, according minutes, OK?
Or I just say hello to learners, right?
And what is going to happen to add this line, we are calling a function which returns something OK,
which does return something.
We will not see this output on the screen because we are at no place, we have done printing on the
screen, right, but that output that is going to come back to the mean.
It would come here or it would come here, but it will not get printed on the screen because we are
not using code anyway, right?
Let me show you the output.
Again, we are seeing the output of, say, high, but we are not seeing the output of what you need
to do.
The output is coming back and I mean, it is coming back in line number 22 when the function call is
over.
We going to see out this output.
Let us print what what the output is now.
If I build the code and if I run the code now, I'm going to see her loading minutes.
And hello learners, this output is now getting produced.
Maybe we can put the right.
So what function does we made a function called say hello calling minutes, and this call got replaced
by the output of the function, so the output of the function is what the functions is a low coding
minute.
OK.
This is what the function is producing, and hence this output is now getting on the screen.
Let me just try to explain it the low.
So we have, I mean it.
Maine is making a call to a function called Say Hello.
I say hello is accepting some data, which is a strength.
It's a coding minute, it is returning some data that is a low coding.
When it's a now mean mean, it is up to mean what to do with this value.
Amanda Knox, let me bring this value to the screen now we are printing it on the screen.
OK, then this way we are able to look at the functions can accept data through parameters.
Functions can also return some data through return values.
You need to put a written statement followed by the value that you need to return and the function should
have a return type.
Of the type of data that you want to read in this case, we are running a string and hence the return
of this function, as Stringer does not void.
Let me give you one more example let's say you want to find.
Area of letters.
OK.
And you're getting the radius.
You don't want to open in the area, what do you want to return bacteria so you can get it done?
Maybe three one one four in the radius in the radius.
OK.
Now you can say that, OK, I want to get the circle area on maybe whatever it is, the area we can
call this function area of the circle, we can give some radius five and that value will come back here
and that we're storing at an area rate that we are storing it in the area.
And maybe you can see if area is greater than, let's say, 10, then maybe you can see out, uh, we
can get the land.
Something like that.
OK.
OK, now let me show you the output of this one.
And you're going to be getting we can cut the land, OK now.
Why am I dating you?
This is why do we need it return value?
Because there is a certain action that needs to be performed based upon what is being computed by a
function.
OK.
We might not always want to print the return value on the screen.
We might want to perform a further action based on what area has been returned by the function.
OK, now this is where the return values are very important.
OK.
And you might also want to print the area on the screen.
You can do OK.
The area is this much.
Let's build the code.
And let me show you the output.
OK.
We are saying OK, if we can get the land and the area of the circle or the land is 78 units, that
is the importance of return values.
And I hope you got to understand some of these concepts.
And with more examples coming in in the next few years, these concepts would become even more clear.