Everyone.
Let us recap what we have done so far, so a C++ function has two parts to one.
What is known as your declaration?
The declaration includes the name of the function, the return tape and the parameters that we have
defined and definition include the body of the function to everything that is in the curly brackets.
Basically, the logic that needs to be executed.
So that part constitutes the definition of the function.
And we have also talked about a function.
OK.
And we have seen the function must be called.
So that it gets executed and a function can be called one or more times.
That is one more thing we need to see.
A function must be declared before it is called.
Now what is the meaning of this statement?
So let us try to understand these concepts through an example.
What will will we have this function, this part?
Is known as your declaration.
OK.
This part is your declaration of the function and anything that is inside the body starting from this
record.
It is known as the function definition.
And this is your this line is your declaration, the name, the return type and the parameters, right?
We are saying the function must be declared before we start using it.
So in this case, we are using the function here and we have declared it before.
We are using it perfectly fine if I believe it works fine.
But if it is now, suppose I move this code from here to here.
Now what we are doing, we are first calling the function and then we have the declaration and the definition
of the function.
So if I will look good, you see, we're getting an added use of undeclared identifier to play music
to your compiler is compiling the code from top to bottom and it reads this line and it observed there
is a function called to.
At this point, the compiler does not know what function should be called.
So how do we handle this case, OK?
The way to do it is using something which we call forward declaration to what we will do.
Maybe if you want to keep the body of the function below it, OK, but what you can do is you can just
tell the compiler, OK, there would be something like a play music function later in this code, right?
What we are doing, we are describing this part.
We are describing the declaration and we are defining it in the beginning so that the compiler gets
to know, OK, and there is a function by the name of music, which except this song and.
If you see a call to play music function, understand this is a call to play music function, OK?
And we have defined the code at any rate.
This way, your code would get compiled and add the runtime when this function is actually getting called.
The corresponding code of play music will also get executed.
So if the code.
And if I show you the demo, I'm calling this nightlies forward declaration.
And yes, it is working fine.
It works.
We are getting playing music with the song Lady.
That is funny.
I hope you have understood this concept of forward declaration, and it tells the compiler in advance
that there would be a function play music, which might get called before you see the definition of
that.
OK.
That is the whole idea of doing the Wildwood Declaration.
Even you can put this party that is all the work in the similar manner.
OK, but maybe we can put it it.
OK, that's all for this video and thank you.