Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we're going to discuss this problem where we want to write a function
that returns the factory often, no, OK, now this is a very easy problem.
The only thing is how do we write a function that returns the factory look?
Let us try to strengthen our concepts of function.
So the first thing is we are given a number like five on five nothing, but it is a product of all the
terms from one to five, right?
And this product is nothing but one.
In order to compute this product.
What we would required is a loop.
Right on that loop, we will write inside a function because the problem asks us to write the function.
OK?
Let us start defining the function.
So what would be the return type?
It's going to run an integer.
All right.
What should be the name of the function?
It should be something logical, like factorial.
OK.
What should be the input to the function?
It should be the value of end.
And now at this point, we can see that how we are going to compute this answer.
OK, now think think of a logic to compute the factorial.
So let's say we have and that is five to one thing is very clear we need to store it on foot in some
bucket.
And let us answer is initially one.
So what I can do, I can generate numbers in the range one twin and I can multiply my answer with those
numbers.
For example, I, as one on one and two one is one.
I update my answer every time that one comes it and they increment, the value of that is two.
So one thing to do is to undo is my current answer.
OK, so I am basically doing this operation until equals.
Previous answer into I.
OK.
Then I generate the next number that is three.
So doing two.
Three, that is six.
All right.
Six comes here.
Six into the next number.
That is four.
That is 24.
So 24 comes here and twenty four into five, that is 120.
120 is the final number that we would return from this function, right?
So let's let's see how we can just do it right.
So let me say that my answer is initially one, then I'll put a four loop and I call the one I then
equal to, let's say, and A-plus.
Plus, in every step, I'm saying that my answer would be multiplied with I after this loop.
I know that answer is going to store the factory of the number, and I can return that answer from me.
OK.
Now.
Again, this year old factory love the number and where and as an input by the user, right?
So we have we are going to build a code red.
Oh, OK.
The world is successful.
And now let us try to run this one again to dodge large factorial.
And here we go.
So if then we're just five to this one to integrate, if it has six, it is seven twenty.
If it is nine, it is some number No.
One word of caution for Victoria to give.
So as the value of and it is going to increase and Victoria is going to increase a lot, OK?
And the largest range of intermediate, we know it is up to approximately 10 at night.
If you try to multiply letter 20 numbers, 20 numbers would mean somewhere around 20 digits.
Which is obviously beyond the range of this.
Indeed.
OK.
And in this case, what you're going to get, you're not going.
You will not be able to store the answer inside the book, so you have to do something else.
So that's one word of caution that you cannot compute a bigger factory and store it inside integer.
You actually need something like a to store all the digits of a factory look.
So that's all for this video and thanks a lot.