Everyone in this lecture, we're going to see how do we compute the binomial coefficient INSEAD, given
the value of and not?
OK.
So we would be given and and we would be given out and we want to compute INSEAD.
The nearest denoted as the binomial coefficients.
I will tell you an example.
Let's say you have five cards and the name of the cards are a, b, c, d e or you want to choose Dugard's
within the binomial coefficient tells us in how many ways we can select Dugard's.
Out of lifeguards, OK?
What problems like these?
Either we make all the possible combinations, for example, I choose the guard Abby or I choose the
guard AC or I choose Eddie or I choose a night.
Or I choose B C, B D, we e but I choose C, B B or I choose the.
Okay, so clearly how many ways we are, it is four plus three plus two plus one, which is 10 ways.
Either you make all the possible combinations and then you compute the other ways to use the binomial
option in zero in this case and is five.
And how many objects we own the juice out of N objects do.
We will compute 5C to get two entities denoted as n Victorian, divided by and minus are factorial.
In do our federal let us try to put this formula for 5C to so it is five factorial five minus two,
that is three Victoria into our victory letters to Victoria.
Now this five actually can be written as three victories in the vote in the five so that we can cancel
out three factorial.
And here we are left with two Victoria with just two to the vote by Tuesday night.
Either you use this formula in theory or you generate all possibilities obviously generating and yet
is more convenient to us and we can get the answer.
By just computing the binomial opportunity, this is what the significance of binomial coefficient is,
what we are doing.
We are going to write a function that compute the binomial coefficient for us.
Let us try to do that.
Will right and not we will take input and they're not.
That means we want to choose in how many ways we can choose our objects out of a set off an object.
So for that, we're going to compute the binomial coefficient.
Given and not right, so clearly, we will write a function that returns an integer, right?
So in binomial coefficient, we get in, then indeed and now how we're going to do it right.
So we know that the onthat is in Victoria divided by and minus odd factorial.
And what victory late, so maybe I can answer is.
And Victoria divided by n minus advertorial in dour Victorian, right?
And this goes in denominator.
One thing is very clear that here is some work, which is repetitive.
That means we need to compute Victoria repeatedly.
What would be a better idea?
So you can make a stand alone function for factorial like we have already done will reduce that go ahead.
And that called that function is going to be used three times in this example.
So and there would be factorial of and divided by factorial off and minus are.
Into Victoria Law.
I nodded and reconsidered and answered.
This actually simplifies our code of binomial confusion a lot because we don't need to compute and victory
here, here, here.
So all of these calculations are burdened by a function which is a reusable block of code.
OK, so it is reusable.
We can use it three times in this computation, and it is going to work for us.
Let us try to run this code and see what do we get right?
So we have built the code.
And now I can run and dodge large binomial coefficient.
And let's end as five artists do, so I get done today.
OK?
How about 63 if and in six areas?
Three I you're done to 20 years working perfectly fine for all of these cases.
And I hope now you've understood that functions are indeed helpful.
And that's all for this video.