I so well, then you have made it so far and you have got a lot of knowledge about functions, but one
concept which is left now is the calls to aggregate.
So what actually happens at the memory level when you work with functions?
What happened to the local variables?
OK, so we are going to understand the concept of a goldstuck to the example that we have already done
right.
Let us try to understand the concept of Carlstadt through this example, right?
What happened is every time a function is called, it gets pushed in a memory that is known as stored
memory.
So there are two types of memory.
One is a stock memory and another is a heap memory, right?
So right now, we are not going to talk about deep memory because it deals with dynamic memory allocation.
And in our current programs, everything is a static memory allocation.
OK, so dynamic memory allocation.
This dynamic, dynamic allegation, we will do little later on, but what now will focus on stock memory?
The one thing to note is will make few notes here.
I will talk about stock memory, not next.
So every time our function is called, it gets created.
In the stock memory, OK, and all the local variables belonging to that function.
Are part of the stock frame.
OK?
And another point is once the function call is over.
The stock frame is cleared off, that means in all the memory that that is belonging to that function,
it gets cleared off and the function.
That is currently executing.
Is always at the top of the stack.
So now I'm going to explain you all of these points, one by one.
What happened, right?
Now your program starts from mean, let's see.
OK.
And you have some variability and and and you take input as well, you are here, right?
OK, so what happens?
The stock is stock memories.
OK, so everything is actually part of the RAM itself or the vision that is done by the compiler.
OK, so the compiler decided to get this part is in the stock.
This part is belonging to him, so it is a partition done by the compiler.
So a small part is a stock.
A bigger part is he and what?
The memories have some different properties.
OK, like stock, memory is only for memory.
That means last in, first out anything that comes into the stock.
For example, if you have a stack of books that you have a C++ book on the top of it, you put the Java
book on the top of it, you put the Python book.
OK, if I want to remove something, what what is the thing that would get removed?
It is actually the python.
OK?
That means the book, which was placed at the last, is the first one to get it removed.
The insertion and deletion in stock always happens at the top.
OK, so that is the property of this kind of data.
So it certainly does have its implicit start, I would say in this case.
You are not coding of the stack.
It automatically exists in the memory for the function calls.
It gets created right.
So whenever a function is called, it's get created in the stock memory.
So that means you are doing a new insertion in the stock.
So what would happen in this case?
Mean would get created in the stock memory.
So what is the meaning of it is getting created.
So there is a stock frame that belongs to me on all the local variables like and is a local variable.
It gets created in the stock memory.
OK.
And all the local variables are part of this doctrine.
This is what it means.
So if you have something like under equal, the faith that answered would be here, OK?
Or if you have an equal to some function call, it's a factorial and you're saying, Look, I want the
answer off victory loving.
And what happens in this case, right?
A new function call.
So.
Every time a function is called, it gets created in the stock market.
So a new stock frame would be created for the factorial function.
And it would have its own local variables later, we have Victoria, which is in then.
And here we have answered all we have in die.
So all those local variables would get created inside this memory, right?
So once the function call is over, the start frame is cleared off.
That means if you say, OK, I'm going to return, someone said to hear that it is getting stored and
you compute the answer, which is No.
120 unusual guy to return this answer.
This answer will go back to the place from where it is called.
And all the local variables in the memory which belong to this function, they will get destroyed.
You'll get the ones.
This function hates the written statement.
All the data that is local to this function, it will get destroyed from this document.
OK, so that means what is the function that is now executing the factorial function was executing it.
Now it is over.
This is the new top of the stack and maybe you are doing the old onset.
Basically mean God was at this line when the victory was executing, and once the victory function is
over, the control flow will again come back to me and you will see you'll get this line got executed.
Now this line will start getting executing it.
So now you'll get the answer on the screen.
It's the function that is currently at the top.
That is currently executing is always at the top of the stack.
OK.
That is the significance of the stark memory.
It basically controls what function is executing, what line of the function is executing, what part
of memory is where, what part of memory is getting created, what part of memory is getting destroyed,
OK?
That is what the significance of the stock memory is.
And I hope you got some high level idea about the stock memory in the next few days will see one example.