Hello, once in this video, we'll see how the gold stock actually works in this example, where we
are computing the binomial option to give the first of all the first function to get a call is mean
and it is called automatically right.
So what happens in the coal stock?
We have the main function.
And now are calling the function by normal goldfish, and OK, so this gets pushed in the mean because
a new call is happening and this line.
Now it is going to call three functions, okay, so it calls affect all function with the value of and
let's say we are computing five, we do it compute and victory.
The first that is victory love five.
And what happens.
This returns some value back to the mean and it says, OK, my onto this one 20 and this gets this call.
OK, that means this memory gets destroyed.
But on the stock to this, this date is achieved.
Now what is the function that is executing this function is at the top.
And this is the one that is executing.
I would make the call for victory love and minus odd because it says.
Let's compute the value of actually love and minus five, minus two.
It makes a call to factor of three.
It does some configuration, it returns some value back to this function.
OK.
And this also gets over from the stock.
This all took it now again.
What is the function that is executing this function?
And now in this line, we are at this point, it again makes a function called again vector.
11th-Gen gets created in the stock.
It executes all this code.
It computes summons, which is vector love to, and it returns something back.
That is the only factor left to is due to what happens.
It also gets bobde from the stock.
It gets removed.
Now we are in this function.
We know that Vector Lo-Fi was 120 divided by three vector, and that was six divided by two.
This under comes out with 10 and unanswered redundancies.
This, then, is a returned back to the mean, and this is also destroyed from the memory.
OK?
This is how the function calls are actually happening in the stock.
Then you have multiple calls.
This diagram illustrates the process of having the stock calls, and I hope this example made the concept
more clear.
And that's all for this video.