Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we're going to discuss a very basic mathematical problem, we need
to write a function to check whether a number is prime or not, OK?
So let's recall what is a prime number?
Prime number is a number which has only two devices.
That is the one and the number itself.
OK.
For example, if I talk about the number seven, then seven has only two devices one and the number
itself, OK.
That means in from the range 2.2 and minus one.
OK.
And if you have a number and then none of the numbers is going to divide.
OK, so none of these.
Is going to.
Divide.
And if this is the case, then we said the number and is going to be prime.
Otherwise, it does not.
That means if for a given number, if you find any one device there in the range, it will do and minus
one.
That would mean the number is not prime.
OK, if if I have led to this number is eight.
If somehow and mortality, I is equal to zero, that means the number is not prime.
OK.
What we can do, we can begin on.
But maybe let's say the number is 11.
Then will I read from the range?
It will do then two three four five six seven eight nine and then we will try to divide 11 with all
of these numbers.
And if no one divides 11, then we will see this number is prime.
But let's say the number is 12, the number is 14.
OK.
Then we know that two is going to divide this number and we are going to say 14 two is divisible by
two.
And hence this number is not right.
OK.
So very simple.
But we will.
I dread over the range for, let's say, I in range.
It's a.
So we are going to say, OK, if I will go from two.
I'll start from two.
It will go till in minus one.
And if somehow and more say if this becomes equal to zero, that means we can done that.
This number does not bring what we consider done for us.
And if we come out of the loop, OK, if we come out of the loop, that means no written statement was
hit, then we can return it.
So this is what we are doing do.
So the would look something like this, and let's see the code in the next few.