Everyone in this lecture, we're going to start dealing with a cat, Eddie.
OK, so that's the area of correctness.
Till now, what we were doing is we were reading certain characters, but we were not storing all of
them.
We were just storing a single character to get out in few problems or in a lot of problems.
There might be a requirement to store the entire list of characters.
Look, if, for example, you want to store the word hello.
And maybe you want to do some updates on it, maybe later, later on, you want to say hello, followed
by some knee, maybe OK, and you want to.
Rent something.
OK?
The thing is, how do we store it?
So one way of doing it is using the character is also known as the traditional the style strings, OK?
And so he provides us C++, provides us the functionality to create an array in which every box or every
book holds one.
OK.
And one thing that you need to remember about character areas is that they need to be terminated by
a null character.
So this is very important.
We will see why it is important that no character is denoted as backslash zero and it has ASCII value
of zero.
Get it either ASCII will you.
Basically, you need to put AI is stored as IDO or another character at the end of the city.
OK.
And these areas this support ID, write and update operations that mean you can put some data into the
bucket.
You can write some data.
Obviously, you can read it and you can also update.
You get to know, I don't want this to be I want this to be a school that is like update operation.
So that is very important thing that we need to remember.
On one, another thing that will frequently come across in your.
Some of the goods is sometimes a stringers written in the quotes like this.
You might see the Otello.
OK.
So is this a correct 30 countries?
No, it's not a character.
It's it's just a constant string, and it's no, it is a sequence of characters, but it is not a good
character.
OK.
And it is stored in a read only memory.
That means you cannot update this constant, OK, it's more like a godsend, and it is read only, right?
Let me talk about the parts of the memory.
So your when an application runs, OK?
So your memory is divided into four segments.
One is a stock segment where your function calls do happen.
Another segment is the stock basically story or function calls and the local variables.
That means any functions that are created inside our function.
They would be part of the stock memory.
There is a huge segment which also is having certain special properties like the dynamically created
objects.
They live on the heap, right?
So basically all dynamic allocation or the allocation of memory during the runtime, that memory is
occupied on the there is another segment which is known as a data segment, and there is another segment
which is known as the text segment to get.
Data segment does store like global variables, are static variables.
All that data goes in the data segment and takes segment includes your executable instructions.
OK.
When you're running the application, you get it.
It's just a set of lines of code.
So all those lines there read only they're not going to change all the executable instructions.
They go into the segment along with any string letters and can sense that you will create.
So they're also read only OK, they are read only, and they also go into the next segment.
OK?
So basically, hello, are you?
Write Later Index equal to five?
Now here, two things that are happening.
This is a five, which is an integer concerned, OK, but you're copying this value into a local variable.
OK.
Your initializing a local variable, which might mean something to let to mean.
And this bucket is now creating this bucket, as announced during this value.
Five.
That bucket is created in the back.
OK.
So what I'm trying to say is that like you have integer concepts, we also have one since quantum strings,
which are hidden in double codes and we call them as string letters, OK?
And by default, they're null terminated.
So that means even if, look, we have not drawn an alert, but at the storage level in the text segment,
it is terminated when it does terminate with no character.
So that is what string literal is.
OK?
Now.
We have understood what is the meaning of null terminated, OK, so the corrected it is.
If you are making a character study which will handle the storage for you, you need to terminate it
with a null character.
It's your responsibility to do it.
But if you're creating a strange little does by having double code, it is not terminated automatically,
OK?
But the thing is, you can do, read and write on the correct.
Plus any updates you can write, whereas a string literal it is read only.
OK?
It does not.
It cannot be updated.
It cannot be updated because it lives.
You know, read only memory.
OK, so when the program starts, this content gets loaded in read only memory and you cannot updated
or you cannot override it.
OK, so it will stay in the memory.
It's read only string.
Now, the thing is, then how do we create a character that is OK, so let us look at a few examples.
So one way to do it is you define the character and using a lubricant, you initialize what this error
is going.
Do it.
So let me show you a few examples.
It's a name and name list, and the one thing we can do is let us try to see what does this area contain?
Right?
In order to bring the city, one thing we can do is we can use a loop.
OK.
Or C++ also supports that you can directly print a corrected array using code.
You may ask how does the old print the editor look?
So this is actually a special functionality.
OK, a special functionality has been added.
You see out there whenever you see an edit of the type correct, but do not print the address of that
ilk.
Do not print the starting point of there.
Instead, you print everything inside the area until you find another character.
OK, so by default, this character that we have created as name it contains 10 buckets.
And we don't know what data it is going to contain.
By default, it may contain zeros, it may contain garbage, it can contain anything, right?
What this sealed function is going to do unless it finds another character in the memory, which might
be at zero.
The index, which might be at the first index, which might be at the seven index, it can.
With an index, it is just going to print everything until it finds a null character.
OK?
So that is what this code statement is going to do.
So let me show you.
So it faces the old name, and I've not done any initialization till now, right?
So let me try to run this code.
On dogs like God -- war, buddy.
I just ran the wrong program.
It's not like God added them.
Hmm.
Let's build a good first.
And now you can see.
So it is actually an integer that in this case, what we are getting, we are getting the address of
our own budgetary, OK.
So this is what she does in case of war in digitally.
But let me change it to work on activity.
And let me try to show you the code.
In this case, it is not giving me any output, which means it did found a null at the zero two place
and building the code.
It is not giving any output.
OK, so it did found in the zero three NICS and that is why it is working like this.
Let me initialize this array with the name OK.
The Wenham initializing I can skip giving the size of the city, which is now optional.
And you can do.
It is giving me the output that the.
OK, now there is one concern that we want to know whether this is null, terminated or not.
Okay, so let us see what I what I'm going to do.
Maybe I can use a function which gives me the length of this area, OK, the length of the edit.
There is a method which is known as Strange Land, SDR Alien and I passed the area to this and it will
tell me how many buckets it has used bestowed this particular string.
OK, so let us try to see the output.
It is saying that they use seven buckets to store this particular string, they.
Though it is giving us the output, but there is one special thing that I want you to remember about
the Sierra Leone function.
It does not count the Nile.
Look at it while calculating the land OK, so effectively.
If even if it is a bit big and what we have did is we have initialized corrected it using a string literal.
OK.
And what we discussed the string literals.
They are not returning the goods and the note that we need to look at.
What does it mean?
Effectively inside the character that we did copy all the letters B, D E J and the character is also
copied, but the learned function is written such don't.
It will count everything until it hits.
Then again, so this knowledge is not counted effectively the that it must be having a safe that.
Is it right?
Now, coming back to some other ways of initializing, so that is one way of doing it.
You are the finest wrinkly little anchor brackets and you created it.
OK, maybe I can say God name.
It's a company, right?
And I say, OK, I want to initialize this string, so I have to give it here.
I have to define got followed by square brackets like we create a regulatory and what we are going to
do.
But not not yet, but apparently I was boarding in Dover, Delaware, has a different notation, so
God company, I define good.
This is an area that can hold up to 200 letters, OK?
Or maybe what I can do, I can do this is equal to according minutes.
So let me just, Brent, if we are able to initialize company correctly or not.
Maybe if I underscored.
Yes, we do get the output quoting minutes.
So here again, what we have done, we have used a string literal, which is knowledge that we need
to look at.
Let me show you another way of doing the initialization may be God lets in done name something and I
say OK.
The name of the end is not defined as a list of categories, maybe are.
Some X that you'll get some x y z, and in this case, I have explicitly defined the list of characters
that will go inside my edit that is name of the intern.
And what I will do.
I will still vote, though, in denim, in the similar fashion.
OK?
So let us try to see what output do we get?
All right, though, we are getting X-rays, but we can get something else as well, maybe I have X,
Y, Z and D.
Let me run this.
OK.
And let me remove the.
Just a matter of chance that we are getting to see an output like this by default, what is going to
happen in this case?
It.
So in Dunn name is Eddie, which is sporting three letters.
And there can be a when when you're printing the internet.
It is starting from the 03 index and it is going to read in the memory until it finds an OK, even if
this is outside the boundaries of the area.
It will not get to know till what later to print, because the printing algorithm, which has been buried
inside out it reads the area a little bit later until it finds an ally to what is going to happen.
So in some other cases, you can get x y z, followed by garbage.
The where is this garbage coming from?
It doesn't come from this place, OK?
They're just a matter of chance this time that we are not getting our garbage.
But it is very likely, or it is very much possible that when you run this code on your system, you
see this kind of output x y z garbage.
This is happening because in the third case, when we are initializing the internet, it does not know
that we need to look if we have to explicitly put an alert.
Now, if heard and the good now it is correct, because if you are initializing your character study
using a list of characters, please do define another character at the end of that, OK?
So for the first two initial positions, the null is not mandatory, OK, but so that is a quick introduction
about corrected errors and in the next lecture will continue working with corrected areas and we'll
look at some more functions to work on corrected errors.