Everyone will know we were working with corrected errors on what we saw is that while creating that
it, we were initializing that will give it some value.
But this might not be the case.
Always.
Many are what you might need to do is you and you just need to define and edit and you want to read
user input, OK, you want to read user input, what you can do in that case.
So one ways you can see some guy and maybe some greetings ended, and maybe you can see this sentence
can contain up to and regulators, including the null character and I can design greeting.
OK, so now what I'm trying to tell you is if you talk about the integer that you have to read each
of the inputs using a loop, OK, which still can be the word will be corrected, but scene does work.
It will accept the entire world as an input and it will store it in the correct.
OK.
Let me show you and the output as well, right?
You're going to see out outward.
All right.
Sorry, Scott, greeting.
Now what we are doing, we are waiting for some input, maybe.
Hello.
It says hello, followed by name which was actually getting printed because of the state.
You can directly print the name without using a loop.
And you can directly input.
A list of characters and get it stored inside, Oh, Eddie.
OK, now when you're storing this inside an area, it is automatically null terminated, OK, because
C knows that the correct way of storing inside look at Eddie is to terminate that area with the null
correct.
So this work, the scene object is going to do for you.
OK, so it happens internally.
You don't do any work, right?
Directly input a list of characters and it gets stored inside automatically.
Let me try to experiment with some more input and we'll see something.
So we are running, let's say hello, and I do get the output.
Which is hello itself.
Well, let me input a sentence.
Hello, how are you doing?
Now, what is happening in this case, so although we are inputting a sentence.
It is only taking the first word, OK.
It is only taking the first word of why this is happening, OK, fingers season will stop processing
and put when it sees a whitespace, it sees a white space and whatever what it is going to do.
So I suppose zen Buddhist hello, followed by space.
Somehow, I might.
What it is doing, it is copying everything inside the Eddy.
And as soon as it takes a whitespace, it puts a nail in the output that ended terminated.
It puts the box under in your daddy.
OK, so degrading it is terminated at this point.
And when you're printing this eddy, you only get the output.
That is it.
And how do we fix this problem?
We need a function that inputs entire engines and stored it incorrectly.
OK.
So the function that does that is not it is known as Good Line or get some great line as a method.
And this great mattered, except two things.
One is it needs this in object, so we both seen to this method.
And second is it needs the connectivity where you need to stored something.
So the character that is your greeting.
OK.
Now, let us try to build a school.
OK, sorry to interrupt.
This is not the lend function that is a function called as seen not on it, except the name of the dairy
that is greeting.
And it also should know what is the maximum size of dairy so that it can load up to that maximum size.
And remember everything that is going beyond that size because of the maximum sizes.
Hundred.
And now we can run this code, it is getting built.
OK, standard guidelines.
It's a method of the thin object.
OK.
And we are calling this method and it is accepting the name of dairy, followed by the length of dairy,
the maximum size of dairy.
And now we can run this code on again.
OK.
Hello, how are you?
Now you can see this output is getting stored as it is right, and that is what seemed to get lenders
as so what I'm trying to tell you is just to summarize what we have learned to use scene.
If you want to read a word that means no spaces and use a not great line if you want to read a sentence.
That means including spaces.
OK.
And one more thing I would like to tell you, suppose you don't want to read till the end of the line,
maybe you want to read a paragraph which maybe terminates at a DOD, OK, which might terminate at a
dot?
What are you going to do?
You can define a third optional parameter, which is that eliminated?
Which does this function?
When to stop processing the input?
OK, now suppose we run this code and we want to give a paragraph.
I suppose I like reading books.
And Java, Python and C++ are my favorite programming languages, and I hate do it now.
What it does, it did stored the entire input until it sort of took it did not store this dog.
But it did stored the entire input inside a character.
OK.
That means you can use scene to get line.
Whether they eliminated and you can tell at what character I should stop processing the input, OK,
so you have the error name, you have the land of the free and you have a character that is a delimit
which tells this input, this function, when to stop processing and it stops processing when it hits.
Not.
This is how this function is going to work.
I hope you got some idea about how you can take input inside the CreditEddie and in the next few years,
you will discuss more concept.