Hi, everyone, so we'll continue our discussion on these style strength, also known as character,
is OK.
So so far, what we have seen is how to initialize the eddy, how to read an attack, and in initialization,
we talked about two ways.
One is in which we.
Even a list of characters, and in another way, we did see that we can initialize a string using a
string literal.
And we also see how to initialize or how to assign a value to a string Wunderlist created by taking
in one more thing we will do in this example and we are going to take.
Sometimes people do make this mistake.
They try to assign a string literal to correct that.
OK, so maybe I'll call it as string.
Functions.
Now let's we have got a battery on it, can hold up 200 letters, including the now look at that.
Now let me try to put something inside it and I say name equals plastic.
If I build this cold, I'm going to get an error rate.
So it is not as high and we cannot assign any value.
Do.
To the Iranian mucosa, the name is actually an address of dairy, and this is a read only constant.
We cannot put something in the address of dairy, OK, so this is something we cannot do, right?
Then how do we update the city?
So one way is that we read foot each of the index and then we try to put some values inside it.
So this is name on this that is indexed like regulatory and it has a zero location, one location and
up to two times up to 99 locations because besides under it, OK, so if I can put something here,
OK, the name is actually the address of that.
It is, it denotes the starting point.
OK, maybe this addresses some one zero eight zero.
Name is a point that points to the beginning of the city.
Now, if I put it to it, it might.
I'm sorry if I would correct that if I can add that I can the name of zero.
This is equal to be made if I want to write my entire name or if I want to update some of the places
in the city, I have to do it by accessing the index as a boys.
I got to know about some constraint.
OK?
And maybe I'm just terminating it by putting another character writing in a less important so that if
you do see your name, you stop printing after print after the first index.
Okay?
OK, so this is actually important.
Now if I run this code?
I can say large, large, the string functions, it does print beer, but just correct it as opposed
to turn off putting, but I want to put all of the letters of my name into this area.
It would be either you will put a loop.
OK, but this could be an operation which could be very frequent.
Or you might be doing this a lot of times and hence what?
Do we have, as we do, have a header file which provides us with certain functions, like if we want
to copy a string literal into a character night, there is a function which is known as string copy
SDLC b why?
And we tell the destination where we want to put something.
And here we tell the source from where we will read something.
OK?
The source in this case is a read-only constant, which is pretty weak.
And what is the destination?
The destination is the name Adi.
OK, so we are putting the letters of critique.
We are copying it into the character.
OK, now if I bring my code and if I try to show you the output, now you're going to read it is working
as expected, OK?
So instead of being name equal to critique which is an invalid operation, you would be doing string
copy name, followed by the value followed by the string literal that you want to copy.
Or maybe you can have space separated string letters as well.
That is also fine.
That will also work as expected it.
Now you're going to it is working as expected, right?
That is another way of putting values inside the character study using an inbuilt function from the
C string library and the function name is string copy.
And what more we do we have we do have some of the functions like string concatenation, string length.
Let me show you the library still C Street.
OK, so see, String has functions for copying that we have seen a function string copy.
It also have functions for doing concatenation, for example SDLC 80.
Let's look at an example of doing the concatenation OK.
Maybe I can say God and I can see Greek.
And I say, OK, string.
And copy.
Maybe I am going to initialize this with I and then maybe I'm going to add Bing.
The function is string S.T.A.R.T., OK, now I'm going to say, OK, you add something to this string.
How are you?
Maybe I want to concatenate this string I followed by how so?
Maybe I can see the old grade and then and.
So this should be like this.
And now we can run this code.
So you can see.
Hi, how are you?
The concatenation is working as expected with, hey, you are spending this spring our if you'll give
us base here or here, and that would also reflect, right?
So, hi, how are you?
So this is an example of a string and garden nation.
Similarly, you have functions for doing string comparison.
For example, this can compare it with strengths.
There are functions for searching inside a string, for example, you want to locate the first occurrence
of a character in a string, you can use this method or if you want to locate a substring, you can
use this method to let us look at the documentation.
How to use one of these methods?
OK.
OK, so I'm going to give you a demo of two functions, one is the structure function on the other is
a string compare function, OK?
Let us look at this function.
So it basically finds a second string inside the first string on it returns a null pointer if string
blue is not a part of the first string, OK?
And let us look at an example.
Maybe I have.
Let me open up a new program and I can say a strange function.
These string functions.
Recover some gold, and maybe I can initialize us, and it's got something intense.
And let's say the sentences.
I love reading books.
On, let's say.
Thanks.
I suppose I want to find out a word which I will take as input, so I will say, OK, I I will agree
on word that can be as big as the sentence I will take and put the word.
And we will try to search for the word inside the sentence.
I can see.
SDR is the search for the word.
Let's look at the documentation, right?
So.
It does, except the sentence and award, so the sentence would be sentence and the word would be OK.
Maybe I'll will just output what this is going to return.
And not like these string functions to.
So it is waiting for the word, so maybe the world is book.
So what it does return, it does return a to the location from where the doing his phone look.
So I'll just tell you why this output?
Why did we get this out?
It actually returned us.
Something of the type God has done, which points to this location, OK, and when we l-cio, OK, you
want the printer corrected, it would start from this index.
OK, to how old gets an orchid?
There is a list of collectors which starts from this location, so this guy to start is the address
of this location, and hence it could found the location and it prints everything till the end.
OK?
So if you want to make this as a Boolean, you can say maybe gonna start out whatever.
Is this output?
You're starting this in in a pointed video and you're checking if this output is equal to null, that
means you're going to see out.
This world is not on.
OK.
And.
As you can see, this world is found.
So maybe what is?
Found.
And yeah, that's how we are going to do it.
Maybe I can say.
Book is book is found if I see books.
Books is not phone book, so this is not dead.
And even if I have a substring like ITN, right, this would be found to because it is part of the word
science.
And it would look for a substring inside a string.
Okay, so Ian is a substring, and hence it is so great.
So I hope you also understood this concept and an added function that we would like to discuss is string
compare that we will do in the next radio.