Everyone in this video will talk about string comparison, which is an important concept, so let's
say you're given those strings.
Let's say some string, let's say hello and we some other string, let's say hi and you want to compare
which string is larger or which string is smaller.
So basically, when we compare strings, we basically talk in terms of equality, character by character
again.
For example, if I wanted to say two strings, they are exactly equal to each of the characters should
match until you don't see analogy.
So now let's present which we don't, right?
But it does present in a regulator like this, OK?
And what I want.
Now, suppose I want to generate a very simple password.
Typekit Maybe I have some passwords stored in my system.
Let's say I have some expected password.
It said.
This is some string.
It's a one zero one zero.
OK.
And maybe I want the user to enter some password.
OK, oh sorry.
This shouldn't be a.
God's not expected by.
Now, this is actually not a very it's just appointed to do what are you doing this spring if you want,
you can make an area as well.
So what I will do, I will again put some letters and I will store them, you know, Eric old password.
OK, so what?
I can again, design password.
And I want to match whether these two are equal or not, OK, so maybe, maybe I can make a Boolean
function so boolean and I can say, Oh, check the password.
Where where I am getting Eric called password and I'm getting a pointer that is expected password.
OK, guys, start expected.
Now you may ask any name is also it 2.0, so we can also write it like this.
It does not make it, but the way these two are stored in the memory, they are little different.
Whereas the first one is a string that is stored in a read-only memory.
And the second one is actually an array that is stored in your stock, right?
And it can be updated because it's very it's not a constant string.
But the Iranian is also blind, and the way we're storing this string little we are, we are great.
We have created a poison pill that binds to this strong little tool that is also key.
That means bypassing dual function.
We can definitely send data like this.
Maybe I want to compare the two passwords.
Maybe I can say I want to return a Boolean.
If the passwords are equal, I will return true or if they're not equal, I will return false.
That is what I want to wait.
And what I can do, I can say, OK, I have a string that is some some password, which is like one
zero one zero.
So we can either rover this using a, let's say, Index II, and we have some input password as well,
which is getting stored in our area, right?
And we can also trade over this, let's say this is also in Park one zero one zero.
And then it would be like, maybe we can do that is there is also an index like we can use the same
index, OK?
We are going to match them location, location.
And since it is read only, we can definitely read it and this ad is read plus, right?
We can do both operations.
OK?
Maybe I can.
To index.
It starts from zero and I get do.
While the buzzword of index, it does not equal to the.
Unless we don't see a nail in the edit, we will.
We are going to compare the two letters, look, if we can jack, if I sort of index, if it does not
equal out any, any place, if it does not equal the expected password of index.
So we can definitely say, OK, there is a mismatch.
And we should return false.
Otherwise, we will go to the next index and we'll do the matching once we come out of the loop, begin
to return to the passwords.
They do match and we are done right.
So maybe we can see if some bad password we pass the password and the expected password if the match
begins, OK, the old log in successful.
And Al, and we can to else, maybe so try again.
Now what I have done, I've built my own comparison function, right?
So this should be done.
Well, it's actually expected by word we give it here.
OK, so there is a warning and there is an.
So the return type is actually bull, the bull is the return type in C++ Boolean.
Is it in Java, right?
And there is a warning that.
We missed out one records to C++, 11 does not allow this pointer to be created, but it is just a warning.
It's not note it, which is OK, so we are kind of doing a conversion from a string letter to cards.
So basically our God studies storing the location of a string letter, which is OK, we can do it and
it's a warning.
It's not an error.
So we can run this code.
So maybe we can go you.
The vile name is in password checkered.
Now we are it is waiting for password to get entered, so maybe hard one zero one zero two, it is log
in success.
Maybe I can say at 2020 it is driving, so we made an unsuccessful attempt to check the password, OK?
That is how we can compare those strings later by later on.
I hope you did understand this concept.
Now one thing we will discuss is we can also use inbuilt comparison to compare to strings that will
look in the next review.