Everyone, so in the last few days will be debate by strategic good on where we wrote our own comparison
function to compare to strength in this lecture.
What we are going to do, we are going to have, let's say, two words I'm willing to use in comparison
function to compare the two words OK, maybe the word one, it's already on word to its alternative.
I'm going to take input two words, let's say a word, one and word to.
And now we are going to compare if they're equally ignored.
So what we're into, we are going to use a function from sea is drink that is the library that works
on good activities.
It provides us function to work on sea style strings.
OK, so this connected, it is a sea style string.
And the library is C Street will get to the function that we have already seen.
One of the function is a story that tells us the land of the word.
Similarly, we have a function goal is to assume that compares whether the two words are equal or not.
What I will tell you is Donald.
At this library actually compares to strings being one in string two, and you can see it is accepting
the character is kept on, it is going to compare the first letter of each string if they're equal.
It continues with the following pairs until the characters before or until no time in another character
is reached.
So unless you hit another character, it is going to compare it with strings on.
It returns either less than zero or equal to zero if what the strings are equal and greater than zero
if the first corrected, that does not match as a greater value in string one, then in string Rachel
again, just try to show you a demo date.
So we are going to build this code and maybe we are going to output this.
OK, now if I clear this and maybe I'm going to run the code, then comparison.
OK, dodge logicians string comparison.
Let's say the first word is.
But and the second word is bagmen, because we are we are getting a negative number.
That means that the first string it is smaller than the second string.
OK, that means smaller means if you talk about the dictionary order, the bat would come first.
Then the second like man, Batman would come next, OK, so that is what it is trying to say, and maybe
I can show you if I give Batman on breakfast.
So it does give me a positive in digital.
Okay, that means this number is bigger or this string is greater than the string, but.
And if they have two equal strength, it does return a value that is equal to zero.
I hope you're getting to understand.
Maybe you can put it felt right if in comparison and if this is equal to zero, you can say, OK.
The out they are equal.
Words are equal.
Otherwise, maybe you can see as if the same does on what we can do is we can instead of calling them
functional again and again, we can store the result.
Here we can say, let's store the result of comparing those drinks.
And then we check what the result is.
And if a result is greater than zero, maybe you can say the out word one is great.
That means it appears after words to in dictionary.
OK.
On else, you can say.
The dictionary, I'm talking about an English dictionary in which the words odd according to a lexicography
order, OK, that is your dictionary order.
As it would be the other case, let me show you again, maybe Apple on Batman to Batman appears after
Apple in dictionary.
That's correct.
And if I have a.
And Apple, right?
So Apple appears after rape, and maybe if I give Apple Andy.
So again, we are getting the same thing, right?
So basically, let me let me give you something else.
I'd say.
Watch, too.
OK, that is fine.
That is fine, right?
Every tab on tablet cable rate table appears after DOB in dictionary, which is correct on Debian Dub
Words.
That is how we can use the string comparison function to compare to strings as a practice exercise.
What are you going to do?
You can write their own string compare method that accepts dual character arrays, and it does the comparison
letter well-rated.
You traverse.
You write a good doctor vs. both of them, and then you'd have done something based on whether they're
equal, greater or lesser.
So this is a homework for you.
Try doing it on your own right.