Hello, everyone.
In this lecture will solve a problem where we want to take put a string which is terminated by our dialogue
and we count the number of letters, digit and white spaces and other special symbols.
Before we hit the toilet, OK, for example, a sample input might look something like this.
Hello, five world.
Maybe someday in this case, you can see there are five plus five.
There are 10 letters that has one digit.
OK, two letters means Alphabet.
And there is a toilet and there are two white spaces, because that is what we need to print.
So the count of letters, alphabets and so on.
So first of all, we need a character ready to store the strength.
Maybe I can take that input and let us assume the largest string can fit in thousand size of error of
size 1000.
That's OK.
And it will actually depend upon the constraints of the problem.
So for now, we can assume that one doesn't is big enough to satisfy the constraints.
And then we will take input, right?
Obviously, we cannot use scene input because it also contains white spaces.
Those in will not work because of the behavior we have discussed.
We have to use in indoor guideline and we have total input.
And we have also to tell that this input can store maximum of 1000 letters.
So we have to pass that limit here as well.
And another thing is we have to tell, when do you stop reading this input?
So we stop reading this input and OK, do not entered new line.
By default, it terminates at New Line, but we want to tell it, OK, you stop reading.
Tell.
If I just show you, what is this input now, it would be the.
Same thing, right?
Maybe the problem is big problem.
Strange letter counting problem.
Maybe Halo five.
And how are you?
Five some star.
OK, question mark.
And maybe right now you're going to be getting the same string.
This is coming in the output.
That means the storage is correct.
All of them, they are stored in a linearity.
And what what actually happened is so in the input when we saw a download, it restored and null end
up in poverty.
I'll just repeat this thing.
So in words like say hello, followed by some space and maybe some toilet in the area that is created,
the great learning function is written down.
It will copy all the letters until it finds this monitor that we have specified.
It will replace this with an null letter because if we don't, we are not actually storing dial-up.
So you going to die?
Is not the part of the output, and printing happens unless we unless we don't see a null and output
in this satellite.
So it is printing up to this particular point right now.
Getting back to hit, right?
So what are we going to do in this case?
We are going to work with both the functions, which are on connectors.
So we include the see-through type library and we're going to include the C string library because it
might be required as well, right?
What we need to do, we need to iterate over this area.
It.
And we have to go go through a list of the characters, are those George, maybe what I can say are
equal to zero.
I list then OK, how do we attract rehydrate tell input of aid?
This is not equal unless we don't see unless we are going to iterate over the entirety and I'm going
to say, OK, the current corrected, it is equal to input off.I.
So let us try to see what this current character is, right?
We are trading and we are saying this is important.
And this is some index.
We are saying, see, it is going to hold this input of it.
This is it.
This is actually actually.
So now we have to classify this.
We have to count the number of letters that is Alphabet.
We need to see the alphabet count.
That is let's zero the digits count.
That is also zero.
The white spaces that is also zero and special symbols.
That is also right in the beginning, we have initialized for values which are zero.
Now what we can do begins, OK, are.
If we have.
If this siege, if it is Alphabet again, so either you can do it like this, if it is greater than
equal to any less than equal duty like we have done in one of the problems, or even use some inbuilt
method from the library.
OK, so you can use is alpha, right?
So is alpha, which you can say Alphabet C++.
Let's increment the count of Alphabet as if if it is a white space.
So the method is.
The matter that we had discussed.
I just followed them at their name.
Yes, it is, is space.
And you can see the number of whites business less plus as if we have digit rate, so the method would
must be is digit.
That is, I can say, did C++ right now, how do we look for special symbols, OK, I don't remember
any method to check if it is a special symbol or not.
So what I can do to others, right?
So everything is in others what I can do I can from the total end of the string, I can subtract the
value of alphabet white spaces and digits to get their count.
So this I will do after my loop is over.
So after the loop, what we know, we know, we know the alphabet, OK?
So maybe you're going to see out Alphabet as alphabet and del digits as digits.
And Al and, you know, white space is white space.
And on maybe special symbols, right?
Don't count, let's try to see that.
Maybe I can say.
Symbol count, this should be actually equal to the total length of the string that does not include
eight, because it is not stored and it does not include as well, that is how its and works.
So the total length would be a straight line of input on this function is coming from C string or minus
alphabet minus digits on minus white spaces.
So this, I'm assuming, would be your special symbols.
And that's it.
No, let us try to run this code.
And the court is building fine.
And strangely, the accounting problem.
So maybe a little five.
How are you?
Five Bass not.
And or harsh and maybe a dollar, right?
It says we have 14 alphabet digits, two yes, five is coming to names wide spaces at four.
So one whitespace here, that is the new line, right?
We did a box and hit it with three and four.
Yes, we have three spaces and one new line, which is four correct and we have one special symbol,
which is this one.
Absolutely correct.
Circle is working perfectly fine.
So I think that this example we could quickly recap a lot of concepts that we have started till now.
And that's all for this video.