I say in this lecture, we're going to talk about or to recruit terrorists.
And let's see.
So basically, in order to define a two degree activity, you can actually do use that I've got, followed
by name of the Eddy.
And this is one way in which you can in each laser to that it will get another way could be you can
write numbers off the number of rules and the maximum number of columns that you will support.
I will go ahead.
The number of rules is optional.
If you are giving a initialization list like this.
Then you can also do it like this, let's say a followed by B, followed by a C, followed by null.
This is one thing.
Then maybe second row second is easy or only.
And so the the thing is this way is not very this doesn't look good and it involves a lot of work to
write this kind of index as well.
So what we do, we write each row as a string.
So each row, each ring actually represents a linear idea because if you see in the memory level what
is going to happen, this is going to.
This is going to be a grid in which we are going to have approximately exactly 10 columns in each row.
So this is how it is going to get stored, and I will just show it to you how these are going to get
stored.
We have one, so we will have you here and here.
We had followed by an.
We have to be W or no.
We have three b h e none.
And so on.
OK.
The number of columnists and columns, that means this index was from zero to nine.
And the number of those is decided by how many elements we have here.
Up to this.
We have.
But this is how it would be corrected at a store, and now you may ask, OK, if I want to print a particular
role, how I can do it, so you can simply do see out numbers of some.
So I think this will print the entire rule.
And if you simply do numbers of like Ma0, it will print the zero correct provided or this will print
the first character off.
I had thought, maybe let's say I use five zero one two three.
Let's say is three, we are talking about digital.
And let me show it to you.
We should protocols and we call on here.
And if I had underscored.
I'd like to the connectivity.
And you going to be regarding the letter all here?
That means this we are talking about this letter.
And if I simply do OK, I want to print the I at all, then it is going to print.
The entire row.
OK, so you going to this is branding 40?
We're going to even read over all the rules I can say for integral to zero.
I less than.
Six plus plus, I can see out numbers of I.
If I were to scold, if I run it, you're going to be able to print all the strings.
So this is a behavior that is little different from the indeed it it is.
And if you simply do print this address.
So this this is actually the address.
OK.
This is not the entire thing.
The number of I actually print the entire electorate.
OK.
But if you printed foreign indeed it, Eddie, this is not going to happen.
Suppose if I change this day today and I finish laser in rigidity and then this is, then you will get
an address, OK?
So this is because code read character that is differently, OK?
See, outrage corrected.
That is differently.
And it is.
A behavior that is conditionally written inside, does the old statement look, it doesn't happen for
all types of errors, it only happens for the character it is.
OK, so I hope you understood how we can represent an array of strengths as a 2D character, Eddie.
So that's it.
That's all for this lecture.
Thank you.