Everyone in this section, we will talk about big manipulation techniques, and these are nothing,
but these are some.
Maybe you can do algorithms using which you can modify the data are binary representation level on every
programming language provides us some database operators which allow us to operate under binary representation
of the data that we have.
OK.
So we will look how to use these, these operators, what are the different types of device operators
and how we can use them to solve some problems, OK?
And the reason why we use Bitwise operators sometime is because they operate on the binary representation
of the data, and they're fast as compared to the use the non device operators.
And what are the different types of operators you can see on the screen?
And we are going to talk about kind, odd zade ones complement.
Binary left shift and binary like, OK, so these are the Bitwise operators, and if you're new to them,
so let us explore each of them one by one.
So the first one is a binary.
And so basically, let's say and has very simple rules, let's say you have two bits.
One, and it's another zero.
So if you do and with a zero, then it is going to give you a result of zero.
Similarly, zero and one is going to give you a verdict of zero, and only when would the are said.
Only then you will get the result of one and zero and zero.
There's also going to be zero.
So anything done and with zero is going to give you a zero.
OK, so these are the simple rules of doing a simple end.
And now what?
How do we use it?
OK, let's say I have a number five and I do, and with seven, then what I'm going to get.
So let's see.
So five five in binary is represented as zero zero zero, followed by two one zero one and select selected
32 or 64 bit number seven and binary can be represented as lots of zeros, followed by triple one.
If you do, and so it will happen on.
Bit by bit level.
OK, so one and one is one zero and one is zero one and one is one and followed by large subtitles.
OK.
So if you convert this number back into the decimal, you will see this result is going to be like.
This is how binary end looks.
So I hope this is clear.
And now let's see what is binary.
So the rules of the order very simple.
If one of the bits is one, then the result is going to be one, for example one.
Or zero?
Is going to give you.
Well, guess what, this is denoted using this operated one or zero is going to give you one.
Similarly, zero or one is going to give you one zero or zero is going to give you a zero on one or
one is going to give you one.
So if one of the breaks is one, then the resulting bid would be one.
For example, if I do five or with eight.
OK, so what is five?
Five is one zero one?
What is it?
It is one triple zero.
Yes.
And if you do an audit, what you're going to get, you're going to get one here, one head, zero head
and one here.
So what does this number?
This is eight.
This is four.
This is two and this is one.
So if you are eight plus four plus one.
So this number is actually 13.
OK.
So these are actually powers of two to do this to divide.
Zero to raise divide one to days to divide, do and do this to divide three.
So you can see I'm doing eight plus four plus one, that is 13.
OK, so this number is actually 13.
So if you do this in your code, you will get an output of 13 in this particular case.
So I hope binary order is also clear.
Now let us move on to those.
So that is also known as exclusive.
OK?
OK.
Exclusive.
So what are the rules of Zod?
So it basically means if both debates are same, then there is going to be zero, for example, zero
zero zero is zero.
And also one are zero or three ones, or one is also zero.
If both the exact same, the result is zero.
Otherwise, if both debates are different than there is a this one.
So if I show you, maybe if I do five.
Zod seven.
So five is what five is zero zero zero one zero one and seven is zero zero triple one.
If I do aside hit, then one or one is going to be zero zero is going to be one.
This is going to be zero and lots of zeros.
This result is going to be two.
OK, so if you do something like the old five or seven, then it is going to print it in your goal.
OK.
So I hope you understood this, though, operator as well.
So the next and that we're going to discuss is not OK.
So the NOT is a very simple operator.
So what what it does if I have a big zero, OK, this is this is not the endangered zero.
This is the bait zero.
So if you do or not of zero, you're going to get one and the is you do not off some number.
OK, let's say you have a number like zero zero zero one zero one later.
This number is five.
If you do the NADA five, then it is going to flip all the birds or OK, so not of one is zero.
I'm not sure this is going to be lots of one's, followed by zero one zero.
OK.
So this you will see it is going to flip all the birds, including the most significant bit.
That is the sign.
OK, that is the sign.
But that means this number could be a negative number as well, OK?
Now, if you have little idea here, I can give you one example.
Let's take something like this.
Let's say take A. And either in days zero and I simply do see out, not Duffy.
Then what you're going to expect, OK, well, what would be done that?
The answer is going to be actually not one, but it would be minus one.
OK, now you may wonder why, why it is so.
So if you look zero at the memory level to what a zero zero is a 32 bit number in which.
Everything is everything is zero, all the side zero.
If you do a lot of it, you will get all that little bits.
As once, OK?
And.
All the better ones and the most significant, but represents the sign.
OK, so if this sign is one that means it is a negative number, so that means it is a negative number
and the remaining 31 words they represent.
The magnitude look now for the negative numbers, if we want to find out the magnitude of that particular
number.
These numbers are stored in a form known as those complement form.
OK, that's stored enough to complement one.
So in order to find out what number is this, what we need to do, we need to out those compliment.
That means invert all the words and add one to it.
OK?
The number is this does this in order to find the magnitude, we have to first invert all the bits.
If not all of it, it becomes like this.
And then I will add one do it.
This number is zero zero zero zero zero one.
So basically, this is a negative number with the magnitude of one.
And this number is actually minus one.
OK.
So if you do not zero and where the are indeed it, you are going to get minus one as output, OK?
And nor does zero where zero is a.
It would be one.
OK.
So that is something that you should be very careful while working on.
So that's something you can trade on your own as well.
OK, if you don't trust me, I'm going to show you there, then why is it that this cold where I have
zero and I'm doing the 0.5X?
So let us run this code and see what we get as a output study, and this should be a dog slash bitwise.
So you can see this output is actually minus one.
That is because of the same reason I have disclosed.
OK, so doing a negation of all zeros gives us a number in which all numbers are ones and center distort
to complement form the first but denotes design work.
The remaining would be not the magnitude.
And in order to find the exact magnitude, we have to take those compliment.
So this process is known as it was complement where we invert all the bits and add one to it.
And whatever you get this number, this is the magnitude of the number.
OK.
So if you convert this number into decimal, this number is one and sign saying this minus one because
the most significant bit is one.
OK.
So I hope this is clear.
Now you understand that doing the negation of a mate zero is one and doing the negation of integer zero
is minus one.
It's an important concept.
So I have explained it to you.
So binary, inarticulate.
Now we will talk about two more operators left and right shift in the neglected.