Everyone know we're going to talk about binary left shift.
So what does this operator so generally you will find us operated a little like this.
Let's have five left shift.
So what does it mean?
It basically means we have a number five.
OK.
And whatever it is, the bet it has.
We're going to leave shift all the bits by a factor of two.
So everything is going to move towards lived by a factor of two.
So what?
What will happen?
These two bits will fall off, OK?
And you will have something like this.
Zero zero one zero one.
And from here, you will add those zeros.
OK.
So you lied like this if you try to understand what is different in this number?
So this was two days to bar zero.
This was to raise the bar one.
This was directly part two bar to are two stories to the bar zero to to one.
And this is to raise the bar two.
This is two arrested bartenders as directed by.
What is the original number?
So original number is five.
OK.
And that is equal to those squared.
Love Story 3.0, and we know this is faith.
And let let let us call this number as.
Now if I talk about this number.
OK, so what is this number?
So it does nothing, but it does do squirt less door for it.
If you take two square common you're left with, you're left with two squared plus two arrested, about
zero.
That means it has two squared off the original Number X, basically doing a left shift by two.
Has multiplied that number by two squared.
OK.
So basically a left shift B will multiply a with it days to the power B.
This is what I'm trying to say.
And if you see what is this number?
This number is nothing but 16 plus four.
This number is 20.
Effectively have got multiplied by two days to.
But that is five in the water district.
Effectively, when you do a left shift, the number is multiplied with the power of two.
So this is the left shift operator.
I hope this one is now clear.
Similarly, we also have something known as a right shift.
The left shift does multiplication right shift divides OK?
Let us start with one example.
Let's say I have a number 10, and if I do a right shift with one, that means I'm going to divide by
two days to divide one.
OK.
So if I show you this number, then in binary is one zero one zero.
And that means if this is the number, doing the right shift means we are moving every bit towards right
by one step.
This bit will get discarded, and the original number would become zero zero zero one zero one.
OK.
And clearly, we know this number is five.
So if we do 10 right shift one, that means divide by 10, divided by two to one.
This number is five and this number is also five.
Again, if you do right, shift one here, it's a hard number.
You should get to this doing right shift one had means zero zero zero.
This one will fall off and we will get something like this one zero.
So this number is two.
Does this same as doing five divided by two this terrible one?
That is OK.
And similarly, if you do it once again, you will end up getting zero zero zero one.
And this number is one.
And let's do it once more.
You will do zero zero zero zero.
This number would be zero.
If I do 10 right shift four, then that means 10 divided by two ways to divide four.
And that is 16.
So this number would be zero.
OK.
So eight night shift basically means eight divided by two days to ever be OK.
So I hope both left shift and right shift are now clear to you on in the coming lectures, we will see
some examples where these operators can be used.
That's all for this lecture.
Thank you.