Hello, everyone, in this section, we will dig deeper into C++ concept and we will talk about your
things like what is a pre processor that active water keywords on identifiers?
What is the significance of mean and what is the concept of namespaces, OK?
As a beginner, you might find some of these concept little Typekit, but as you get comfortable with
the course, the understanding of your these concepts would even become deeper.
OK.
This is a brief introduction about a few of the things that I've listed here.
So in the beginning, we'll start with the preprocessor that we need to understand two things at what
is a directive or directive is kind of a statement that that the compiler to do some kind of a book.
The processors are special kind of directives which give instructions to the compiler about reprocessing
some code before the actual compilation starts.
OK?
Now, in the previous module, we have seen that we can easily do input output using the incident.
OK.
But there is certain code that needs to be pre-processed before that functionality starts working for
you.
OK.
So it is a pre-processed directive is used to pre-processed some code before the actual compilation
starts, and you will observe the directive begins with the hash.
So we have seen the example of ash in glorious stream.
And the actual code is being compiled by the compiler only, so let us see an example the hash in glued
is an example of a preprocessor.
OK.
So what this hash include is the compiler.
OK, you go and be pre-processed the code that is there in the file stream.
So Extremism header file, which contains some code for doing input and output.
So the code for input and output.
Is written in a special fight.
That is a header file, and the name of the file is extremely harsh and stealing the compiler to include
this header file in the source code, I guess, or during compilation.
It is also going to pre-processed the code that is written in Io Stream.
It's only then you can use the in ENCODE because the code that is responsible for doing input and output
is present in this particular file.
Look, that is an example of a hash include directive.
So similarly, there are other examples also where you can have you can have other type of directives
also, for example, and in the day before that activist as defined, it will under different orders
that you can include one hydrofoil.
And later on, you will see that there are different data sectors like stock or queue.
You want to include the implementation of that particular data, as it did in your code, so you can
include the header file of that particular data center as well.
Using the ASH include that Active two has defined that active is used to define symbolic constants and
let us see an example.
OK.
These symbolic constants, they're also known as macro.
So what happens when you define something like this the user has defined I'm defining a constant by
that is based on the value of this by is three point one foot to what what does it happen is it's a
symbolic quantum.
That means whenever the compiler will encounter this symbol, OK?
The gold will be replaced by the value of that particular symbol or the value of by, we have defined
as 3.1 port in this score, whenever the compiler is going to process this line and in line number six
or in any line, wherever you have, wherever you encounter this constant buy, it will be replaced
with the value three point one four.
So that is the importance of this hash defined that it will get.
And this is also known as macros.
We have defined a macro byte whose value is 3.1 four.
So what we are saying is all subsequent occurrences of the macro in the source code will be replaced
by its replacement text.
So this is actually a replacement text.
This value is not stored in any memory like it out, it's just a replacement text.
OK, it's not creating any bucket in the memory.
It's just in your source code.
Wherever you write this content, it will be replaced by its replacement text, so replacement text
is a better term as compared to to value something that was stored inside.
So it's not actually a value, it's a replacement text before the program is compiled.
OK, and this replacement happens before this court is compiled.
Because of binary, you're going to compile this code.
It will process discordance three point one four multiplied by odd into this is what the macro is.
So I hope you have understood you've got an idea about preprocessor directives, so I've given you two
examples.
One is the hash include A..
There is a defined directive.
There are also directives like if?
Or something like that.
But this is sufficient for now.
In the next, we will talk about a next concept of identifies you in the next lecture.