Everyone in this lecture will talk about Randy Fires and a little bit about variables as well.
OK, what is an identified identifier is derived from the word identity.
Basically, whenever you want to identify some entity in your program, you define its name using identified
so identified as just kind of a name.
OK, so so what?
And then divide on the variable.
There are the names allotted by the users to particular entity in the program who is a user.
It's actually the programmer.
The programmer can give any name of his choice to a particular entity in the program.
What could be an entertainer program?
So an example of entity could be a function.
OK, maybe I want to compute a function, and that function gives me the factorial of a number.
Let's see.
So maybe I can create a function whose name is factorial?
And it could be some bucket where I'm going to store some data.
So maybe you want to store some data and that data is stored in that particular bucket called ledger
marks.
So you look, I want to store some marks and that Marks is equal to 80.
Mox is actually identified, but since it is also holding some memory, so we call this Mox as a variable.
OK?
We call this as a variable.
You can have functions or functions are nothing, but it's a group of instructions that are trapped
inside a block of code.
And we need to give it.
Give it some name.
OK?
For example, Victoria will adopt certain instruction inside it.
The logic to compute the Victorian OK, so identified as only used to identify an entity uniquely in
the program at the time of execution.
Whereas a variable is a name given to a memory location that is used to hold the value because it's
a memory location and we are giving it some name.
We are saying that Marks is a variable and we are identifying this variable marks by the name of marks
identified as just a name, wherever the concept of variable means the bucket as well, OK?
Identified as just a name and variables do have a name.
OK.
And when we say variable, it also means the bucket where the data is being stored, OK?
The name of the bucket is just to identify it.
There is a very slight difference between the two items identified as just a name wherever it bucket.
The variable is a bucket, which also has a name.
OK, so identifiers can be used to give names to the buckets, to the bunch of lines of code, to the
classes and so on.
I hope you have understood this slight distinction between the concept of a variable and a bucket.
I suppose you have two dogs.
And these four, these two dogs, you want to store information in the memory, OK?
What are you doing?
You're going to create some kind of bucket which can hold a dog and maybe you can give this bucket a
name.
Maybe you can say this dog is screwed up.
OK.
And it's stored, OK?
This dog has curly hair.
It has a height of eight or something, something like this, and we'll be in for another dog.
Maybe you want to create another bucket that is brutal.
OK.
The name of the bucket.
Is identified, whereas the bucket itself.
Is a variable look, it's kind of a variable or object.
So that's what I wanted to convey.
And let us have this example.
We want to identify the identifiers, OK?
Let us see who can do it.
So I hope you have given it a try.
So if you look carefully now, this is actually a function in C++.
The function is a block of code that robs certain instructions inside it.
So we are actually sending three things to this function.
So we are sending.
B, C and M, which might refer for the marks in physics, chemistry and maths, and we are saying,
look, these names PCM, they identify a bucket.
OK.
They are the names of variables, so they are identifiers and this is the name of the function.
This is also entered divide, so calculate marks.
It is also a name that has been defined by the program at.
And there is also a variable average that is also.
Defining the name of the bucket, which we call it as a bridge, all of them are identified.
OK.
And.
From all the Red Devils, except calculate marks, bcm and average, they're actually very much look.
That name is identified, but what they are, they're actually variables because they're holding some
data inside it.
They are variables as well.
OK, so that is what is the difference between an identifiable and variable?
We'll dive deeper into the concept and will you'll get more comfortable as we do more coding questions,
and this will bring a lot of clarity in the coming lectures as well.
OK, so that's all for this video.
Thank you.