I in this lecture will talk about keywords, which is quite an important concept when it comes to learning
a programming language.
Every language has keywords on whether keywords, so keywords, special words that have a special meaning
for the compiler will get.
That means they are kind of resolved.
You cannot use these names for any other purpose, like you cannot use these keywords for giving a name
to a function or giving a name to a variable.
You cannot use them, OK.
These keywords cannot be used as identified.
That is what you need to know on C++ as 95 reserved words.
So you do not need to memorize how many keywords are there or what all those keywords.
But I will give you a quick look of what kind of words in a programming language like C and C++.
You will find and we can call them as keyword tool kit.
For example, a word like LS, you will use it very frequently word like long, which is kind of a data
type.
It's like double auto brake.
God, Gonzales Lord.
Continue.
OK.
So we are going to see a lot of them while we are going to write code, OK?
All these are examples of keywords, right?
And there are 32 keywords which are both common in C and D Plus Plus, and there are some new keywords
which were introduced in C++, for example.
A keyword is a namespace is a keyword.
Rent is a world class, is a keyword.
The glass is used in object oriented programming.
D is not an object oriented language, but C++, as C++ has the keyword called class and that is true.
Falls and type name public private operator OK.
A lot of lot of keywords you can see are dead and you cannot use these keywords.
Giving a name to a particular variable look.
So if we go to this particular code and what we want to identify what all key words this code is using.
So if you look at from the previous example that ended up given in the very beginning and discovered
this in dissolve turkey, but if it also achieved OK, this is achieved, this far is achieved, this
it had done is achieved.
OK.
And.
Yeah.
So you can see there are a lot of key words we are using in our particular program.
OK.
And we're going to see this Ford is actually a key word, right?
That is what I was trying to show you here.
This fight isn't even particularly vile.
It'll give it these key words.
Each word has a special meaning.
For example, the four key word is used to create a loop and loop is used.
If you want to do something again and again in every program, you will find there are certain keywords
which are specific to that particular language, and many different languages can also have same keywords,
for example.
The fight is also given in Java.
It's also keyword invite.
Then it's a very commonly used keyword, right?
And that's all about key words that you need to know, and in the next few days, we'll talk about the
concept of mean.