Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we're going to talk about namespaces, OK, so the concept of namespaces is has been
created to avoid naming conflicts when you can use multiple third party libraries in the same program.
Whenever you're writing code, you are importing some code, like from India while you're importing
few things.
And if you use multiple libraries.
OK, so it may happen that two people develop two different libraries and they created a common function
for the same.
OK.
One example there is a popular choice that is a popular library, which is known as open TV.
And it is for basically used for tasks related with image processing.
OK.
And what may happen is not two different beams later, these libraries, and that was the team that
created C++.
Let us assume they created a function called print.
OK.
And that except in digit.
And they print that integer on the screen.
But let us say there is these people are open to, let's say they also created a library and they created
a function called print.
And maybe this except the image, and it draws that image on the screen.
It.
Now, the functionality of this brain function would be very different from the functionality of this
brain function, but they have the same name.
Now how do we get to know that OK, if are using both the libraries in the world, for example, if
you write some good news, OK, I want to include iOS stream.
Because I also want to print Indigenous and I also want to use opens even my library because maybe I
want to look with images as well.
I mean, we should include open TV.
I include both of these libraries in my code.
Now in your mean or in your other function, you're saying, OK, I want to use the brain function.
Now, how do you identify which brain function is this one?
Is it the brain function coming from the C++ library or is it the brain function coming from the open
TV C++ library?
This is this is actually creating a kind of a confusion.
So how do we resolve this conflict?
So we resolve this conflict by defining the namespace before the function?
So these OK, if it is coming from the C++ library, those C++ library defines all its functions and
in entire classes inside a namespace which is known as SD.
OK, that means the standard name of the C++ namespace and openly will be able to find everything inside
the namespace called TV.
If I want to use the function from this open TV space or namespace, I will say, OK, it is equal and
go and OK.
That means the brain function from the open living space.
Or if they want to use this function, I can look at study.
Brent, maybe use this particular function to namespaces odd used to.
Avoid conflicts because and when you're using multiple libraries.
Few of the things, they can have common names, but I hope you understood what what is the concept
at the high level to avoid data structure and function name conflicts?
OK, so even and there can be two different researchers which behave in a different manner, but they
might get the same name because it was created independently by two different teams.
But each team will define its own namespace.
OK, so open TV has its own namespace, which is known as S.V.
And if you does, OK, I will not define.
Wee, every bit I will just show you, the good to study is the namespace for the standard it as a name
for the standard C++ namespace and writing studio code, for example, you want to use the object code
and this object belongs to the standard namespace.
It will tell the compiler to use code from the standard namespace by default when we are writing code.
I will just give you a quick demo as well.
So.
OK, so this is one of the code that we have written, so we are saying it using names.
So that means all the data, such names, all the function names that we are using in this code they
belong to, the standard is OK.
So we are just kind of saying, OK, you don't ask me which namespace see belongs to or which namespace
code belongs to.
Everything belongs to the standard namespace, OK?
That is why we have included this line in the beginning so that we don't have to tell compile it again
and again.
But suppose you don't include this line in your code, and let's say we're building this code.
And this time I'm not writing using names, but as Julie.
So let me see if this file and maybe say a namespace demo or TPP.
If it's intimate.
And I feel out, it's a hello world.
Let us see what happens if you use something from a standard name spit and without telling the compiler.
This is this code belongs to the standard namespace.
Let's see what happened in this case.
OK.
The file name is names beside them.
We are going to compile this.
We can say the C++ namespace got damaged or ZBB.
And now you can see that.
It is saying error.
Use of undeclared identify it the out it says, did you mean s2.0?
It is giving you a recommendation that this identified is not declared.
OK.
So although this object exists in the library, I was dream.
But but.
Every object should come from a namespace, the name is a region where all these names are declared
OK, so they are not defined.
Declared.
So in order to use anything, the declaration is also important or equally as their definition.
One thing is how to create that object that is given a new stream.
OK.
And another thing is registering the name of the object with this compiler, that thing that registering
the name is known as declaration.
We are telling the compiler, OK, and there is something known as C out how code works.
It is in our stream, but we have to register this name.
That is that it is stored in the namespace of C++, which is goes by the name as Judy.
So a study is the name of the standard C++ names.
In this course, we are only going to follow one namespace that is a standard C++ namespace and everything
is declared.
And this namespace was the OTAs declared here.
The declared here.
OK.
Either you include the entire namespace.
OK, that will mean all the things are coming from the standard namespace.
But if you just want to use this code, not everything else from the start namespace, you're going
to study well, then go out.
OK, I'm saying the code that has been declared inside the standard namespace.
Use that and print Hello world.
OK, so now if I build my code again?
And now you can see it works perfectly fine and I can run it using it out.
So it says hello, so this is working well, firstly, fine either you do this, but if you do this,
you have to use it with every statement like you have actually seen and do some work.
And or whatever is the number that you want to take in, so you're going to end then and begin to then
write something like this?
So let's build the gold again, and let's say I want to run it again, so I will dig and put another
five.
So one runways, you use a study with all the researchers, all the objects are all the functions that
you want to use from the standard namespace.
The database you OK, I will only follow the standard namespace.
And dressed everything, I will figure it out on my own right.
Maybe what you're going to do if you're using working with the image processing library and you also
want to.
Maybe include open TV.
This needs to be installed separately.
You can also include two namespaces.
Insider gold and now a conflict will arise if you have a method to print and it exists in both the namespaces.
Let's say it exists in a steady namespace also, and it exists in the sea names.
But also then you have to specify, OK, I'm talking about the print method that is there in the CV
namespace, something like this.
So this will help you to avoid any naming conflict that may arise that that is all about named basis.
I wanted to talk to you.
And that's all for this video.
I hope you find it a little helpful.
Thanks a lot.