Hello, everyone.
So till now, we have been writing programs on in some of the programs, you might have seen that I've
written something that starts from the last.
This thing is actually known as a comment.
OK, so what is a common comment is just a piece of text that is ignored by the compiler.
It is basically to tell.
It's basically to annotate what your code is doing.
Or we can use this command to explain something inside the code.
OK, so it's just a piece of text that is used to enter the code, and it is ignored by the compiler
because this is not executed by the compiler.
And we can also use comments to make certain lines of the code inactive.
For example, I don't want to take input that I want to make this part inactive.
I can command out this particular line.
We can also command out multiple lines by defining a comment like this.
OK?
So this is known as a multi line comment.
So if you start from the baseline.
So this creates a single line comment.
OK.
Anything that is written below will not be a comment.
So this is an example of a multi line comment that I'm trying to show you is here.
So, for example, I want to comment this part out.
So I will start with backslash start.
I will write the comment and I will end with Star Backslash.
So this creates a Maryland comment.
So these are two type two ways of commenting your code in C++.
So we have seen that we can write a single line automatically line comment in a C++ program.
So that's all for this video.
Thank you.