So let us recap what we have learned in this particular section.
The first thing we have learned is about keywords.
Two keywords other terms that have special meaning for the compiler and they are resolved.
Second thing we learned about identifiers to identifiers are the names that are used to name an entropy
variable name is also a type of identified.
And third thing we talked about header files.
These files contain some pre-written good that is required to provide additional functionality inside
of a program.
The program execution always starts would mean this you need to remember on curly brackets, they are
used to enclose a block.
So this block can be a block of function.
It can be a block of if it can be block of file.
So these concepts we are going to see in the next sections to C++ compiler ignores whitespace.
OK, so that means in your code, you can have as many white spaces as you want.
So all the spaces, new lines, Dobbs, they are ignored by the compiler when it is compiling the code
book.
So for example, if you are writing and you can give a single space, or maybe you're going to end,
followed by a lot of space, followed by OK, then maybe you can leave these two lanes empty, then
you will gained.
Some see that is equal to, let's say, A-plus, because something like this, all these spaces that
ignored by the company that OK, it is only what is the actual part of the code that does the thing
that only matters for the compiler.
The output is done using code and input is done using scene.
So both of them are special objects.
And right now we have not talked about object oriented programming, so I will not dive into the details
of how out or housing works.
So we'll discuss them later on.
OK.
And we have seen the water comments.
So there are two ways a single engagement and a multi comment on last night were the list.
So every statement must end with a semicolon.
So you will see that most statements that you write, they end with a semicolon.
OK.
That is what you need to remember inside.
This module, and that's all for this video.