Everyone in this section, we are going to learn about loops, two loops are a very fundamental concept
in a programming language, and they're used when you want to repeat some work again and again.
OK, so the first example of a loop or the first kind of a loop that we will see is a value.
OK?
And we'll write a loop.
Suppose you're running on a treadmill and you want to 100 calories, OK?
So we'll see what are the components of the loop.
So in flowchart, if you remember what we did, if we wanted to repeat an operation again and again,
we'd draw something like this.
Physiology will have a starting value.
Let's say I start from one.
And we defined a stopping condition, took a little bit of an isolate, is I less than equal to 10?
OK, so if this is true, then we will talk.
It will do some work.
Maybe we will run on the machine.
And will increment the value of that is equal to this one.
And again, we connected back here, OK?
And if this condition is false, we actually came out of this flow and maybe we look at exit.
Our work is done right.
So now what is this?
This is actually a loop, right?
So if you go through this flow chart, you will observe that this process alone increment by Jack IRA
and increment by Jack.
This is going to happen 10 times, right?
So we are actually repeating some instruction.
Inside inside a look book is let's see how we can write this using a value.
So when you're going to use a value, we are going to define some initial condition, let's say like
equal to one.
OK.
So while the condition is so this loop is going to run all the time when the condition is true, let's
say delay is less than equal to 10, right?
So that condition will go ahead.
And then we will we are going to execute some stuff.
Maybe we we can look at.
We are running a one step.
We are running one step on the machine.
OK.
And update.
We also need to update the value of.
So that is your called libellous one.
To all these steps, go inside the blog of the do you have any condition?
You have a stopping criteria, you have the book that you want to do, the work that you want to repeat.
And this is the update condition.
OK, the way the public statement, actually the way you're going to update the value of I and I is
going to control when the loop should run or when it should stop.
So let me show you a quick demo of value.
So let's go into the good will, right?
A very basic program here.
And.
Will collect calories equal to one, so in calories equal to one, or maybe calories equal to zero.
So while calories is less than 10, what I'm going to do, I'm going to run on the machine.
Maybe I can say running a step and burning on many calories later, after burning a step, I actually
burn one calorie so I will print calorie plus one hit and I took calorie equal local groups, one in
the memory I'm updating.
The actual value of calorie has been implemented by one.
So let's see.
Let's see the output here.
So dogfish while loop, which is running a step on blending one gallery, two gallery three gallery
up to 10, right?
So we are out of the loop when the value of calories is actually golden.
OK, so maybe here you can print out of the look and see out the final value of calories, so that would
be the end to this loop would stop when the value of calories becomes equal to then, right?
So you can see out of the loop and the value of calories lost in this loop actually executed this statement
10 times, OK?
So this loop looked for band names.
And what would happen if you somehow forget this, OK?
In this case, you will end up in an infinite loop.
That means the value of calories would always remain zero and zero is always less than 10.
So it is going to run in finite times.
OK, so that is why this update statement is very important whenever you are writing a loop.
Similarly, this condition is also very important if you put something like calories greater than zero.
So what would happen in this case?
In that case, you will not enter the loop because the value of calories is initially zero.
OK, so you have to write these conditions very carefully, and that's all for the value.
And in the next part, we will discuss some examples.