Everyone in this body will talk about break and continue statements, which are also very important
in controlling the flow of the law.
First, we will talk about the brake statement.
Now think of a scenario you would in a gym on.
You were trying to burn calories and your girlfriend called you in the middle of the workout and she
asked you to go for dinner.
OK, so maybe you decide to stop the workout and you come out of that loop of running on the treadmill
and you decide to go for dinner, right?
So that is where the break statement is going to helpful.
If you want to stop the loop in the middle of a workflow, that is where the break statement comes into
picture.
So I'll show you one real example.
So what?
We will write some code on.
We'll try to simulate this condition of break.
OK, so maybe break the mold out CPB and just to start with, maybe we can have some boilerplate code
and
Ant-Man.
Now, maybe you go to the gym you started from zero calories on your target was to achieve I'm burning
like 230 calories.
So while calories less than equal or less than 30, you are maybe running on the treadmill.
Running, running on, maybe you can print how many calories you have burned.
Maybe running and burning these many galleries.
Now suppose at some point, maybe when 112 110 calories.
Your girlfriend calls you up, so maybe will simulate this condition using this variable, their girlfriend
will call you up.
I 10 goals so you can check if the calories burned.
If this is equal to girlfriend calls up, that means I need to stop the workout.
Okay, so I need to stop here.
So you going to break?
Otherwise you continue in your loop and you say, OK, read C++ because we are running, we are burning
galleries.
And finally, you can say out of the loop now there are two ways of coming out of the loop.
Once when this loop is over.
But in this loop, we have put a conditional statement that if this condition becomes true, we will
break this brake statement.
What it is going to do, it is going to take you out of the loop.
When it is executed, OK, when it is executed.
Let me show you the output, and that would allow for more clarity to you.
So let us try to see this in action.
So.
Let's go ahead and try to run the break demo.
So maybe now you can see we will run Intel one two three four five six seven eight nine 10.
And actually what we are doing, we're actually printing calories plus one, so maybe I should print
calories only.
And you can see that after burning ten calories, right?
We are out of the loop we'll give you.
We could not go till the end of the loop to complete the workout because when the value of calories
it became 10.
This condition became true and the break statement got executed.
So once the break statement hits, you come out of the loop, right?
So that is the significance of the break statement.
So anything that is written below the break statement, this will not get executed and you are out of
the loop, you're out of the loop.
You will end up out line number 18, right?
So I hope you understood why the break statement is sometimes it's going to be helpful and how it works
and its significance.
So that's all for this video.