Everyone, so you have seen the statement, the next statement that is used in changing the flow of
control of loop is known as continuous statement.
So as the name suggests, it is going to ask the loop or you start kind of continuing from the next
iteration, OK?
So what happens when you hit this continue statement inside the loop?
The control flow, everything that is written below this continues statement.
It is going to get skipped and it is going to return to the next iteration will get basically what what
this example is showing that the galleries were zero and we wanted to run this loop when galleries were
less than 20 and when galleries is 15.
I'm doing galleries equal to galleries plus one.
So basically what is happening is.
We are actually skipping this step.
We are skipping sealed calories, that means we are not going to print it and we are also doing this
step calories equal.
Look at this place when this is important, so I will explain you through really good what is going
to happen.
So continue will take you to the beginning of the loop and I'm going to screen you how it is going to
work.
OK, so maybe a new example and again, to continue the CBB.
So we are not going to use a break.
So maybe if calories equal to some number, it save calories mod five if it does zero right, if calories
is a multiple of five, I don't want to print calories, so I can maybe put this statement out, right?
So, so maybe I want to print laden.
And I want to increase the number of calories by one, and I'm going to continue, right?
So effectively what we are trying to say.
So every time we hit a multiple of five, we are not going to print the calories.
We are just going to print well-done and we're going to say, continue.
OK, so now let's try to execute this code and try to see what is going to happen.
In this case, though, the shoulders continue them right now.
Initially this well, then maybe I should also put right.
That would be a little better.
And let me make this as 20.
So that we get some more space on the screen, so I get laden running and burning one two three four
rather, then six seven eight nine Velden 11, 12, 13, 14 very, then 16, 17, 18 19.
And as soon as we hit 20, we are out of the loop, right?
So this is the significance of continued statement.
So what it is doing now, in the beginning, we had zero and this condition is true.
We a very then and you increase the number of calories you go to one.
So we print very learned into this one.
The condition is not true.
We come here and we are running and burning.
So one.
Similarly, we print two three four.
Again, we hit five five five five zero.
We print well.
Then we increase the number of calories.
Now this is a very important step here.
If you don't do this, what is going to happen?
If you suppose you forget to obey orders and maybe you're starting from one to what is going to happen
at one, you print or get ending and burning and you go to two running and burning, three running and
burning for running and burning at five.
What are you going to do?
You are going to print very then and continue.
So when you go back here, right?
So what is the value of calories?
It is still five and five is less than 20.
So again, you come here, you print, well done, well done, varied and varied and varied.
And this loop is going to run for a finite number of times that is going to cost your program to crash.
So it is not recommended that you use the Continue statement without updating this variable, which
is controlling the execution of the loop.
So this must be updated so that our loop also finishes.
So if I show you the demo now, we will see this program will get stuck.
And it is actually printing well done, a lot of things in finite times, it's still running.
OK.
It's still running.
You can see on the right.
So we will stop it and we'll suspend it.
OK.
And we have suspended the program.
We have to stop it explicitly by giving a keyboard interrupt.
And then it stopped.
OK, so this will lead to infinite loop.
So I'll just make a note.
Don't forget this statement.
Otherwise, you will end up, you know, in finite loop.
OK.
That is the significance of continued.
Now you may ask, why can't we do this using if it's not and there is, of course you can, continues
one more concept that we wanted to teach.
That is why we took this example.
Otherwise, feel free to do this using it felt as well.
That will work perfectly fine in this case.