Hello, everyone.
In this lecture, we'll solve this problem given a number, and we want to check if it is a prime number
or not.
So let's see how we can solve this problem.
So any number is prime.
It has only two dividers, that is one and the number itself.
So talk about the number like 11 11 has only two dividers, one and 11 or knockabout.
A number like seven seven has only two dividers, one in seven.
But talk about the number like nine or 15 or 21.
All these numbers they will have, at least one divides it in the range you do n minus one, you'll
get one and they are the dividers of every number.
OK.
That means if you need to find a device it, it must lie in the range.
Starting from total and minus one to nine does have a device that is three.
And it lies in the range two, two and minus one.
Similarly, 15 also has a divider in the range.
It will do 14.
That is n minus one on the divider.
You can see trees are divided, highways are divided.
OK, so we need to find at least one divider in this range to prove a number is not right.
OK.
So what do we need?
We need to.
Find at least one device that.
In the range it will do and minus one will prove a number is not.
And if we if we don't get to televise it, then it means it is a prime numbers.
Let's see how we can solve this problem.
First of all, will create and will read what and is a now.
Maybe we can put off our Lou, by the way.
Then maybe we can say we'll start finding the divisor from do and we'll go till and minus one.
And we are.
Trying to check if I is one possible by thereof.
And if not, I if this is equal to zero.
So what you can see, you can see that this number is not prime.
So you can say, you know, the number 10 is not prime and you can break, OK, that means you're going
to stop the look.
You don't need to go further.
For example, for the number 15, you take it as if you are to divide 15.
And that is no.
You go to the next number, that is three.
The three divide 15.
And there is, yes.
So you don't need to check for the numbers four, five six up to 14 at this point only.
You can say that 15 is not prime number or give you a pin is not a prime number.
Now, what is going to happen?
We also want to print when a number is prime or not, so the number would be prime if we reach here.
But based upon a certain condition or based upon a certain condition.
So that condition would be if I has reached a value that is equal to and only in that case, we can
say the number end is a prime number.
No, why?
Why this is true.
Talk about a number like, let's say, seven, right?
So you started from two.
So I became three.
Then I became four.
Right?
Then I became five and then I became six.
So it does not divide seven three, does not divide seven four, does not divide seven five, does not
divide seven six, does not divide seven and you're doing 8+.
Finally, when you're not willing to stop.
I'm going to take the value seven.
And that means there are actually two ways to come to line number 18, right?
One ways you can buy the break statement.
OK, so if we can buy the break statement, the number is not prime.
The number is not.
And if we don't come by the break statement, in that case, the number is prime.
In that case, the number is right.
So.
That's how you you can solve this problem of checking whether the number is prime or not.
So let me try to run this code and we'll show you in the demo, right?
So let's build a scoreboard first, so we have OK now we have got an error that is not declared.
So as I discussed, I is declared inside the blog scope of for loop so we can create this eye outside
and that will solve our purpose.
Now, Isaac says, it will outside the loop as well, right?
And let us try to run this code for the number who find the body.
We have to run this file first.
Fifteen is not right.
And if I give the number seven, seven is prime 21, not prime 23.
It is prime, well, guess what that means this court is working as expected, and the only thing that
we need to know is that there are two ways in which we can end up bad outside the loop.
The once the loop is over, the value of I would be called when and if the loop breaks in between.
I will never reach the value that is equal to and in that case, the number is not OK.
If you don't put this check, this statement would be printed always, irrespective of number is prime
or not.
So that is why we're doing this check is important.
So I hope you have understood the logic, and that's all for this video.