Everyone, so now we have seen the value and the fall.
One thing to note about both of these loops is that their entry controls so that what does it mean?
So basically, whenever you write a value, you have a condition that needs to be checked and it's only
then you enter inside the loop, right?
So both violent fall, they behave in a similar manner, and they are known as entry control loops.
In this video, we'll talk about the loop, which is actually our exit control loop, right?
And this is known as a Dubai loop.
So do Block has a set of instructions that will define inside a vile block.
But the thing is the condition is checked at the exit of the gate at the exit.
It is known as that and exert control loops.
I'll give you a few examples to make this understanding a little better, right?
So basically, let's say you were running on on a hill and in this case, in the first case, you're
checking if there is not an edge of the hill or edge of the cliff you are going to run.
But in the second case, you are going to directly run and after an enduring attack or have encountered
the edge of the cliff because it's a problem to relate this idea of the entry control loop, which is
over loop and the exit control, which is the low value right now, maybe we can build a code and to
see what happens then when we use or do well.
So let me show you a quick demo of using this loop, right?
We have Maine and now what we are doing, we are going to do something like, let's say.
It's the end.
Money equals two zero.
And later, do maybe you with your girlfriend and you're doing quite shopping and you don't have anything
in the pocket, so still you are doing shopping.
And you're saying while money is greater than zero right now, we know that this condition is false.
But what is going to happen?
We are first going to do shopping.
Even we don't have money in the pocket.
Okay, so that means this loop will execute at least once again.
This loop will execute at least once.
Let me show you the output of this code, right?
So let me just clear it, and I can say dodge large.
Do I look now you're going to you're getting the output shopping because.
The do block, it's going to execute, then it is going to check for this condition.
Now what happened is it got executed and now you came here, died, you saw this condition is actually
false.
The money is actually zero eight.
But we have already printed out put on the screen right now, this loop is going to stop.
Let me show you another example.
Let's say we have something like money equal to five and you're doing shopping, and every time you're
doing shopping, your money is getting reduced.
And maybe you can say I can print how much money is left right.
Shopping and money left.
Let's say let's build this school.
Now let's try to run this one, right?
Oh, we should give her nil right now, it would be better.
So shopping and money left.
So initially it does five right, and then it does reduce it becomes four and it becomes three, then
it becomes two and it becomes one.
So then when we are printing the statement, money left is one in this line, the money left to zero.
That means you're going to come here and you are going to check how much money is left after this step.
When the money left is one in this line, it becomes zero.
So money is zero.
That means this condition becomes false and this loops stops.
That means this work is getting repeated again and again until this condition is.
Until this condition is correct, so as soon as this condition becomes false, your loop is going to
stop.
So this is known as a Dubai loop and this is known as exit control loop, right?
So I hope you have understood the difference and this loop is going to execute at least once, irrespective
of the condition is true or false.
That was the idea behind Dubai Loop.
And that's it.