Hello, everyone, so in this lecture, we are going to talk about nested loops, what are nested loops
basically in many problems.
You were required to write a loop inside another loop, for example, in Britain, problems or injury
based problems or in some other problems that relate to what we're doing.
We're going to show you that two loops or multiple loops can exist inside each of that.
For example, I want to do something like, maybe I want to print something like a matrix.
Maybe I want to print one two three four five six seven eight nine 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15 16.
OK, now what I'm looking at is that in this kind of a problem, I have those and I also have columns
to be printed, right?
So this is a little.
Yeah, so this is a little and this is another.
This is another.
And this is another and this is another right?
What I need to do, I need to iterate over multiple rules letters starting from low No.
Zero till the rule.
No.
It's a one, two and three.
OK, I will.
I will be given or go on to print odd number of rules and I want to print some number of columns.
Is number of columns and maybe I want to print the values which are in a linearly increasing fashion.
Let's see how we can do it.
So firstly, we need to iterate over all the rows right back into four integral to zero I list then
are eight a plus plus we need to define what is the rule number eight and R and C.
So I'll take those as input from the user.
Now we know, OK, I need to three rows and four columns.
What we will, we'll go over every row and for every row.
We also have some work, which is repetitive.
We are printing a number and the number is not being initially from one for the first two and then it
is continuously getting increment.
So we will define a value that is one outside of this.
Or look, because we need this initialization only once we don't need to initialize one in every eight.
What we will do, it will say, OK, for every do I have to print column number of numbers?
OK, so I will need a loop for printing the columns.
So Jake called zero dollars, then see.
And as a jobless rate.
And what is the reality?
I want to print in every column.
Well, guess what, that is actually this value, which is initially one we can print value followed
by some space and we can increment that value to a local value plus one.
OK.
And.
After reading a video of what we have do, we have to go to the new rate so we have to go to new lines
of illiteracy out and that finishes our work and it looks like we are good.
So what we have seen here is that this loop is going to run multiple times for every.
So when I zero, the day is changing from zero to six day gets the value zero letters these three digits,
the value one day get the value to OK.
Then when I is one day again, get the value zero one two.
When I used to it again, get zero one two.
When I used three, it again gets zero one.
And what we are doing, we are printing a value that was declared outside initially one.
Then it became two.
Then it became three.
Then we came to the next to begin four five six seven eight nine 10 11 12.
OK.
So four rows and three columns.
So this is going to feel it is going to print in this fashion.
And after printing every row, we are going to come out of the inner loop and we are going to hit this
new line.
Correct?
OK.
So this is an example of an attitude, and you will required nested loops in some problems.
Let me show you the output as well so I can see.
Look, we have one errors.
This needs to be commented out.
So we have.
OK, let's for those entry columns.
I knew going to this is what we are getting, OK, loud protests, correct?
And this is what is expected from this particular program.
And I hope you understood this one as well.