Hello, everyone, and this lecture will try to solve another pardon problem, and the burden looks
something like this.
And this is what we want to print for a given, and, for example, and his vote for this example.
Let's try to break down this pattern like any other part and what what we'll do, we'll find out how
many roads we need to bring in this for.
So we do see there are photos, the first row, the second row, the third row and the fourth right.
And then we need to observe what we are doing in each row, right?
So the pattern actually starts from this part.
OK, so this part is not considered OK.
What we can observe is not if I talk about the rule number one.
Rule number two, number three and four in each row.
What I can, I can see some number of spaces.
OK, then I have some number of numbers which are in the increasing order, and I do have some numbers
which are in decreasing order.
This is what we have and we will try to count how many such numbers are there, OK?
So if I talk about of all true, I have zero spaces.
Third row, I have one space that can draw.
I have two spaces and in the first row I do have three spaces.
OK, so we know that and is for.
And while it's true, we have four miners, one that is today's best second, we have four miners,
two that is to space for miners, three that is one space and for miners for that.
So again, is it in the eye it through?
I do have and minus Espaces.
OK.
It's a pure observation thing you can easily write and you can observe.
As the rule is increasing, the space is decreasing.
So as I increases, the number of spaces would be from this one.
OK, then I have increasing numbers, so we have one that is in the increasing order.
We have two numbers in the increasing order.
We have three numbers in the increasing order and we have four numbers in the increasing world.
OK.
So basically one, two, three and four.
Effectively, this is same as the rule number.
So you have eight numbers in the increasing order, and they start from a value that is equal to the
number again, starting from.
Starting from a value that is equal to my.
That is that solves the problem for the increasing numbers as well, OK, then what are you going to
absorb?
We do have decreasing numbers, so here we don't have any numbers, so we have zero number of numbers
here.
We have only one number.
All right.
Here we have two numbers.
And here we have three numbers.
OK, any relate?
This with the value of two countries is the data i.e. minus one numbers, which are in the decreasing
order and starting from the value that is actually one less than what we printed.
Or so we printed.
Seven.
It starts from six.
We printed five.
It starts from.
The bill will initialize the value correctly and will see how do we do this initialization correctly
while writing the code OK, so now we have the breakup and we can start building over code.
So maybe I can start from here again to me and maybe I should write the loops so and scene in.
And maybe then I will.
First right to look for rules, OK?
The in intake will the one I lived in equal to an A-plus plus.
Now we are inside Egypt.
All right.
So we want to repeat some work and we want to repeat the work for Egypt.
Also first work, we have to do four spaces, then we have to do it for increasing numbers and then
we have to do it for decreasing numbers.
OK?
The four spaces we have seen that we need to print and minus ibises.
Maybe I can say for our count, that is equal to one count place and equal to and minus I count plus
plus every time I want to put into space, this is going to print and minus eight spaces in the I through.
We are Denver's business.
Then we have to print the numbers in the increasing order, so maybe Reagan to Ford and co. equal to
one count less than equal, do I?
Boundless bliss, this loop is going to run our times, and we know we need to print some value so that
value will begin from the true number itself.
So that is equal to I, and every time I'm printing a value again to see out value, I will increment
this value for the next iteration.
OK, so this will bring I numbers in the increasing order.
Then comes the decreasing numbers because of what we discussed.
We need to re initialize or reassign the value so that we.
The correct value from where we want to operate, and then we say we want to print a minus one numbers
in the decreasing order, OK, so we are going to see how do we initialize this value and we'll print
the value and every time the value is decreasing by one value minus money.
Look, if the count is increasing because we want this look good on a minus one times the value that
we are printing, this value is going to reduce at every step.
So let us talk about the rule number three, right?
What happens?
You will get in row number three, the value starts from high and you run the slope items.
So that means you print three and the value becomes four.
You print four.
Undervalue becomes five.
You print five.
And the value in the memory it becomes six.
OK, so you are doing a value plus plus operation after printing every value.
That means you give you have printed the numbers in the increasing order and the value is no increments
to six.
But what is the next value that you would be printing, right?
So if you look carefully?
So you made four or five, you printed five and you made it.
If you look carefully in the part of the value that we wanted to print was four, right?
And then we wanted to print.
How do you reach this single forward from this value?
Six.
And this meant this values in the moment it's not printed, but it is dead in the memory because of
this update, right?
That means if you try to print the railroad, take this look.
It would be six.
It would be not five.
And I want to get the villagers four.
So I have to do value equals two value minus two.
So I have to subtract two.
So that I get the correct value and now it should work.
And after every rule, we have to go to new lengths of illiteracy out and.
And that's it.
I should solve our problem.
You know, maybe I will include the header file so that I can run the code.
And let's build it.
Illustrated to it.
The name is Pyramid.
And as for so I get this pardon, which is absolutely correct.
And if it is five, I get the Spartan, which is also correct, OK?
So I hope you have understood this logic.
So I will just give you a quick recap of what we are trying to do.
The first, we tried to break down the button along the rows, and in each row we see that as a component
of spaces.
There is a component of increasing numbers and there is a component of decreasing numbers in each component.
We are doing some work that is getting repeated and we are printing some value that needs to be initialized
correctly.
Again, these are the two initial positions that we have done, and the values also need to update for
increasing numbers.
It is a plus pleasure and for decreasing numbers.
It is a minus minus upgrade.
And after every rule, we have to go to new line.
And why don't we put it down?
OK.
So I hope this makes your concept of loop more quiet, and that's all for this video.