Everyone's in this lecture, we're going to discuss this problem where we will take input and followed
by an input and binders, and we'll get to what is special about this problem that we have to read and
input first and then find there some way.
Let me give you an example if let's end this five and the numbers are.
Let's say 10, 20, 25, 15 and let's 40.
OK.
The way we're going to calculate the sum is that we are going to read all of these numbers one by one
and we are going to updatable some.
Okay, so the way we would do in our mind is we do not store all the numbers at once.
Okay, so easy.
OK?
Let me start with the value of some that is initially zero.
And let me see what is the correct term, but I'm it so I read the number and I make it as done right.
So this some is not that it was OK.
What is the next?
No.
What is the second number I'm reading?
That number is 20, so I make this an M.D..
OK?
What are the next number I'm going to read?
That is actually the third number.
I read it and I add 25.
So I make it does.
55.
OK, let me see what is the fourth number?
The default number is 15.
I make this as 78 and I took it.
What is the fifth number?
I feel good.
This is 40, and I make this final sum as how much the final term is not 100.
This is what the final sum would look like in order to build a program for this.
We need to create few bucket one bucket for the value of an OK one bucket to store.
What is the current number?
OK, what is the number we are currently reading?
And another bucket we will need.
They denote.
Availability, I so that I is noting what is the number we are reading or how many times we need to
run the loop so that we can read five numbers.
This we will do it using a loop and I will control how many times this loop is going to get executed.
Let us define few things.
First, we will define and which is a user input on this and decide to look at.
This is how many times the loop is going to run.
But.
In order to control it, which no, we are reading, we need available.
While I is less than equal to and is fixed, whereas I extending the value from one to and what is the
work that we need to do, the work is we will read a number from input on it to the same rate.
So.
So initially, we will define or get this missile, and there is a budget called No.
That we will read from you.
OK, so let's read this bucket and add added to the sums of some equals samplers number, so that finishes
our work, but not yet we have to write the update condition as well.
Update statement for the VI loop So we say this value is dependent upon the condition is less than equal
to N in order to go to the next position.
The next iteration, we need to remind the value of PHI so equal to plus one.
Or you can write A-plus plus water fine.
Finally, if you come out of the loop, right, if you come out of the loop, you will have the correct
value inside the very bottom, OK?
So the way the things are changing is this is how this number is changing.
This is how I work.
It is changing.
So I as one, as two, as three, as four.
OK.
So in this state like this?
And finally, I is actually five.
Yes.
In the fifth iteration I read, I read the number 40 and added to this.
So finally, if you come out of the loop, final sum would be 100 and so out some and.
So we have the code.
Now we can run it.
So I can assure you, we are running some of our numbers five numbers 10, 20, 30 or 25 59 40.
Yes, we are getting the correct answer.
I hope you have understood this very simple program and that's all for this with you.