We have seen how to work with the value in this example, we learned the about follow on for Luke basically
combines the three steps of the vie loop in a single line of code.
OK, so the three statements the initialization, the stopping criteria and an update statement.
Okay, so all of them get combined in this index of thought.
And here we will write whatever we want to execute again and again.
OK.
So let me show you an example for let's end calories equal to zero calories less than 100.
So this is your stopping criteria and this is your update statement.
OK, if?
And this is what we want to print again and again.
Now you may ask, what is the difference between fight for loop and why?
Look, the thing is they both are equal and took.
Everyone by loop can be converted into for loop on every value, can be converted into white look,
and every four can be converted into white.
So they are basically the same.
So they have the same speed.
They have the same time complexity only defenders.
The syntax of for loop is more come back to.
It is a more complex index, and a lot of programmers generally prefer working with a for loop.
But most scenarios instead of valuable get and the chances of making a mistake or missing some statement
are less because, you know you have to complete these three things when you are talking about a loop,
right?
So let me show you another good demo so will do for them.
And maybe I'm just going to copy one of the earlier code and we're going to convert this well into a
full plate.
What we need to do, we need to put forth statement to the initial condition that can be made inside
the four loop.
And I can say Gallery C++, so that is your update condition right now.
Everything is going to be same and no one one error that you're getting that use of undeclared identified
CAD.
So what happens when you declare galleries like this and you want to access this variable outside the
our loop?
So here comes the concept of a copyright.
So anything that is declared inside the for loop will give that variable is not accessible outside the
boundary of the volume.
That means this variable as a scope.
Bob is basically the region in which this variable is being existing, you can access this variable
only inside the boundaries of the up rate so you cannot access it outside.
So what you can do, you can define this variable in other scope.
For example, you can define this and declare this in mean, OK.
And now what happens if you declare it, it becomes a part of the scope of mean, OK, it becomes a
part of this method so you can use it anywhere inside this function, OK?
The one change I will do, I will say, OK, end galleries, and we are saying we'll get the initial
value of calories is zero.
While it is less than 10, I'm incrementing it and I'm printing it.
OK, so now it is getting compiled.
And now let us try to run this code.
And I can see a large, large Ford demo, you can see running one step and burning calories one, right?
So again, it is running 10 times and the output is exactly the same as the while loop.
But the thing is, it's more compact, according to index, right?
So that is what I wanted to discuss about the outlook.
But before jumping to the next part, I can show you that the four look and look a grilling and that
will see in the next picture.