Everyone's in this example, I'm going to show you that would the for loop and the Loop, they are equal
and OK.
So what we discussed in white Dindo, while Loop has some condition, then we have the body of the loop
and we're we have an update condition and in the beginning, we have some initial vision condition.
Now, if I want to write this for loop in a similar manner, what I can do, I can also declare galleries
outside the loop and I can initialize it with some value.
And this is also valid and this code will run as expected.
OK, so it is running as expected and what what you can see here is not giving this statement is actually
optional.
You can give it outside the loop as well.
You can give it here as well.
Similarly, this update, OK, you can apply this update it as well.
And now, if you look carefully at this index, the initial condition, a stopping criteria.
OK.
We are putting these goals because they help compiling all this is the stopping criteria.
This is not some initially conditional.
This is not the upgrade condition.
So these semicolons are still needed, although we are leaving these statements and as blank will get.
And here we do the work, and here we have doubled it.
Now you can see this for a loop is exactly behaving like a balloon.
So we have compiled the code and we are trying to run it so we can say, OK, again, this is running
as expected, and now you can see this is very similar to the structure of the loop.
And one more thing I can tell you is even this part is.
Optional, but what would happen in this case, you will end up in the infinite loop.
But maybe what you can do, you can break the loop from inside.
So later on, we will see the public statement as well so you can save calories becomes, then you break
the law.
If you build it, it is still going to run.
And now you're breaking the loop from the middle.
And yeah, so that is something we are trying to do here, right?
So that's all for this video.
We'll talk about the break statement, definitely, but in some other we do.
Thanks a lot.
I hope you understood that for and while they are equivalent.