Hello, everyone.
So in this lecture, we're going to solve a problem given a number and we need to find the sum of its
digits, OK?
So let me show you an example.
Let's say the number is one two five three, and we want to find out the sum of digits, which is one
plus two plus five plus three eight, which is 11, right?
This is what we want to print.
Now how you're going to approach this problem?
Let's have a look.
In order to find the sum of digits, you need to extract each digit one by one.
The one common way of finding the last digit.
OK, so maybe I will find out what is the last digit?
This last digit is currently now three.
And how do I do it, Isaac, if I take the more of the No.
With 10 rate, if I divide this number with 10 and the remainder, what is the remainder that is left?
The remainder is actually three.
These are the last digit.
Nothing would end modern, OK?
This actually gives me the docket from the number one to five three.
I got the remainder three and I will add this three to a bucket called sum.
The sum is initially zero.
So I treat it in the next app.
What I need to do.
OK.
I actually need to extract this number five in order to extract that.
Five.
I need to remove this tree so that I can use the same thing again and again so I can again do if my
number is 125.
And if I do a mod with 10, I will get the number five.
I can easily add five in the next iteration.
I even want to remove this five.
And I want to make the number as self.
So that I can get to by doing that and more generally, so I will add to do my answer.
And the next step, I even want to remove, too.
And I want to make the number as one that I get one as the remainder in the next step, I will reduce
it further by saying, OK, let us reduce it to zero and we will stop working.
So this is the point, then we will stop.
This is your actual number.
And now you can see how this number is getting changed from one to five, three to 125 in every step.
We are applying an update that.
And is equal to anybody.
This is what we are doing right now, this can be sold either using a for loop or using a value.
Let me show you how you can do it using a for loop.
OK.
Let me first show you how you can do it.
Using a value to end it is amazing.
So you have to take and put a number in so that we have done and we have to do some work.
While this number is, let's say, greater than zero are not equal to zero water fine.
What I will do, I'll find out the last digit, which is nothing but end modern and I will add this
to my son.
OK.
And I will say, okay, let us put the update condition, how we are changing, and in every step,
you can see that from one two five three two one to five, it is an equal two and divided by right.
And finally, when you're out of the loop, you can print the sun, and this will give us the sum of
digits of the number eight.
So.
Let me try to underscore maybe one two five three eight oh.
So some to some plus large strategic trade, we just somehow made this mistake.
One, two, five and three.
We're going to we're getting this armadillo in Mozambique, if you want to do it using for look, you
can do it, so you will see OK.
Bored and not equal to zero and is already initialized.
And either you can put the update condition hit or you can put it hit and equal to and write and write.
So every time you find out the last digit and you add it to the same rate, but even you can make this
more shorter, you can do some equal to some less.
And Martin, which is the last.
So you can just do it in one line of code as well.
And let's build this code and let's try to run this.
So one, two, five three.
Again, you're getting an output element.
OK.
It's totally your choice how you want to proceed.
But this is a thing that I wanted to teach if you want to find the last visit of any number you do and
model Austin.
And if you want to reduce that number.
OK.
Some people might think one two three five upon 10 is why not one twenty three point five.
The thing is, in programming we have, especially in C++ and Java.
When you divide two integers, you always get in digit.
You do not get the fraction of.
That is why this division by then really works well here, and I hope you have understood the logic.
And that's all OK.