Hello, everyone.
In this lecture, we're going to solve this problem.
So you have already seen that if we are given a number and this is the kind of burden that we want to
print, right?
So we have already discussed the breakup that the for problems like these we need to go to.
And we need to print something, right?
I'll just give you an example.
Again, hit the suppose.
In the first row, we noted that we have one start.
Then we have three stars and then we have five stars, OK?
So clearly the number of stars are increasing as we are going down to the Roland Burris one, the Roland
Burris two and Roland Burris three, right two in each row.
I have to go into a minus one stars, right?
And we also discussed that there are and minus espaces you need to do what I need to do.
I need to implement this using loops to let us see how we can do it.
So, first of all, will include the header file.
We will build our main and.
We can now declare a number and we can read what is this number?
And now once we know what is the value of, then we need to print and number of rules.
I can look at the rule number starts from one.
The rule number goal is still an A-plus plus, and in each row I have to print spaces and after spacing,
have to print stars.
So how do I print spaces?
So again, in order to print spaces, I will need a loop so I will default in some stars that is equal
to zero or stars equal to one stars less than equal to and minus I.
Look, this is a formula that we have already derived on recent Star C++.
And now what we can, we can say, see out.
A single stock.
OK.
And by printing this single story that it will print a single space, right?
We are actually printing spaces for straight spaces.
So I should name the variable as space and I should printer space, right?
And four times I can to 14 stars equal to one stars less than equal to the window I minus one stars
C++ and we will now do the actual printing of the star, which is like this.
And after every row or give, you have to go to new lengths will print a new line corrected using INDL.
And that's it.
That will do the work for us.
We have built the code.
OK, so this loop is four rows on inside every row.
We have to print spaces and we have to print stars as well, right?
Now let us try to run this code and see what we get as a output rate.
So let me show you.
So maybe if necessary, I get this pardon.
If in his faith, I could get this pardon.
So it absolutely looks correct.
And this is what we expected this program.
OK.
So I hope you understood the logic.
What we have that we have converted the pseudocode that we have discussed in the pseudocode module into
a real C++ code that actually works.
That's all for this video.
Thank you.