Everyone in this lecture we're going to solve in a department problem.
So let us look, what do we want to do?
So we are given away love and and we want to print a button which looks like this.
OK, let us try to break down this burden.
So if we have any faith, so clearly we have five rows, one two.
Three, four and five.
And what you can observe in each rule, like in the first rule, what we have, we have five letters
which are in the increasing order and then we have five letters which are in the decreasing order.
So effectively I have n minus.
I have n minus I plus one.
OK, so these many letters, they are in the increasing order.
And these many letters, they're also in the decreasing order rate.
And every letter starts from me.
So for the second row, we have like four letters.
So if I try to put this formula that is five minus two plus one, it gives me Yogev four letters which
are in the increasing order and then four letters which are in the decreasing order rate.
And then then the same thing is happening for the third row three letters.
Then two letters and then one letter, OK.
So for the fifth third would be end minus and is five minus one plus.
So five minus five plus one.
So it would be one letter in the increasing order and one letter in the decreasing order.
So we have we do have some observations, OK?
And how do they generate letters in the increasing order?
So I know that with each letter, there is a ASCII value that is marked.
So if I want to go from A to B, I can do simply if my bucket is storing the letter E right, which
internally is getting stored as the number sixty five.
So if I increment this by adding one to a plus one will give me 66, which gets mobbed to the letter
B right.
We will play with data types in this problem as we write code right.
So first of all, let us do one thing.
Let us first write the code and we will try to break it down side by side, right?
So I'll just copy this sample input and now we are in the code editor.
This is what we want to achieve for and equal to five.
So let me read the good hygiene include ice stream using namespace SD int main.
And let's save this file as well right
now.
What I want to do, I want to create a budget and I want to read it.
And then what I need to do to I need to iterate over Andrew.
I have to do some work for any number of rules so I can start from one I can go to and or you can start
from zero, you can go to and minus one that is all to OK.
Now in every rule, we have to print the letters in the increasing order, or we have to print and minus
I +1 letters in increasing order of values.
And similarly, we have to print letters and minus I +1 letters in decreasing values.
OK, so now what is the first value that we have in every row?
So in every row, the value starts from the letter, so I can say God letter that is always eight on
every two.
So remember, I'm doing this initialization inside this loop.
I am not doing it outside because I need this eight at the start of every door.
And this is the point where this rule is getting started.
So what I will do, I maybe make a count.
So it count equal to one count less than equal to and minus eight plus one count plus.
So what do I need to print?
I need to print the letter and for the next iteration, I need to increase its value so I can do later
equals letter plus one, or I can do letter plus plus.
It will automatically see when you write letter guards the edge.
This is equal to eight eight or letter equal to eight.
If you don't see it plus one, it actually gives you the number six to six to eight.
If you try to print as it will, you can observe.
But if you just see it equals C-H plus one, right, I'm doing this correct problems in Digital Edition.
This actually results in an integer like we have seen here.
But when you store this in inside a bucket, which is of the type gathered and when you try to access
that bucket for printing, it is going to print that in in the correct representation.
OK, it's not going to give you an integer.
So we are doing letter equals letter placement.
This is the same as doing letter equal relatedness, and we are going to the next little for printing.
OK.
Now one thing that is going to happen.
So suppose we are in the second row and what we did, we said, OK, we'll print D and we'll do later
plus plus, which makes this letter as B.
So we print being the next iteration, we make this as C in the next iteration, we print C and we do
letter plus plus, which makes it as D.
And in the next iteration, we print the letter, which is D, and we make this letter as a unit.
Now what do you want next?
So you want to print a and you again want to start from the right.
You again want to start from within this jump.
How do I get a d from the letter right?
That means we have to take one step backwards.
So now if you come out of this loop or if you see what would be the final value of letter when you come
out of the loop, so it would be one value more than what you have last printed.
So what is the last printed?
So you have printed B, So what is the next that you want to print?
It is all 2D, so you have to take one step back and you have to say, OK, it letter equal to letter
minus one.
Basically, you're kind of resetting the value to the previous printed letter.
So you are going from E back to the D, and this is true for every row.
So now I can tell I again want to print and minus one letters, but now in the decreasing order, so
I can t count equal to one count less than equal to and minus I placed one count plus plus.
So count will still still remains m.
So we are saying OK, if we want to print four letters then we are losing.
We want to print four letters.
OK, so now what those letters would be, they would start from B and they would go in a decreasing
order of printing.
So I will see out later and Al and I can select a minus minus.
That's it to the count is getting increased.
And finally, when your completed, do we have to go to new line?
So we'll see out and so actually and is not required at these places.
So I will remove it and I will give Andal here.
OK, now let us try to build this code and let's try to run it.
We do have an error because of this statement.
So let's just command this thing out, and now it is building fine.
And maybe I can show you in the demo as well.
So dodge large for.
Rector, pardon.
Maybe five.
All, so I'm getting this burden that looks absolutely correct.
So this is what we wanted to do in this example, and I hope now you have understood what we are doing,
so we have this loop of rules, OK?
And for every rule, we have letters in the increasing order.
And we also have letters in the decreasing order.
But to initialize the value from where we should start printing letters in a decreasing order.
This particular statement is needed and this statement simply initialize the start later as a forever.
OK.
And this new line you're already familiar with.
So this I hope this breakdown is clear, and that's all for this video.