I loved ones in this lecture, we're going to solve this problem, given a number, we want to find
the reverse of the item, but a discussion can be approached in two different ways.
So first way is very simple where we don't actually reverse the number, we just print the digits in
the reverse order.
For example, if the number is two three one four.
So what?
We will extract the last digit.
OK?
And you know, the last digit can be extracted by doing so and modern operation.
And maybe we print this last digit, right?
So we print the number four in the next iteration.
What I want to do, I actually want to get this digit.
So for that, I need to remove this digit, right?
So I I will remove four by doing any equal to anybody.
So we have reduced the number from two three one four.
We got the last digit and we reduced it to the number two three one right next name again.
What I want to do and I will do the same thing, get the last digit printed, OK and reduce the number.
So get the last digit, which is three.
Reduce the number.
Make it to get the last digit, that is to print it and reduce the number that is now zero.
So two divided by 10 is zero.
So every time we are doing the operation.
Anywhere in Britain, and we are printing the last digit.
OK, now this is very easy.
And if you do it for.
The number, the number is greater than zero.
You are actually going to print all the digits of the number in the reverse order, right?
So maybe we have and then and we take and put the value of and this loop is going to print all the digits
in the reverse order, so we end last digit here, right?
So now what we will do will run this code and will show you the output, right?
Let's say dodge, flash, reverse.
And the number is, let's say, two three one four.
So I get like four one three two three four one two three, which is correct.
And if I have a number like one zero zero one two two one zero zero one, which is fine, and if I have
a number like hundred, so I get the reverse as zero zero one.
OK, now this is a case where you might expect the reverse to be either zero zero one or you might expect
the reverse to be only one rate.
So if you store it, if you try to store zero zero one in an integer, you cannot store it, you will
store only one right now.
This will depend upon what is the sample input output is the problem statement expecting this kind of
output will with this approach.
If the problem expecting this kind of output, we need to change our approach slightly.
OK.
So now I will discuss the second approach as well, where we'll actually revise the number instead of
printing it in the next video.