Everyone, so you've already seen given a number.
How do we reverse it?
OK, and how do we print the digits of the number in the it was in this lecture, I'm going to show
you if you actually want to reverse the original number and what should be above reproach again.
So for example, if I'm given a number like 123 and I want this end to be country 21.
OK, so let's see, how do we do it?
If you look at 123 how it is made, it is made by combining these digits multiplied with certain powers
of ten.
OK, so one is multiplied with 10 squared.
It was multiplied with ten point one and three is multiplied with ten but zero and adding this hundred
plus twenty plus three.
This makes the number 123 OK.
And if you want to get the number 321, so you actually have to multiply three with 10 square two with
10 by one, one with ten point zero.
And I think this would become 300 plus 20 plus one, leading to 321 right now, what we can do is we
have seen how do they extract digits and.
But in the digital and reverse order, so instead of now just printing their digits, we are also going
to form a number.
OK, so let's look at what we are going to do.
Let me call this number as 123.
And let me call this number, which is zero in the beginning as my answer to what I will do.
I will extract the last digit and I will move the digit to the answer.
OK, so I will say I will apply this operation.
Answer equals answer into 10 plus the last digit that I'm getting.
Now you see the significance of this operation, OK?
Why it is important to in the first step, we get the digital three.
And the answer would become zero into 10 plus three and which is equal to three.
OK, and will reduce this number by dividing it with 10 to end becomes 12, right?
So we segregate 12 and three.
And this is what our answer is in the next step.
I'm going to find out the last digit again to that last digit would be two.
And my number would be reduced by end by then, which is No.
One.
Now how do we combine this two with this three?
OK.
So effectively, I want this three to become 32.
So how it will become so it will do whatever is the correct answer.
OK, so what will be multiplied with 10 to train to 10 makes it 30?
And we add the last digit to it.
So it becomes a No.32, right?
Great.
So this is what we are actually trying to achieve next time.
What you get.
You will get the last digit, which is one, and you will reduce this number by dividing it with 10.
So it becomes zero, it becomes zero.
That's a good thing.
And now we have this reminder as one.
So what we want, we want to attach this one with 32.
So how do we attach one with 32?
So we have to multiply 32 with 10?
That is again, this operation.
Multiply your previous Andrew.
It's 10, right?
And add.
One, do it, so it becomes the number 321.
And your original number is now zero.
And that means we can nonstop and you'll find a land that is now 321.
And that is what we wanted to get, right?
So how we will modify this code, so we'll keep one more bucket, that is answer that was initially
zero.
And instead of printing the last digit, we will add this digit to our answered.
So answer would be answered in 210 plus last digit.
So this is a way of combining the last digit with the correct answer.
And again, we are reducing the number by a factor of 10.
So finally, what are you doing to put your link to output your answer, which is the reverse of the
actual number that you have got, right?
So we have built the code and now we are ready to test our code.
So maybe I can say it like it was actual device number actually.
Yes.
So maybe one two three four I get four three two one.
Great.
I have one zero zero one one zero zero one two two one zero zero one and if I have one.
And now you can do.
In this case, the output is actually one.
It is not zero zero one.
Okay, so that is a difference between two approaches.
And here you are actually reversing the number, whereas in the previous one, you were only printing
the number.
OK, so reverse it.
Finally, if you want, you can do any word once it and you can talk.
I have reversed the actual number itself.
That is also OK.
So I hope you have understood how we can use a loop here.
OK.
You could even have used a for loop.
You could have said four and greater than zero and an equal to end by ten.
And I don't want to do this.
That's OK.
And you understood the last digit as end model is.
That is all talk.
So you can simplify this code for the by using the for loop.
But it does not affect the execution time because what the loops have similar performance are now,
you will get the same output, but now we are using a four wheel.
So I hope you have understood what these approaches and that's all.