And welcome to this course on C++ essentials, and I'm very excited to welcome you on congratulations
on taking the first step into the world of programming.
So my name is pretty.
I've been a software engineer at Google.
I have co-founded two tech startups, including coding minutes.
I work with scalar academy as well.
And I've been instructor on Udemy for about one year now.
And if you want to learn more about me, so I created an interactive portfolio resumé website on that
igniting dot com, which you can visit and look at my journey of learning coding.
When did I start and what did I achieve?
So before we dive into the specific details, I would like to share my perspective on learning to code
on becoming a problem solver.
What we do is I break down the step into three parts, like the first step of learning programming is
learning to hold the knife.
What does it mean?
Get them translated with a real world analogy so that if you're a beginner, you understand the flaw
in a better sense, right?
The first step is always to learn to work with the programming language.
So programming language is our tool and will try to get comfortable with the programming language in
this course.
Once you're comfortable, the next step is you learn to use the knife by cutting a fruit.
It means you learn how to solve a problem and what solving problems you need something.
Already the researchers, which are basically the containers that you need to store data on, you need
to learn algorithms which are basically their techniques to solve the problem, OK?
So then in the next step, you will learn about data centers an algorithm.
And the third step is, once you have learned to work with the researchers algorithms, you have to
apply them to newer kind of problems.
OK, so this is what is also observed in many interviews.
So you would be given a problem statement, which would be a newer, unseen problem, and it can be
a problem inspired from real world.
For example, you want to find the nearest hospital, or maybe you want to devise a route for the cab,
which works in a sharing model, something like that.
So the third step is about sharpening your knife and you have to cut your kind of route.
So that is one step ahead of these three steps.
I have created a problem solving track, and this is the first course of the track where you get comfortable
with the programming language in the next course, which is on data centers.
You learn how to work with different containers and their time complexities as well.
And in the third step, you learn how to sharpen your skills, how do you sharpen your knife and applied
algorithmic techniques to different type of problems, OK?
And so that's why I have devised three courses so that you go from zero to hero in in your journey of
solving problems.
I will be there in all three courses to help you the must become the master of problem solving.
And yeah, that is the problem solving track for you.
So before we discuss about this course, let me also tell you a little bit more about my professional
experience.
I've created several top rated online courses on did great coding minutes to bring high quality courses
on Udemy.
And a lot of my students who have gone through this journey of problem solving with me.
They're working in top product companies, including startups and companies like Google, Amazon, Microsoft
as well, right?
So what to expect after this course?
So I'm just going to talk about this course, so you'll get comfortable with the programming language.
It does not matter which programming language you start with, it can be C++.
It can be deployed, can be Python.
But for this course, I've picked C++ as the language, and it helps you to get into more details of
how the programs work, what happens at the binary level and all that stuff.
We do go in this course and you build solid programming foundations annually, radiological thinking
skills which are required to take the next step.
And you'll get familiar with concepts like loops, branching is string through cohesion, back dragging
on with masking and loops will cover these.
You can have a detailed look at the curriculum, right?
The first part is the logic building curriculum, which is again optional if you're already familiar
with logic building.
So I discuss.
Few things before you start writing good.
I discuss floor jokes and go dark, tell you how to think like a programmer given a small problem.
How do we break it down and how do we build logic for the same?
The second part of the course is more C++ specific, and we try to learn with various language constructs,
like how to write code that is using effects, ranging concepts, loops, operators, functions, pointers
et is Gutierrez Strings recursion and basics of object oriented programming so that the complete curriculum
of this course and um, and you know the good thing, there are no prerequisites to take this course.
So if you are an absolute beginner and if you have not worked with programming anywhere in your life,
you are at the right point.
This is the right step to start learning programming, right?
And so I hope you are ready to join me on this journey of learning coding and you will tighten your
seat belt and I will see you in the course.
Thank you.
Bye bye.